A list is a collection of objects.
So in Python the way to declare a
list is using these empty square brackets.
Now this variable "my_list" here is an empty list.
If I just print this variable you can see that
I get these empty square brackets. This indicate that
this variable is an empty list.
So how do we insert values in the list.
One simple way is to just write them down.
Separated by commas. So if run it again,
I can see that I have 4, 3, 2, 1.
I have these four different values in my list now.
The next question is how do we fetch them.
So to fetch them we use the square brackets again
with a variable name and we write the index of the
value we want to fetch.
So let's say I want to fetch the first value.
So the index for the first value is 0.
So for the second value it is 3.
And similarly It goes on to 1 and 1 will have an index
3. So if run this, I get 4 here as 4 is
on my zero index. So if I want to get the last value
which index I use? I should use three.
You can see I get 1 here now.
So in python we have this feature where
we can get multiple values or a range of values
using a single statement.
This is known as slicing.
So how do we do this?
We write the name of our list of the variable name
and we write the index we want to start
and the ending index plus 1.
So just to give you an example.
If I do this, let's say I want to get values from 4 to 2.
So 4 has index 0 and 2 has index 2.
So that would be 2 + 1 according to
a formula here. I would use three.
So if I run this now, you can see I
get the first three elements, 4, 3, 2.
So let's say I want to get first two elements.
What I'll do is I'll use 0, 2 and I
get the first two elements.
Perfect.
So now I'll just quickly go over some of the most
commonly used functions in Python which are related
to list.
So this "append" function here what it does is it
receives a value as a parameter and it adds this value
to the very end of a list.
Just to show you how this works.
I'm going to add 5 to get to the end of my list.
Just let me move the statements. If I print my list
now,
you can see I added 5 to
the very end of my list.
So let's move to "pop". What "pop" does is it receives
an index as a parameter and it removes that index from
a list and it returns that value which it has removed from a list.
Let's say I want to remove the first value.
So what index does the first value has?
It has index 0.
So I'm going to use print "my_list.pop" and zero
index and then I'm going to print "my_list" to see if
I have 4.
So if I run this,
you can see that it pops off the first element which is 4.
And now I get the rest of the list back, 3, 2, 1.
I don't have four here.
It has removed it from a list.
So what does "remove" do? It accepts a value as its parameter.
The value is an element which is present
in my list and it removes that.
So let's say I want to remove 3. So I'm going
to say "remove(3)" and then print "my_list".
You can see 4, 2, 1.
I don't have to 3 there anymore.
So it has removed 3 from a list.
So what does "insert" do? "insert" accepts two parameters.
The first is the index where you want to insert
a value
and the second parameter is a value which we want to insert.
So let's say I want to insert the value 100 at index 1.
So what I am going to do is I'm
going to say "my_list", "insert", value.
I want insert 100 on one index. So 1 is my index
and hundred is my value and if I print "my_list" now, I get 4,
100, 3, 2, 1.
So 100 is on the first index just as I wanted.
So what does "clear" do?
"clear" deletes all the elements present in my
list. So if I use "clear" and if I print it now I won't have
any more elements.
It would be an empty list now.
What does "index" do? It accepts a value as its parameter
and it gives me the index of that value like
where it is right now.
So if they use "my_list.index" and I want to
know where is my 1 like at which
index is 1 present.
So if I use this, I get three.
So 1 is at indexed 3 and that's absolutely correct.
So what does "count" do? "count" accepts a
value as its parameter and it counts the number of times
this value occurs in my list.
So let's say I have 1 three or four times and if I
run this now "my_list.count", I want to count 1.
So I'm just going to use it
and you can see it gives me four.
I have four 1's in my list.
This being this, the last function that
we use very often is "sort". So if I use "sort"...
So I'm going to print "my_list" before sorting
and I'm going to print "my_list" after sorting.
So now you can see before starting my list was
4, 3, 2, tetra 1. After sorting it is tetra 1, 2, 3, 4.
So these were some of the commonly used
functions which we use while dealing with lists.
Next we'll have dictionaries and tuples
and dictionary comprehensions and list comprehensions.
All the compressions and then we'll move to some
more stuff like map, filter, reduce and then finally
I think you'll be more familiar with data structures used in Python.
Thank you very much!