Hello everyone! In the previous
lecture, we discussed list. In this lecture, we are going
to discuss another data structure which is commonly used in
Python. They are known as dictionaries. I'm
sure everyone has used our real life dictionary.
So how do we use it?
What we do is we search for a word and then when we
get that word like we find it in a dictionary and
we see the definition against that word.
So how does it work
actually? A real live dictionary
has items, item1 , item2, item3.
Each item is basically like a word with a definition.
So it goes on and on and on.
So I'm going to have items from A to Z in an English
dictionary and each item contains two things, a
key and a value.
The key is the word you're searching for and
the value is a definition against that key.
So I'm going to give an example here. Let's say I want
to find what school means, the word school means.
So I look up school in my dictionary.
So school is my key and when I
find school I get a definition for
school and that's my value.
So for the school in my dictionary, I have a value which is its definition.
Similarly the same thing goes for coding
and then in my third item it's
Python, the key is Python.
So when I search Python in a dictionary, I'm going to
a get definition for Python. That's going to be the
the keys value.
So how do we declare a dictionary in Python?
The very simple way to do this is
"my_dict" is equals to use this empty curly braces and
if print "my_dict" now you see I get these empty curly
braces. This indicates that my dictionary is empty now.
So how do we insert values or items in a dictionary
in Python? Python dictionaries works the same
way as real life dictionaries work.
I mean we have items and each
item contains a key and a value.
Each item contains a key and a
value and we get the value by accessing the key.
So if you want to find the definition of
school, we look school in our dictionary
and we find a definition for school here.
So that's the value for a school.
I'm going to build this dictionary,
"my_dict" dictionary using these three items. So I'm going to
insert my first item here, my first item is school,
the key school. I say "school" and
then I input this colon.
And I have the value now which is "definition of school".
Now I have a single item in my list. At the
left side of this colon I have school.
This is my key and at the right side of my colon and
I have the value which is definition of school.
Now if I want to insert another element what I do with
is I input a comma and then I repeat the same thing.
I say coding and then I input a colon and
then I have the value coding which is "definition
of coding".
Now same goes for my third element
which is Python. So "definition of Python".
So if I print my dictionary now.
Let's see what I get.
I've printed my dictionary and you can
see I have three items in my dictionary now.
They're all separated by a comma.
So my first item here says "Python",
second is coding, and third is school.
So each item contains two things a key and a value.
The key is at the left side of the colon and
the value is at the right side of the colon.
So here it says Python is the key and the
value for Python is "definition of Python".
Let's say I want to look up the definition of school.
So how am I going to do that?
I say print "my_dict", I use this empty square brackets
and I input my key.
I say "school" and if I print this now you see
it gives the value against this key, gains this key school here.
So one thing to note here, keys are unique.
You need to understand this.
Keys are unique. I mean you can't have two keys saying school.
That's wrong.
You can't have two keys, two similar keys in a single dictionary.
A key is unique, a key in a single dictionary is unique.
You can't repeat that, have two keys,
the same keys in a single dictionary.
OK, so let's add some more items to "my_dict".
So I want to add a definition for pen.
So what I do is I write "my_dict", I use these square
brackets and I say "pen" is equals to "definition of
pen" and if I print my dictionary now you can see I have
another item. I successfully inserted another item in my dictionary.
This is how I do this.
So how I insert a new item into my dictionary.
Like if I have to define one and then I
want insert another item in my dictionary,
I use this index.
OK.
So do you remember keys are unique and you
can't have two same keys in a single dictionary.
If I say "my_dict", I say "school", "key number 2",
it's just going to update the value of school.
So if I print "my_dict" now
against school I have now "key number 2".
I don't have another key named school.
You see how this works now. OK, good.
So one of the most commonly used method for dictionary
is "items". As we've discussed before a dictionary
has items like different items.
In our dictionary right now, I have one, two, three.
I have three items.
So let's say I want to know what items
I have and I want to do something about it.
Let's say I want to print them all in separate lines.
So what do I do.
I use a for loop, I say "for key,
value in my_dict.items" and I say print
"key", "value".
Now what happens is this "my_dict.items" is iterable.
This returns an iterable.
So one by one, it returns me each item and in
each item as I told you I have two things, I have
the key and the value.
So I say for key, comma value in
"my_dict.items", print "key" and "value".
So if I run this now, you can see
I have the keys here, on my left side.
The first key is "Python", it says
"definition of Python" and "coding" and then "school".
So this is how dictionaries work.
This is a very basic introduction to what we can do
with dictionaries and one or one and one other thing
I forgot to mention is that the keys can be anything,
they can be any objects, they can be integers even like
I could say "my_dict[2]",
"the key is 2".
So if I print "my_dict" now, you see
I have four items.
Just let me remove this loop or comment it.
You can see I have four items in my dictionary now.
I have "coding", I have "school" and then I have this
element which has an integer as its key.
It has 2 as its key. If I say "my_dict[2]"
and print it, I get the key is 2.
And the value can be anything too, it is not restricted
to strings only, it can be any object.
You can have anything in there.
Maybe another dictionary if you want, a nested dictionary.
So I hope this is clear.
We'll move to tuples next.
And then we have list comprehension and dictionary
comprehensions and we'll this discuss this and more
about this.
Thank you very much.