Hello everyone! I hope all you're doing OK.
Last time, we discussed dictionaries.
And today, we will discuss tuples in this lecture here.
So tuples is another very useful data
structure we have in Python. Tuples
basically you could say it is a package containing
different values or it is a sequence of values and
once you have declared, it cannot be changed.
I'll just explain all of this, what I've just said right now.
Think of a person. A person can have different attributes.
Let's say he has name, a person
can have a name, he has an age.
And let's say he can have his hair color.
I mean suggesting that he has hair.
I hope so.
So like let's say I have this guy here. His name is
Sammy and he's 27 years old and he has brown
hair.
So what I can do is I can declare a tuple for this guy.
I can say "person" is equal to "Samy".
Now this is my first value and
then my second value as is his age.
I insert that separating it by comma
and then my third value was his hair
color which was brown. So now I have brown, I have
two different values, they're separated by commas
and if I print "person" now, it say's "Samy", "27", "brown".
So this is one way to declare
a tuple.
This here is a tuple, this "person" variable
right now is a tuple.
And if I print it, you can see
I have three different values here.
I have a sequence of values
in this variable here.
So how do I access each value.
That is pretty much the same as list.
What we use is we use the square brackets and
I input the index for each value, I say like 0
I'll get "Samy". For 1, I'll get 27.
And for 2, I'll get "brown"
OK.
So we use indexes to access each value in a tuple.
So now when we are assigning different values
to a single variable, we call this as boxing.
This is another word for this.
Like for this phenomenon we use another word.
This is known as boxing.
And let's say I have I say "name", his
"age" and "hair_color", I say "person".
So this is known as unboxing or unpacking.
I mean whatever you are confortable with. And if I print
"name" here, I get "Samy". If I print "age" here, I get 27
and if I print "hair_color"
here, I get "brown".
So I mean it works both ways.
So right now "person" is a tuple and it contains three
different values or a sequence of values and the
first one is that person's name.
The second is age, third is his hair color.
And it can be anything, it is not
restricted to strings or integers.
I can have different objects here,
any object here and it will work.
All we have to do is like if I'm going to
insert another value all I do is I have this comma
and enter this number and it will work just fine.
OK.
So moving forward now.
We have...
Right.
Right now we have covered how to declare
a tuple, the syntax for that.
And this declaration is also known as boxing.
What we are doing is we are
boxing different values into a
single variable name. So this we
call boxing and when we
take these values from that single
variable, we call that unboxing or unpacking.
So a tuple is basically also an attribute,
we can actually loop through it.
So I can say "for value in person", print "value" and if I
run, it says "Samy", 27, "brown". So that was like
we can loop through our tuple.
So a tuple is an iterable.
What I mean by iterable is that I can loop
through this iterable like each attribute in Python.
I mean as the word itself says that an iterable
is something on which you can iterate over. So a
tuple is an iterable.
We can iterate over that.
OK.
Now I'll move forward with nested tuples.
What I mean by nested tuples is that I have this "person"
equals to "Samy" and now what I do is I have another
tuple here.
And how do I add that?
OK, I'm not so good with my imagination.
Sorry, it's bad.
Let's say I have his hair color that is brown.
His eye color that is black.
And then I have his age finally.
So what I have right now is I have three
different values in my person variable.
It's tuple sorry.
So the first value is a string, "Samy".
The second is another tuple.
And the third is an integer.
So this is basically a nested tuple.
So if I say print "person" and I say one, this
gives me a tuple, you can see "('brown', 'black')".
It has returned me a tuple so I have a tuple
inside another tuple. I have this tuple and it is inside
another tuple which is here, this person. So
we can have this and I mean this is perfectly valid.
It's the same as like having a dictionary inside another
dictionary or a list inside another list, like 2D lists
or 3D lists.
So this was nested tuples.
I hope this is clear.
And lastly what I want to clear was
I mean what differentiates a tuple from a list
or another data structure like some other data
structures.
That is that there are immutable.
Once you have declared then, we can't edit them.
If I have a list, I say "my_list" is equal to
"[1, 2, 3]" and I can say "my_list",
0, is equals to 100. And if I print "my_list[0]",
if I print "my_list",
I get "100, 2, 3]".
So I can change the values in my list but I
can't do this for a tuple like if I say person
0 is equals to "new_name".
And if I print "person" now that is going to give
me an error because once you have declared a
tuple you can't change its value.
It is immutable.
The values are immutable once you have declared them.
So that's one important thing to remember about tuples.
You can't change their value once you have declared them.
I hope this is clear.
And next we'll move to lists comprehensions like
all the comprehensions, we will move to dictionary comprehensions
and tuple comprehension and list comprehension.
I hope this helps and thank you very much.
Have a nice day.