Hello everyone.
Last time we discussed tuples, now we are at a
list comprehensions. List comprehension is another way
to make less and other more natural and refined way.
Those some would say that this is a more complex
way of doing things.
But I think in my personal opinion it's more neat
and it's more good looking and it doesn't
consume too much of your line when you actually write
it down that way when you actually make a list using
list comprehensions.
We'll just see how this works.
Let me first make you familiar with this module we have,
random, we'll be using a function of this
module.
So what "random" does is
it prints random numbers.
I mean like it gives us random numbers and we can
print them or we can do whatever we want with them and then
we'll be using this function "random.randInt".
It takes two values as its parameters.
The starting is like we give
it a range. Let's say I want
to generate a random number from zero to 100.
I'm to give it 0 to 100 and it will give me a
random number between this range. It will be between zero
to 100.
So if I run this, it gives me 24. If I run this again, it gives me 43.
So this is a function that you'll be using
making our list so that we have
random data in that and not just linear
values.
Ok, so I have made a list of
random values using a loop.
This list has 20 elements in that.
I'll just walk you through this.
I declare at line number five
a list, the name is "our_list" is equals to empty square brackets.
Then I have this loop which loops to 20 times.
So this loop is going to run for 20
times and each time it runs
what I do is I say "our_list.append", and I append a
random number with the range from 0 to 100 in my
list.
This list we have is our list.
So if I run this and I print it, I get a
list which has random values, random 20 values.
Let me just check the length of my list, that is "len(our_list)".
And we have 20 values in the list.
You can see that we have a list which has 20
elements in it and all of them have random values.
All the elements are just random values.
OK.
So this was how we make a list of
random values using a loop.
So we consumed three sentences, three lines for
doing this. We wrote three statements for doing
this thing.
Now we're are going to make the same list.
But we are going to use list comprehension,
I say "new_list" is equal to this.
Now I have my loop here. The loop is "for value in the
range(0,20)" and this loop is going to run for
like 20 times and I say "value". If I print this,
I get a list which has linear values like from
0 to 19 like each time this "range" gives a value
I entered that in my list.
So this is basically an example of list comprehension.
So the syntax is that I use these square brackets.
I open them. At my left most, I have the value
which is going to be inserted into my list
so "value which is being inserted into my list"
then I have the "for" loop and I close these square
brackets.
And this is the basic syntax for a list comprehension.
Now what I want you to do is I want you to write
a new list which will have
random values and it should have 20 random values.
I mean you have to write this code and you have
to write it through list comprehensions. The syntax is at the
leftmost, you have the value which is being inserted
into your list like right now this variable
value is being inserted into my list each time this loop runs.
So I would suggest that you pause the screen now
and do this and when you have done it, give
it a shot.
And when you have done that then
continue again to see how we do this
if you are unable to do it.
OK, so I hope all of you have done it.
OK, so what we do is I say "new_list",
I say "random.randInt",
0, 100.
Now comes my loop, "for value in range(0,20)".
And if I print my list now.
Sorry, "new_list" now I get a list of
random values, 20 random values.
So what did I do.
All I did was I just changed this.
Here I had this variable "value" here.
All I did was I just changed that.
I call this function here, "randInt", which
gives me a variable,
a random value and that is inserted
each time the loop runs.
So this statement, that line number 16
is equal in these three statements
we wrote. This is a list comprehension, this is how we
make less using list comprehensions. You can see that
they're more neat.
They are more natural looking.
But for some of you,
some people would say that this is something complex.
So it would take time for you to get used
to this but this is a very neat way of doing things.
And I would highly recommend that you practice this, that
you make different lists using different values
and you practice more on this. And we'll discuss this more
in my next to you so I hope all of you understand what I told you today.
And thank you very much.
Have a nice day.