Hello everyone.
Last time we talked about list comprehensions and
an alternative way to making this a more natural one.
I hope you're more familiar with
making lists using list comprehensions.
Now we'll discuss this concept more. Now in this
lecture, we'll make 2D lists using list comprehensions.
and discuss how to manipulate them and how to access them.
So first questions first, what is a 2D list? 2D list is
basically a nested list or a list in a
list.
What I mean by this is that let's say you have a
shop and people come there for shopping.
So for each person comes to shop has his own
cart and they go and they add items to
their cart and they can add unlimited items their carts.
And they come back to you and you check and
then they pay you and they can take that items.
So how can I illustrate this concept in Python.
Let's say I have carts like I said, I have many carts,
I have unlimited carts and what I do is I say OK, the first
person bought toothpaste, he got shoes,
he got bread and then I say my second
person got pencils,
he got erasers, let's say he bought a notebook
and there's a third person who bought meat,
bought some fruit and
he also bought some vegetables.
So like I have three persons, they came,
they took your carts and they shop these things. The
first person took toothpaste, shoes and bread, the second
pencils, erasers and notebook and the third meat, fruit,
vegetables. Another way to write this can be "person1"
one is equals to this
and I can say "person2"
is equals to this,
"person3" is equals to this one: meat, fruit, vegetables.
And then I can say "cart" is equals
to "person1", "person2", "person3".
I've just done this for readability.
I mean this is not so readable.
So now I have three carts, cart one for "person1"
contains shoes, the cart for "person2" contains
pencils, erasers and notebook and person3's
cart contains meat, fruit and vegetables.
So if I print "carts",
what I get as I get a single list and that list
I have three different lists. So this is basically a
nested list, carts is nested list or
I could say that this is a 2D list.
Another way to represent this
can be like "person1 cart",
"person2 cart",
"person3 cart"
and I can have a loop
"for value in carts", print "value".
If I do this.
Let me just comment that.
You can see.
I have three lines and in each you get a table.
It has three rows and three columns, one
two, three and three columns like
toothpaste, shoes, bread. Three columns.
So this is basically a 2D list. To access a single value,
what I can do is let's say I want
to see what is the first thing that my
"person1" bought.
So what I'll do is I'll say print "carts[0][0]".
It gives me toothpaste.
I want to know what my last person, "person3", bought at the very end.
So the index for last person is 2 and the index for
the last value to that item the person
bought that's also 2 like our list contains three values.
The last index is 2. So if I run this, it gives you
vegetables. Let's say I want to find what
"person2" bought at the very start.
When you started shopping what is the first thing he bought.
So the index for "person2" is 1,
and the first thing he bought, that would be 0.
And if I run this, it gives me pencils and he indeed
bought pencils first, then he got to erasers and notebook.
So this is basically a 2D list.
This here, this cart here is a 2D list.
I hope that this is making sense to you right now.
I just want you to go through this and I want you
to call this yourself so that you understand this
better and how this works.
And you can think of 2D list as a table.
And what you do is you use two indexes to
access any single element, like the first index
gives you your row so if you use 0
here this gives me "person1" cart and
the second value gives me the column number.
I mean like which column I am talking about.
So if I'm saying this 0 is like my row, this gets me
to "person1" and if I say 0 this this gives me
this toothpaste here.
Why?
Because this is the column zero.
If you represent this in a table format,
that would be something like this, "0, 0".
So "0, 1", "0, 2", "1, 0", "1, 1", "1, 2".
This would be "2, 0", "2, 1", "2, 2".
So this is the first index is row.
And the second index is column.
I hope this makes sense.
Now the task is to make this, to make a 2D
list which contains these values.
The first row cantains value from 0 to 4,
the second 5 to 9, and then 10 to 14, 15 to 19
and 20 to 24.
We have to do this using "for" loops right now.
I mean like the way we normally declare list,
the way we normally make list right now
and then after doing that, we'll use
list comprehension to make the same 2D list.
So I say "task_list".
I've declared an empty list.
And before I go on with this, I want you
to understand the "range" function.
Like if I say "for value in range", "range" takes three
parameters. I mean you can also give it one or
two or three.
But it can also take three parameters.
The first is the starting value.
The second is where I want to go.
And the last one is the increment one. So if I print "value"
here, what does it give me? It gives me like
the first value gives me 0.
The second gives me 5 because what it
does is it says 0 and adds this increment here,
it gives me 5 and it sees if it's
less than 25 it goes into my loop.
So I get 0, 5.
And then after that I get 10.
Then add 5, 15, and add 5, 20, and as soon as they
get to 20 what it will do is it will add five.
It will say 20 plus 5.
That makes it 25 and it sees is it less than 25.
It isn't.
So it won't get into the loop and they
don't get the value 25 in the very end because
this value is excluded.
I mean this loops runs until 24, if it was 1 here.
So, OK, what I'm going to do now is I'm going
to make a 2D list for this using "for" loops
I could say "for row in range(0, 25, 5)"
and then I say "for column"...
OK, so in each row I have a list, right.
Each row has a list and it contains five values.
So I declare a list, "inner_list" is equals to this, and
I say "for column in range(row, row+5)".
I say "inner_list.append" and I say "column". OK.
So why did they use this? For the first row
this is going to give me 0.
And if I go through this, this loop will give
me values from 0 to 4, this inner loop, this "for column
in range"
will give me values from 0 to 4 and
then add them to my "inner_list".
And after doing that what I do is I
say "task_list.append", "inner_list".
The next time this loop runs, my "row" is 5,
the value of "row" is 5, it gets to this inner
loop.
And now my inner loop starts from 5 and it
goes till 10 or 9, preciselly. To be precise, it goes to 9.
And now the values of my
"inner_list" now are 5, 6, 7, 8,
9 and I add that "inner_list" in my "task_list".
So if I print my "task_list", I say
"for row in task_list", print "row". If I do that,
you can see I have this 2D list here.
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12,
13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19 and similarly the last row.
So "task_list" now is a 2D list and it contains
five rows and each row contains five columns.
Just take a pause here and understand what's
going on and see if you can I would like to decode this
side by side if you can do this so that you
understand this better and how this is working. OK.
Now we're going to use a list
comprehension to do the same thing.
And it is going to be more neat though it may
look a little complex right now but once you get used
to list comprehensions, you won't look back.
So I say my "new_list" is equal to...
I have this empty square brackets here.
So to declare a 2D list.
I mean if you remember, to declare a list comprehension
what we did was we had value which is
to be added and then the loop.
This was the syntax right.
So what I do is I add the loop, I say my outer loop
is "for row in the range(0, 25, 5)". OK.
So now what's missing is this value which is
to be added. So the value which I'm adding is
this "inner_list", right.
So what do I do now.
Basically this "inner_list" is a list.
So I can use a list comprehension here.
What I do is I say I want to add a list, the value
which I want to add each time this loop runs is
another list and the values for this list are going to be
now comes my inner loop, I say
"for column in range(row, row+5)". And in this inner list
I want to add this column
and if I
run this now,
you can see that it gives me the
same output as this loop was giving me.
I mean these two nested loops we used. But
the line we were consuming were like from 41 to 47.
And in this list comprehension what
we did was we only use a single line for
creating a 2D list.
This is a very efficient way of doing things.
It is more neat, it is more natural looking.
And once you get to understand this and once
you're familiar with them, you won't look back.
So now I want you to understand what happened here.
So I had my outter loop, this
"for row in range", this one. I had my here loop.
Now according to the syntax, I have written
my loop, now what I want to write is the value which I
want to add. So the value which I'm
adding to "my_task" list each time this
loop runs is another list, this "inner_list".
So what I do is I use this empty square brackets, I
have these empty square brackets so that each time
the loop runs, I'm inserting a list.
OK.
And this list contains what values?
I use another list comprehension here.
I use this loop. I say "for column in
range(row, row+5)" and then for this inner
list I have to add the value, right.
So I add the value now which is supposed to be this column.
So I add this column and my list comprehension is complete.
This line,
this statement creates a 2D list and
after that I print it and I see that
I have a 2D list and each row contains five
values, each row contains five values or a single list
which contains five values.
I hope this is making sense to you right now.
I would drop by some assignments which I would like to
do and perform and I would have the solutions
with this so that you understand how this thing
is working and I want you to practice this more
and more as this is a very efficient way of doing things.
And this will be mostly how we will be doing things
in the later part of our course when we are analyzing
the data which we are scraping
because is way more meat than writing
five to six lines for just creating a 2D list or
maybe we can have a 3D list too. So thank you
very much.
I hope you understand this and have a nice day.