Hello everyone.
Last time we discussed list comprehensions. Today in
this lecture, we're going to discuss inline "if
else" statements. In Python, we have this feature
where we can write an "if" statement in a single line.
And it's very handy.
I'm just going to walk you through this very quickly.
Let's have this variable, it has a value 20 in it.
So normally I would use an "if" statement,
if "a" is equal to 20 print "a is 20"
else
print "a is not 20".
So if run this, it says "a is 20".
So how can I do this in a single line.
So one way to do this is we say
print "a is 20" if here comes the condition,
else "a is not 20". So if I
run this, it says "a is 20".
And let's say I change it to 21 so
this should evaluate to false now.
If I run it, it says "a is not 20".
So how did I write this.
The syntax for this was that I'd do something here.
Then I write "if" condition and then
I say "else" and then do something.
So here in do something
what I was doing was I was writing a
string here that is 20 if condition else
and then I was doing something here.
So if I write 20 here, it evaluate true.
And we can also use it to let's say if "a" is 20 I
want to say that "b" is true else "b" is false.
So what I'll do is I'll say "b" is equal to "True"
if "a" is equal to 20 else "False".
So if I print "b", just going to comment this line,
if I print "b" it says "True" because it is 20.
OK, so inline "if else" statements are used
extensively in list comprehension. Let's say I have a list of numbers
"num" is equals to "value for value in range".
Now if I print this list, you'll see that
I have negative numbers and positive numbers.
Now I only want a list of positive numbers from this "num" list.
So what I can do is I can use list comprehension and
these inline "if else" statements to do this. So I say
"positive_numbers" is equals to
"value for value in num if value > 0".
And if I print "positive_num",
it only gives me positive values from this whole list.
And similarly I can do this for negative values.
So this is how you use inline "if else"
statements in list comprehensions and in general Python.
Next we'll move to how servers work and how the Websites are hosted on servers.
Thank you very much.
Have a nice day.