Hello everyone! In this video, we're going
to learn how to write to an Excel file.
As you know that we have been learning web
scraping and we have learned how to extract data from
webpages and how to refine that
data and get exactly what we need.
So after we have that, we can't
really have all that data in the RAM memory.
So what do we need to do now we need to write
somewhere, we need to write it to maybe a file
or something or anywhere or maybe to a
database or somewhere so that we are able to
access it later back on in a
defined format or in a predefined format.
So one way to do is to
write an Excel file and then
you could write it to a database.
You can do the same with Excel file or with the
the CSV file.
It is the same thing.
So in this video, we are going to
learn how to write data to an Excel file.
We'll be using the module
"xlsxwriter". I'll just show it to you.
But first I'm going to open Microsoft Excel and
I'm just going to show you how this works, how Excel works.
Like the very basic. I'm sure you all know.
I'm just going to give you a quick review.
So here I have an open Excel and you can see that there
are different things, different templates
but I want to open a blank workbook.
So now if I click on this,
it is going to make a blank workbook.
It is going to make a workbook.
OK, so here we are.
It has now made a workbook.
OK, so now
look. I have this workbook here and
then I have these rows and then I have these columns
here.
The ABCD are columns then 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
are rows.
So like this being this, what I did was
I made a workbook and it automatically added a sheet
to this workbook. So you can see that
where my cursor is "Sheet1". If I click on this,
this is going to say "Sheet2". I can have as
many sheets as I want and the data will be separate on each
sheet so I can write something here but it won't
show up on "Sheet2" because it's separate and all of
this is in a single workbook or in a single Excel file.
So I hope
you know what I mean by workbook now.
Or our sheet.
OK.
So let's get started.
How we can write an Excel file using Python and "xlsxwriter". OK.
So the necessary import is from "from xlsxwriter import Workbook".
So the first step we need to do
is we need to make a workbook.
So this module "xlsxwriter" has a class Workbook.
We are going to make an instance of this Workbook class. We are
going to say "Workbook", it takes a filename as its parameter
which we want to create.
Let's say I want to say
"first_file.xlsx".
So now the Excel file which is going to be
created now, it is going to be named
"first_file.xlsx".
OK.
So as soon as you make a workbook, you should
definitely close in because if you don't
do that there is a high probability that your data
might get corrupted or something if
it unwritten in some buffer, somewhere.
So good practice is that you always close
your workbook as soon as you make it.
So I'm going to say "workbook.close".
So right now what I've done is I've written
"workbook" is equals to "Workbook" and then
I've instantiated an object of this class.
I've sent the name of the file I want and then I closed
this workbook. Now I'm going to run this and we'll see
does this create a workbook and if it does what exactly is there in it.
OK, so you can see that I have something here.
You can see this here, "first_file.xlsx".
So if I open this,
I have a blank Excel file, I have a blank Excel file.
Great.
So what we did right now,
it created an Excel file.
We created workbook and then we closed it.
What we are going to do is we are going
to add a sheet like the default sheet.
So that is like we say "worksheet"
is equals to "workbook.add_worksheet".
Like the "Sheet1", "Sheet2", "Sheet3" we saw earlier right now.
So, OK now we have added a single sheet to
our workbook and now we get to the actual thing,
to do the right thing.
We are going to get how to write data into our Excel file.
Ok, so what we do is let me think
of something like what should we write.
OK.
So I say the method is "worksheet.write".
And it takes three parameters for now.
I mean it takes more parameters but
keep it simple and take three parameters.
The first one is the row number.
The second one is the column and the
last one is the value you want to write.
So I say like 0 row, 0 column and I say "zero row
and zero column" and I could do the same
thing then I could say "worksheet.write",
I could say 0, 1 and I could say
"zero row and one column".
OK.
So we'll just copy this so that it is easy.
So I'm going to change this here, I'm
going to say "one row", "one row and one colum".
OK.
So here we go.
So what we have done right now is
we said "worksheet.write", giving it row
number then column number and
then the value I want to write at that place.
Same goes for this one.
I've written four statements, it's going to write
four values in four different places. I'm going to run this and
then see how this works out and does this right as expected.
OK, let's get started. I'm going to run this.
So I did run this and let's open this first file now.
It did open. OK, here we go.
So great.
This is like your "zero row zero column", this is your "zero row one
column" and this is like "one row zero column" and "one
row one column".
So you can see it has returned as desired.
It has written as desired.
So I had row number here and the column
number here and then the value. Let's
do something different.
Let's say I want to write, I want
to have numbers here until
20.
I want to write 20 numbers in my Excel file.
What do I do now? I say "for row in range(20)" then I say
"row" and for this I say "Row Number",
"worksheet.write",
I say "row", 1. So I'm going to run this now.
And we are going to see what the output is.
Sorry.
So you can see it here. What it did was
I had the loop here which ran from 0 to 19, or 20 times. At zero column
what I have, I have written "Row Number"
and at my first column I have the relative
row number according to that row. So for
first it says 0, then 1 and it goes to 19.
So you can do whatever you want.
OK.
I mean you can have as many statements as you want.
It is not a restriction and you can use as
many columns as you want, as many rows as you want.
I could have this loop run
to like 200 and it will work fine.
I'm just going to close this and let's see this quickly.
So when I open this now, you can
see that this goes on.
This goes until 199, 200.
Yes, because the index starts from one and
it says 200 there but their row number
it says 199.
OK.
So you can see you can use as many rows as you
want and as many columns as you want, you can use loops
or whatever you want.
I mean that depends on your data
set or on how you want to have the
data classified in your Excel file.
So this was how we write data to our Excel file and in
the next video we're going to learn how
to read data from an Excel file.
Thank you very much.