Hello everyone.
In last video, we learned how to write an Excel file.
So in this video, we are going to
learn how to read from an Excel file.
So this was the file we wrote in the last video.
In this we have 200 rows and you can see in the first
column we have the string here. It says the row number
and in the second column we have the actual
number for the relevant rows.
Like for this it says 0, then 1, then 2 and
this goes on to 199. In total there are 200.
OK.
So we'll be using "xlrd" module for reading
an Excel file. This is the import we use for reading from an Excel file.
Obviously there are many other ways you can
do this but we are only going to talk about
the most easy way and the one which is frequently
used which is sufficient for a user right now.
OK.
So what we do is we open the workbook,
that's our first task. We say "xlrd.open_workbook". I give it the fileame.
The filename is "first_file.xlsx".
I have opened the workbook like I want to read
from this so I give it the file, the path of that
file which is the name here.
So this is goig to open the file here, "first_file.xlsx".
OK.
Now after doing that what we do is we select the
sheet from where we want to read. Here we only have
one sheet, so we are going to select this one.
But if we have multiple sheets,
we could specify the index there.
So I say "worksheet" is equals to
"workbook.sheet_by_index".
And then I say the first sheet
which is the zero sheet.
OK.
Now that I have that, I want to
read the whole of this Excel file
so I need to know how many rows are
there in this Excel file. What can I do now?
There's a method here.
We can say it is like ".nrows".
And if I print it, "worksheet.nrows", it is
actually going to tell me the number
of rows in this Excel sheet.
It says 200.
And this is absolutely right.
I mean there are 200.
You can see that here. There are actually 200 rows here.
OK, so now what we do is we say "rows"
is equals to "worksheet.nrows".
Now what we are going do is we
are going to read each row and then we
are going to interpret the value or
we are going to print it right now.
And see how this works.
So I say "for row in
rows".
Now this method for worksheets,
the method is "row_values".
And then what it takes is the row number and it
returns a tuple of values, a tuple of different
values, the value of all the columns that are present there.
So I'm just going to show you
how this works so it will be more clear then.
OK.
Now we only have two columns here.
OK, the rest of them are blank.
So it is only going to returns us
a tuple of two values for each row.
The first value would be first column and
the second value would be the second column.
So I could say "first_column" and I could say
"second_column" is equals to "worksheet.row_values"
and then I say row and then I could say print "first_column"
and then give some space and then I say "second_column".
And let's see how this works.
I'm going to run this now.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Actually it should be "range" because "rows" is like 200.
I'm sorry.
That's my mistake.
OK, so you can see it here.
Now what it did was like I used a
loop which I run 200 times.
And each time it ran, what I did was
I use this "row_values" function.
This takes input as the number
of the roll with which we
want to get the values and then it returns me a tuple
of values of all the values that are present in that row.
So we only have two values here in each row.
So it is only going to return
us two values in our tuple.
OK.
So let's say first column and second column
and I get them. Then I'm just going to print them.
So this is how this works out and you can play
around with this module or you can create
your own Excel files and then you can
read from them and you can manipulate
them in different ways just to see how this works.
So I hope that this is clear to you now, how we can read Excel Files.
And if there are any queries, you can reach back.
Thank you very much.