Hello everyone! In the previous section, we discussed
how we can navigate through our parse tree or
our HTML tree.
And then in this section, we are going to discuss a
specialized language known as Regular Expressions which
will help us search through tags and data through
our parse tree while we were doing searching
in our next section.
So this Regular Expression basically is a specialized
anguage which is used to search for text or strings
in a given document or a string
with extreme precision and efficiency.
It's blazingly fast as it's written in C.
I mean the engine written to match
the strings is written in C.
So how do they work.
You can say that there are a set of rules or
it's an expression which is compiled into bytecode
and then that bytecode is executed by matching engine written in C.
As I told you before. So it's blazingly fast, it's
very efficient and you should definitely use it.
But the drawback is that for complex expressions
like if you want to find a very complex string
in your document, your ugly your expression it's going
to be very complex and that reduces readability
which is a key point
in some scenarios.
So what's the main usage of Regular Expressions.
In that case, that is matching characters or finding
tags or finding data through our parse tree.
So how do we do this.
How do we actually find data using Regular
Expressions and how do we write these expressions.
So a simple Regular Expression
matches itself in the given string.
What I mean by this is that let's say I have written
a Regular Expression "abc". So I mean, yes this
is a expression. First things first, this is a Regular Expression.
And what this Regular Expressions is going to do
is like if let's say I have a string that says
"abcdef".
Yes.
So if I match this like if I run this and
if they want to see if this Regular Expression
exists in the string, it is going to give me "true" because it does exist.
So this is a very simple expression.
And what I want to convey is that if you write a
very simple thing, it is going to find itself
in the given document or in the given string.
So if I've written "abc", it is going to find itself int this string heree.
I mean if it was a document, you would got a document here.
So there are some exceptions to this rule though.
The exceptions are metacharacters.
So what are metacharacters. Metacharacters are characters
which don't match themselves. Like if you did
an ABC and you get an expression "abc"
and you were finding it in string "abcdef",
this will find it, this "abc" will find
itself in this "abcdef", in this string.
But this metacharacters,
they don't do that.
You know this is a complete list of
metacharacters which I use in Python.
And let's say if I have this metacharacter
here and I say... This is a Regular Expression I've
used this I corrected and then add this this
is "a" character and I say I want to match this.
It won't match because these metacharacters
they don't mean like that.
They don't mean what they are like.
It doesn't mean that I'm looking for
a "*" here.
It doesn't mean that. These metacharacters
have different meanings and they
xecute according to those meanings.
So once we get more into this I hope
you'll understand more about this like
once we actually code this.
So just stay with me.
And let's get to the first metacharacter.
And I think they'll help clear things up.
So the first metacharacter
which you'll look at are these square brackets. We call
them character class. A character class is a set of
characters you wish to match.
So let's say a user is going to input some character, any character,
you know.
Let's say the user inputs a single character.
Let's say he inputs "b".
So what I can do is I can write a Regular
Expression to match what the user inputs. Let's say
I want to see if a user is
inputing a character which is like from "a" to "b".
So what I can do is I can say I'll use the square brackets, I say "[abcdef]".
OK so.
And close the square brackets what this means is that
if any character comes from these six characters
"abcdef", if the user inputs any of these characters
and if I match them it is going to give me "true".
Like the character the user has input, that exists
in this character class. So if the user inputs "Z", then
this is going to give me "false" as my character class
is from "a" to "f", like "a", "b", "c", "d","e", "f"...  Actually it
only contains these characters and there is no "z" here. And other
way to write this is "[a-f]", this is a range.
So this means like from "a" to "f", all characters are included.
So if I input "c" now this is going to give me "true".
Because like my ranges from "a" to "f". This is
like a very basic use of square brackets.
OK, so let's say I have this here
I have 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 here.
And if the user inputs 9, do you think this will match? It
won't match. Why it wouldn't match? Because what happens
is like when you run this,
it says that
"OK,
Is this character from any of these characters which are like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5?" and then
the it says
"Oh, no! It isn't.""
So it just tells that.
"OK.
It doesn't match."
So what is the other way to write this.
I mean I have numbers from 1 to 5, I could say "1-5".
So this means that this and this is the same thing.
This includes all numbers from 1 to 5.
Or I could write them down if I want to.
OK so this was a very basic introduction to meta
characters and the square brackets are character
class.
In the next video, we're going to discuss more
about this and I hope that you'll understand more as we
code this.
So please stay with me and let's watch the
next video to see how this works.
And I like I hope you'll understand more then.
Thank you very much.