Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed
what metacharacters are and we discussed a
very basic metacharacter known as
character class or square brackets.
In this video, we are going to discuss
this compiled function and we will discuss how we can
actually run this like these patterns and see how
they work and we'll work with character class too.
And I hope this video will clarify your questions
you have from your previous video. So at line number
one,
I have this "import re". This "re" is the
module for Regular Expressions in Python.
So if you want to use Regular Expressions
or something, you need to include this
each time you want to use Regular Expressions.
OK, so this "re" module has a function "compile" which takes
a pattern or a Regular Expression as its parameter and it returns us a RegEX
object.
So I could say "regex" is equals to
"re.compile". Let's keep it a simple "a".
I've only written "a" here, OK.
OK, so now this "regex" object has a function ".match".
And in this ".match" function, I give it a string and it matches that like
if this expression is in the string or not. And if it
finds it, it returns us a match object or if it doesn't
find it, it returns us "None" that it was unable to find it.
So let's say I say print "regex.match".
And I say "Does this 'a' exist and this 'a'?".
And if I print this...
OK, so.
If I print this, it gives me...
Oh I'm sorry it's running. OK.
So if I print it, this gives me a match object.
It says yes, it has found "a" and the
span is 0,1 which is like from 0 to 1.
The range of characters it has found it. If I change
my expression, if I say sets "ab" and if I run, it returns me
"None" because it can't find this string in this string.
So this "re.compile" takes our Regular Expression
as its parameter and it returns us a regex object.
And then this regex object has a match parameter.
So a match function which takes
a string which we want to match,
its parameters, and it
searches this Regular Expression in the string.
And if it finds it, it returns us a match object
which tells us details like from where the string is starting
and ending and that kind of stuff.
And if it is unable to find it,
it returns us "None", like it did.
So in this case I said
I want to find "ab".
And when I ran that through this match here in this "a" string,
it gave me "None" because it couldn't find
"ab" in this "a" string.
Ok, so what we're going to do now is I'm going to use character
classes to clarify this concept more on how
this works.
So if you remember, what a character class did was like
I have the square brackets and I wrote "abc".
So this should accept like if I input a character,
it should accept any of these three characters.
If I input "a", it should give me a match object,
if I say "b" it should still give me a match object.
And similarly for "c" but if I put anything other
than these three characters, it should give me "None".
So let's see if this is true or not. I say
"regex.match" and give it "a", and if I run it,
it has given me a match object and that
tells me exactly where it found this match.
The span gives me the indexes.
So if I say "c" and then run it.
So gives me a match object.
If I give it a D.
Let's see if it gives me something. And it gives me "None"
because it was unable to find this "d" in this
Regular Expression.
So what character class allows us is that we
can actually provide multiple characters to match
a character from like you know I have
given the range of characters I've said
I want to match.
Either it could be "a" or "b" or "c". It could be any of
them and if the character is any of these characters
mentioned in the pattern, it returns us a match object
else it says it was unable to find it by giving us
a "None". Here we go, it gives us "None".
So if you remember I can actually give it a range.
I could say "a" to "h".
And if I run it now, if I say "g",
it sends me a match object. I can have the range
from "a" to "z" even .And now all the lower case letters
are going to come into this strange.
So if I try caps lock "A" or an uppercase "A".
It returns me "None" because it
is unable to find it.
So to make it a little more complex, I could say "a-z"
and then I could have capital letters too here. So if I
run this now, it returns me a match object because now
this pattern here looks for all the lowercase letters,
all the lowercase alphabet, and all the uppercase
alphabets. So you can see how powerful this RegEX is.
Just by writing this expression, it is able to search
through each alphabet like no matter if they are lowercase
or uppercase. Ok, so we have this complement function,
not a function.
So I mean we could make the complement of this set.
You could say that this is a set of characters,
this "a" to "z" and "A" to "Z".
I mean this expression is a set of
lowercase and uppercase alphabets.
So what we can do is we can actually
have a complement of this set.
So what I mean by that is like I want to accept all
those characters which are not lowercase
and which are not uppercase.
So that would be like our digits or our symbols.
So I could say "regex.match". So if I say one...
So what I'm going to do is I'm going
to input this hat symbol here.
This hat symbol means that I am going to
take the complement of this character class.
If I run this now, it says "Yes, this
is a match" because now what
it is matching is that it is going to match anything
apart from lowercase and uppercase alphabets.
If I remove this hat.
Now it is going to match any lowercase and uppercase alphabet.
If I run this, it returns me "None" because "1"
is not in this character class.
But if I have this hat back on, this hat assures that the complement of
this character class works. A complement
is that in this case any character
which is not the lowercase or uppercase. So if I run this now, it
gives me a match. Ok, so all meta characters lose their meaning
inside a character class.
So I could actually search for plus here
if I wanted to. I could say "+" and if
I run this, it finds us a plus sign.
But if you remember meta characters like
plus is a meta character.
You see this is a symbol and this is the
whole list of meta characters. And in that
we have plus, and then we have this question mark, and
this curly brackets and they all lose their meaning
here when you're using character class.
So I hope this is more clear to you now,
like how this "compile" function works
and what a character class is and how we can specify ranges
of class and how we can complement a character
class to search for a particular string.
Next we'll move further into RegEX
and I think you'll understand it more
once we do more stuff in it with it.
OK so thank you very much.