Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed the
"compile" function and character classes and we also
went over through the "match" function and how we
can match RegEX expressions using the "match" function.
Ok, so in this video, we are going to discuss
special sequences especially sequences
that are commonly used character classes and
we can just use these special sequences instead
of writing those character classes.
I will just quickly go through the
sequences and I would like you to play
with this code and experiment with this yourself and see how it works.
So here the first special sequence is this "\d".
This matches any decimal digit and is equal to this
character class, like 0 to 9 range.
So this capital "D" matches any non-digit character.
So that's the complement of this character class.
So this "\s" matches any whitespace
character like tabs, new line, spaces.
And similarly this is a complement, the capital S..
And then I have a "\w". This matches any
alphanumeric character and
the character class for this
is this like, "a" to "z"
lowercase,
and then "A" to "Z" uppercase, and 0 to 9 range of
any numbers. And then this here is the complement of
this set here.
So I would like you to play with this and
experiment with this yourself and see how it works.
And I hope you'll understand better
then and how character classes work.
Next, we'll discuss more about RegEX and I'll
discuss how we can repeat different characters
and we'll go through this in the next video on how we
can repeat stuff and write more powerful RegEX
expressions.
Thank you very much.