Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to discuss
how we can write more powerful RegEX expressions
and how we can handle recurring characters.
So let's say I have this expression here, this "a" one.
So this regular expression is going to
match any string which contains an "a".
So if I say print "regex.match" and "a", it says
"Yes, it's a perfect match". But let's say
I want to
have an expression which can match any number of a's.
So, OK. Let's start with five numbers of "a".
So what I can do is I can say one, two,
hree, four, five. And if I run this
now, it says "None".
So my string has to have five "a".
If I run this, it says
"Yes, it's a perfect match."
OK, but what if I want to match 20.
OK, still you can write 20.
But let's I want you to match 500 a's.
So don't tell me you are going to write 500 a's.
You are going to write like this, this,
this, this, this... That's not happening.
RegEX gives us a very powerful
tool, a very powerful character to which we
can actually handle this very efficiently.
So the first character we are going to discuss is this
asterisk character. This specifies that the previous character
can be matched
zero or more times instead of exactly once.
So what this means is that if I use this, this means that either they can be zero a's or they can be many
occurrences of "a".
That would be like infinity.
So if I run this now,
it still gives me a match, a perfect one.
If I don't have anything here,
I still get a match because asterisk says that either
this "a" will come once or like in finite time.
So the lower limit is zero and the upper limit is infinity.
OK so I can have any number of a's and it's going to match the
them.
So in this video, we discussed this asterisk
character which matches zero or more times any
character which comes before it.
And I can have a character class here too.
OK, I could use it like this too. So I could
say "a" to "c" and if I run this,
it still gives me a perfect match. And I can have "b"
and still it will give me a perfect match because
this expression says that "a", "b" or "c" can come as many times as they want.
And in any order they want to come.
So this is a very powerful expression here right now.
This is going to match any string which contains "a", "b" or "c.
And in any order.
So you can test it out. I can have the "bc" here
and you'll see it will still match it. So I could
start with "c" and it will still match.
So I hope this asterisk character is more clear to you
and I would like you to go through with this yourself
and write some strings and check this out, write
some expressions and test so that you understand
this better.
Next, we are going to discuss some
more characters which help us repeat things.
I hope this is clear to you.
So thank you very much.
See you in the next video.