Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed the
asterisk character which specifies that the
previous character which occurs before it, can be matched
zero or infinite times. In this video, we are going to discuss
this plus character which specifies the previous
character can be matched one or more times. So
the difference from a asterisk is that asterisk says zero to infinity.
And plus says one to infinity.
I'm just going to give a quick example here.
So let's say I have this and if I run this.
I say print "regex.match" and then have an empty string here.
So this will give me a match because asterisk says
that "a" can either come 0 times or as many times as
it wants to.
But if I have this here, this is going to give me "None",
it doesn't give me a match because plus says that it
should at least come once.
So if I have "a" once here, it gives me a match
and then I can have "a" as many times I want.
So I have a match. OK.
So now same as before, we can use this with character classes, I could say "a" to
"c" and "+".
I can have any string here.
"abcabcabc".
It gives me a match.
But if I have an empty string here, it gives me
"None" because plus says that this character,
character class,
should come at least once.
If I have a asterisk here,
it would give me a match.
So this is the difference between plus and asterisk
and I hope this is clear to you.
So in the next video, we'll discuss one more "repeating
things" character and I hope that this is clear to you.
The difference between asterisk and plus. This
is a very common mistake most programmers
make.
So I just want this to be clear to you.
OK.
So thank you very much.
See you in the next video.