Hello everyone! In this video, we're going
to discuss two final "repeating things"
characters and I will end the "repeating things" characters
here in this video and I hope by the end of this
video you are more confident to write expressions
using these "repeating things" characters.
So let's get started.
The first character we have here is the question mark.
So this question mark says the previous
character can either come once or not at all.
So I've written this RegEX expression. It says "a?b".
This means that this a
can either come once or not at all.
So if say print "regex.match" and I have
"b" here, it will run. It says
"Yes,
it's a match."
Was it a match?
Because this "a" optional, it can either come or not.
So if I have one single "a" here, it still is a match.
But if I have another "a" here, it says
"None". What does it say that?
Because this question mark depicts 0 or 1. It says minimum is zero,
maximum is one. OK, so this was the question mark character.
And lastly going to move to this character here,
these curly braces.
You could say you can implement any of the
"repeating things" characters from these curly
braces.
So these curly braces expect two parameters.
They are integer values, "m" and "n", so "m" means that the previous character which
is (inaudible), will have at least "m" repetitions and at the most
"n" repetitions.
So what do I mean by that.
I'll just explain this with one example
and I hope I can clear things up.
So let's say I have this "a" here.
So what I do as I say "a" and I say zero.
Let's say I want this "a" to come at least two
times and at most four times. So I do this, "a{}".
This is my minimum repetition and this is my maximum repetition.
So this is going to accept values of "aa", "aaa" and
"aaa". Not more than and not less than that.
If I say print "regex.match('a')", if I do this, it says
me "None" because it expects at least two repetitions
of this "a" character.
So if I have one more "a", it gives me a match.
So if I have three "a", it still gives me a match
because this expects minimum two and maximum four
repetitions. So if it's four,
it still gives me a match.
But as it is going to five, it is still getting me a
match but it's only giving me a match for the first four
characters, not the first five characters. You can see that here.
So the first parameter is the
minimum repetitions you want and the
next one is the maximum repetitions you want.
So the thing with these curly braces is that we can
implement any "repeating thing" character we've discussed
before using these.
Let's say I want to implement this asterisk.
So what I can do is I can use
these curly braces with the following
syntax.
So I'll say for minimum at zero and for maximum
it leaves the field blank. If I leave it blank,
it means that it expectes infinite boundary this way.
So if I say "regex" is equals to "re.compile" and I say "a"
and this. So say print "regex.match",
it gives me a match.
It still gives me a match.
And I can have as many values I want and that still gives me a match. OK,
so the thing about this was leaving it blank was
that if I leave the first value blank that means
that by default
it is expected to be 0.
If I leave the first value blank. And if I leave the
second blank that by default means that it expects
an infinite value there. So for plus I have "".
So this blank depicts an infinite value which means that
the previous character again have at most infinite
repetitions. And for question mark,
I have zero and one.
I want you to write these expressions and I want you to use curly braces and
for learning how we implement them and have
different expressions which are equal to this last
character here and this question mark, and the asterisk
one that you were familiar with repeating Regular
Expressions and how we can handle them and
how we can write complex Regular Expressions.
So thank you very much.
I'll see you soon.
Thank you.