Hello everyone.
This is the last video we are going to have on Regular Expressions.
And in this I'm just making you are more
familiar with some more metacharacters.
I want you to play around with them and experiment with them
yourself, I'm just going to explain what they do and
never do any basic expressions using them.
OK, so the first is this hat character.
I mean these are the most commonly used
metacharacters. There are more
and if you're interested you can look them.
I can have them in a Word document if you want.
OK, so the first one is this hat character.
What this does is
this say that this string should start with
this character
Let's say I have this "^a".
This means that my string should start with "a".
OK, so this pipe character is the "or" operator.
I've written this expression here.
This means that the string should have either A or B OK.
And then I have this dollar character.
It says that it matches at the end of line.
If I wanted to match this string using this expression,
that would mean that that string should end
with "c". That's definite, that string should end with "c".
Ok, so I just want you to play around with it and I
hope you're more familiar with Regular Expressions
and are able to write Regular Expressions. Next
we are going to move on to searching our Beautiful Soup parse tree.
And we'll use Regular Expressions while searching through tags and classes.
So, OK I think I'll see you in the next video and I
hope that you understand Regular Expressions
better now.
Thank you.