Hello everyone! In this section we're going to learn
how to navigate through our Beautiful Soup to access
different tags. Ok, so I have this HTML file here.
You can see it has the same structure,
I mean like the very basic one. It has a "head",
it has a "body" and in its "body" it has "b" tags like
this "b" tag first and then it has this "p" tag,
then another one and then another one. So there, basically,
body has four children and this "p" tag further
has three children which are "a" tags.
And if you consider navigable strings then there are more than four.
So how do we access these tags individually.
We're going to discuss this in this section.
So one of the very simple ways to do this
is that what we do is we use direct tag names
and access that tag through their names.
Right now I have written a very simple code which
reads this file and it returns me back this
file and then I have a soup of this file.
So if I pretty print it, I say "soup.prettify",
it gives me this tree. Exact this tree.
This is HTML tree. OK, so now let's
say I want to access this "title" tag.
So what can I do is.
I can say "title" is equals to "soup.title".
And if I print "title" now, we get "title" tag.
So this is a very simple way how we can access
any tag data directly through their tag names.
But the problem here is:
let's say I want to access this second "p" tag.
What will I do now.
I mean if I write "p" is equals to "soup.p".
If I print it,
it gives me the first "p" I have which says its
class is "title" but I want the "p" where the
class is "story".
This one here. I want the second
"p" tag, not the first one.
So the flow this method has is that it only gives me
the first available tag with this name.
So it gives me the first "p" tag
i comes across in my tree, which is this one.
So it gives us this "p" tag.
But as I wanted this one I have to consider some other
ways to get to this "p" tag. I can't do this
directly accessing the "p" tag name.
So in our future videos, what we are going to do is we are going
to learn how we can navigate through a tree like this and
move down our tree, accessing
different elements or different tags.
In our case like as we discussed this scenario, the second
"p" tag, how we can access these tags and
how we move through them.
Thank you very much.