Hello everyone! In this video we're going to discuss
how we can access our tags children and how we can
move through them.
So I'm going to use the previous HTML file we used in the previous example.
So in this file we have this "html" tag
which contains two children, "head" and "body".
This head contains one child, "title",
and then this "body" contains further children.
They are like this "b" tag, this "p" tag and other "p"
and then another "p".
So I think there are four. One, two, three, four...
Yes, there are four. So "body" has four children and "head" has
one child
and "html" has two children.
So how can I know that this tag contains this many children.
OK, so Beautiful Soup provides us with different methods to do access a tags children.
The first method is ".contents".
This is a method for any tag.
"Returns a list of children"
for that particular tag we're talking about.
So let's say "head" is equal to "soup.head".
And if I say print
"head.contents",
it returns me a list and this list contains this "\n".
This is a new line character because we're
reading from a file.
So we have these new line characters and we don't really need them.
They are basically garbage right now for us but
for indentation we have to have these new
line characters.
So just don't focus on them right now.
I mean it displays "title" tag which shows
that it has this "title" tag as its child.
OK.
And actually this is a list so I can iterate through
this. I can say "for child in head.content"
print "child" if "child" is not None.
So it gives me this "title" tag as its child.
So it had has only one child which is
the "title" tag. Let's move to "body" now.
Let's say I mean I'm just going to give you an example
of "body" that this is more clear and we'll
have new link for this, doing
that we just simply ignore them.
OK.
So I say "body" is equals to "soup.body".
And I say "body.contents".
So when I run this...
I think we need to make sure that we know there's a difference.
I think this should do this.
OK.
So this is one child. This is another child.
So two children.
This is another child. Three.
And lastly this is another child. Four.
So "body" has four children.
We are not really focusing on new line characters.
I'm sure (inaudible) here do.
So if I just printed this way
you can see it has this new line characters we're just
going to omit them for the time being because
we're dealing from a file.
So that's why they are here. When you're
actually scrapping from the internet.
I'm sure you won't encounter them.
It's very rare that this will happen and even if
that does happen you can just ignore them.
Like we're doing right now. OK, so if I run this, you
can see that body has four children and the method
I used to access body children were "body.contents".
This "contents" method returns a list of that
particular tags children. Just to crosschecked, you can
see body has four children. One, two, three and four.
OK, so now let's move to ".children" method.
This method basically returns an iterator or you can say
it returns a generator and through that generator
I can access the children of that
particular tag to which I call this method.
So let's stick to "body".
I have the body.
So I can say print
"type", "body.children". And if I run this, it says that
this is a list iterator. And if I say print "type",
"body.contents", it says it's a list. So you can tell
the difference between ".content" and the
".children".
So children is an iterator and I can use a
for loop to access the children
in "body".
So I mean I can just copy this here.
So
if I run this now, it gives the same as before but
the difference is that "body.children" returns an iterator
where ".contents" method returns a list of children.
So let's say a tree is huge.
So you wouldn't want a list of children in that case.
But I mean in that case an iterator would be preferable,
you would use the "children" method as compared to
the ".contents" method.
I hope that this is clear.
This is another example of how we can move
down our tree and how we can access a tag children.
So in the next video, we will to further study
how we can move down and the further methods
like the other methods Beautiful Soup provide us like
the "descendants" method and how that differentiates
from the "contents"
and our "children" methods. I hope this is clear.
Thank you very much.