Hello everyone! In the last video, we've discussed the
".contents" and ".children" methods of tags and how we can
access the children of any tag through these methods.
In this video, we're going to discuss
the method ".descendants" each tag has.
I mean like if you see the names "children" and "descendants",
they are pretty much the same thing.
But there's a difference.
Like a great one. If you see in this example here,
like this is we file we are using in the previous video
as well and I mean to use it in this one too.
So in this video, in this HTML file, you can see
that I have this "head" tag and it contains it in
the "title" tag which contained a navigable string.
So this navigable string is basically a child of this "head" tag.
And if I use the ".contents" method, should I get this as a child or not.
I mean up to now what we have seen,
I think we should get this as a child.
But if I say "head" is equals to "soup.head" and
I say "for child in soup.head", print "child",
you can see I don't really get this as a child.
I don't get this navigable string as a child here.
I can print the length. I can say print "head.contents".
And I can say print "len(head.contents)".
So you can see it has given me this list which in
its first index contains in a new line character and
second it contains the "title" tag and in the third
it contains another new line character. It gives me three,
the length three.
But in actual I mean it only contains one child
when we omit these new line characters.
So when we used ".contents" method it is giving us
one child but if we see this, this navigable string,
is also a child of "head".
So what's happening here.
So the issue with ".contents" method is that it only returns
any direct children of the said tag we are using it with.
So the direct children of "head" are... is only "title".
Navigable string is a child of "title", it is not a direct child of "head".
I'm just going to clarify this with another example.
Let's take "body" here. "body" contains four children: "b", "p"...
I mean four direct children: "b", "p", another "p",
another "p". And you can see these are four.
One, two, three, four. But if we see the children in here I mean there are different tags.
I have these eight.
See I'm not really counting them but if you really need to get all the children "body"
tag has, so these "a" tags too count two and these navigable strings, they do counting.
But when we use the ".contents" method it only returns us direct children.
"returns us direct children of the said tag".
I'm just going to show you this with "body".
I can say "body" is equals to "soup.body" and if I print
"body.contents" and I say print the length of "body.contents",
it gives me 9 and there are many new line characters here. So we can just omit them.
After that we're only going to get four or maybe I could just show you this. Just give me a sec.
"children"... I want to make my custom list and I'm to say "for child in" this, and I say "child",
"if child" does not equals to this. And now if I print "len(children)",
you can see I get four. And now if I print "children".
So the first element is the "b" tag, this one.
Second is this "p", class="title". Then I have
this "p".
And then lastly I have this "p". So it has four children, as you can see.
I mean four direct children. So the ".contents" method
returns us direct children of the said tag.
But when we talk about the descendants method,
this returns us all the children there are for any given
tag.
They're not really confined to direct children.
It is going to access all the children a tag has.
So for a very simple example, here "head" has two children, this "title" and this navigable string.
I mean if we count all the children.
It only has one direct child which is this "title" and all the children it has, the number is two here.
So this "descendants" returns us
all the children of the said tag and it returns us a generator.
So I can say "for index, child in enumerate".
I can say, talking about "head" here:
"soup.head.descendants".
Then can just print this, print "index" and I can say
print "child" if "child" does not equals to "\n" else this.
So if I run this, you can see it gives me two basically because this here is a "\n"
or, just to clarify, just to show you that it's really a "\n", I'm
just going to say "do this here" so that you know that
this is a "\n". Oh, I have to escape this. I'm
sorry.
So you can see, it contains a new line character and that the ending index contains another
new line character.
So we can just omit that.
So after that we only have two children.
The first one is the "title" tag and the second one is
the navigable string we have in that "title" tag.
So ".descendants" method returns us all the child
a particular tag has, regardless of the
fact that is that a direct child or it is a child of a child.
So I hope this is clear the ".contents" method
returns us direct children of the said tag. A very simple and a brief example is that this "title" is a direct
child of "head" whereas this navigable string is not a direct child of "head".
It is a direct child of "title".
And similarly this "head" tag has two children. Like if
we see all the children there are inside this "head" tag,
they are
the "title" tag and this navigable string.
I hope this is clear to you and I want you to play around
with this so that you're most familiar with
this and how this works.
So thank you very much.