Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed how we can
move up our parse tree. In this video, we are going to discuss how
we can move downwards in our parse tree.
As we discussed earlier, there are three
types of basic movements in our parse tree.
One is that we move downwards.
Let's say from the "html" level to this "body"
and then to this "p" and then do this "b.
So I have been moving downwards in this scenario.
Another is that it moves upwards. Let's say if I'm at this
"b" tag, I move to this "p", then to this "body", then
to this "html". In upwards, we are moving towards a parent,
and in downwards, we are moving towards a child.
Then there's this third type of movement which we are
going to discuss today. That is like we move sideways.
If I'm at this "p" tag, I move to this "b" or to this
"p" or to this "p". When you make a tree of this
HTML, we can see that these all tags, this "b" tag, this
"p" tag, this "p" and this "p", they are the same level.
We can call them siblings.
So I've read this file here and I made a soup of
this file here then I have my "body" tag and
and I have to first "p" tag.
So if I print "p".
It gives me the "p" tag with
"class='title'", which is this here.
OK, so
now what I want to do is I
want to move at the same level.
So either I want to get to this B or I want
to get to this "p" tag which has "class='story'".
So what can I do know? If I print "body.contents",
you can see that the first child of "body" is this
new new line character which we are going to
omit, we are not going to consider that.
Then the first child is this "b" tag.
Then the next child is this "p" tag and the next child is then
again a new line character which we are not going to consider
as a child and then we have the story one.
So what we want to do is: currently we are
here at this tag and we want to move to "p" here.
So what can we do.
So I mean we have to move two places. Like in one place,
I have this new line character and if I move to
the right again then I could go to this "p" tag.
So I'm just going to run so it's more clear.
Now we have this function in Beautiful Soup, this tag function.
What this does is if I say print "p.next_sibling"
and then again "next_sibling".
The reason I'm doing this "next_sibling" again is because
as you can see that I have this new line character
which I have to omit.
So if I do this once and
if I run it, this doesn't give me anything because it's
a new line character that just prints a new line.
So if I do it twice.
You see I have moved to the next "p" tag.
So I've successfully moved to the next "p" tag.
I've moved sideways successfully.
So this can be done like
if you are at our "head", we could move to this
"body" tag using the same method, "next_sibling".
So the "next_sibling" method, what this does
is this allows us to move sideways in our parse tree.
It allows us to move to our siblings, our next siblings.
In the next video, we will discuss how to move
to our previous siblings.
Let's say I'm at this "body". How do I move to "head"?
I can't do that with that next sibling
because "body" has no next sibling. "body" is the last sibling,
"head" has next sibling which is this "body"
tag here.
So I hope this is clear to you and I'll elaborate this more.
Once we get to "previous_sibling" and we'll discuss this more there then.
Thank you.