Hello everyone!
In the last video, we discussed the "next_sibling" method of a tag.
In this video, we are going to discuss the "previous_sibling"
method of a tag. As we saw earlier in our previous
video, we saw that if I'm at this "p" tag, I could move
this "p" tag using not using the ".next_sibling" method.
And similarly I could move to this, the last "p" tag,
which is the last tag which is the last
last sibling here of this tag.
So with the "next_sibling" we can go forward. We
can actually move forward over tags or other
tag siblings. So we have a method in Beautiful
Soup which allows us to move backwards as well.
It allows us to move backwards.
Like if I'm here I can move to this "b" tag or this
"p" tag using a method which will allow me to
walk over my siblings backwards.
The "next_sibling" method what it does was it
allowed us to walk forwards over our siblings.
This method here, "previous_sibling", it allows
us to move backwards over our sibling tags.
So what I'm to do now is I've made a soup of this file
here, this "three_sisters.html" and now I am going to
print the contents of my HTML.
OK, so you can see I have this "body" tag here.
OK.
And before that "body" tag I have a new line
character which we are going to ignore.
And then I have this "head" tag.
So what I want to do now is I say that I'm at "body"
and I want to move back to my previous sibling.
So we are going to do that now and see how we do this.
So I have this "body" variable which is the
"body" tag. "body" is equals to "soup.body".
So what I do is I say print, and
comment this here. I say for print
"body.previous_sibling".
This will give me the new line character.
This one here. We don't want that, we
want to move our "head" tag.
So if I just run this, you can see it
gives me nothing except for a new line.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to have to
input this again and just say "previous_sibling"
So if I do this, now it gives me the "head" tag.
You can see this here.
So using this "previous_sibling" method,
we've successfully moved backwards to our "head" tag.
And we were at our "body" tag initially and using
this method we have gone to our "head" tag.
So we have discussed right now two
ways of moving sideways. One is
that we move moved downwards, like to the next siblings,
and other method is the "previous_sibling", like
we move backwards to our previous siblings.
This example illustrates this concept better.
If I'm at body,
I can move backwards to "head".
So I'll use "previous_sibling" method. And if I'm at the "head"
and I have to move to "body", I'll use the "next_sibling"
method.
OK.
So next we'll discuss the methods "next_siblings"
and "previous_siblings". I hope up till now
this is clear to you.
And thank you very much.
See you soon.