Hello everyone.
In the last video, we talked about the "previous_sibling"
method of a tag and we saw that if I am in
this "body" tag I could use that method to move to this "head" tag.
And similarly if I am in this "head" tag, I could use the
"next_sibling" method to move to this "body" tag.
So now the question is: if I'm at this "b" tag and I want
to see how many siblings I have or what siblings
I have.
So what do I do.
One way is to use a loop and call the "next_sibling"
method again and again to see at which sibling I am right
now.
I mean like doing that what I lose is all this
outside the ".next_sibling", I come across this "p",
then I can move to this, then I can move to this.
And now I'm at the very end. If I call the "next_sibling"
method again it is going to return me "None".
And I know that I have no further
next sibling after this "p" tag.
But this is a very inefficient version of doing things.
Beautiful Soup writes us with a built-in method
which returns us a list of all the next siblings for a particular tag.
So right now I have a "p" tag which is the first "p" tag.
I mean it's this "p" tag here.
This "p class='title'" one.
So you can see if I'm going to move
towards my next siblings, I only have two.
I have this "p" and this "p". I am omitting the new
line characters. So I'm just going to print this
"p" here.
So just, you know, like which "p" this is.
So this is the "title" one and if I get
back to my document, you can see this one.
And I have two further "p" tags. OK, let's move forward then. I say "for sibling in p.next_siblings",
I say print "sibling" if sibling does not
equal to a new line character else
print this. And if I run it.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I should say print "sibling.name".
OK, so if I run this, it ives me two "p" tags. And
if I am at this "p" tag here, I only have two further
siblings which are two "p" tags. This and this.
So this method returns us a list of my next siblings. OK.
Similarly if a wanted to know the previous siblings,
one way was that I could do this manually by having
a loop
and updating my previous sibling value. The other way
is what I'd do is I have this method, this built-in
method, which gives me a list of my previous siblings.
So I say "for sibling
in p.previous_siblings", I say print "sibling"
if "sibling" does not equal to "\n" else...
If I run this, it gives me "b". And you can see if I am at
this "p" tag here, it only has one previous sibling which is this
one, this "b" tag here.
OK.
So these were two methods and which
returns us a list and we have the whole
siblings now.
If we use this, we have the whole next sibling and
if you use this, we are all the previous siblings.
So we have discussed three ways of navigating our parse tree.
One is that we move up, one as that we move down
and the last one which we discussed right now is moving
sideways. Next, what we are going to do is we are
going to discuss RegEX, or regular expressions.
And after doing that, we are going to move to searching data
in our parse tree and how we do that because I mean
you can only navigate through your parse tree
if you know what you expect to find.
But what if you have like let's say you have
10000 lines of code and you have ten thousands of
thousands of tags in there.
I mean you really can't navigate that much, can you?
And if you do, that's going to be very inefficient.
Like checking each tag to see if that's the one you want.
So when you get to searching after doing regular
expressions which are going to help us search. I hope
this section is clear to you and we'll move forward then with regular expressions.
Thank you very much.