Hello everyone!
In the last video, we discussed how we can move down in our parse tree.
Like if I'm at my "body", how can I access the "body" children individually. It happens actually
moving through them.
And how I could access the direct children or all the children, discussed the ".contents",
the ".children", the
".descendants" method for doing these.
In this video, we are going to discuss now how
we are going to actually move up a parse tree.
Let's say I am at this "p" tag here and I want to move up
towards the enclosing tag.
I mean towards the parent of this tag.
How do we do that.
There are
in general, when we speak about this area like you could say three kinds of movements.
One is that we go down our tree like I'm at my HTML
and I am moving down. One is that I and moving up. Let's
say I am at this "p" tag and I want to move to the parent of this "p"
tag which is this "body" here.
The third one we can say is the movement we have sideways.
So if I'm at this "p" tag, I could say how can
we move to this "b" tag or how could I move
to this "p" tag or the other "p" tag.
So in general we can get (inaudible). There
are three kinds of movements in a parse tree.
One is that moving down, one is that moving up
and the last one is that moving sideways.
So we've discussed how we actually moved down our parse tree
in the previous videos we did. In this video
and the next one, we're going to discuss
how we can move up our parse tree.
So we have a method in Beautiful Soup
for moving up our parse tree.
So I'm using the same HTML file I used for moving
down the parse tree. I am using the same HTML file
because I think this would simplify things more.
I mean you can actually compare how you're moving down
and up in a HTML file and better to create
concepts this way.
OK, so I have the soup here of this file.
And then what I do is I extract the "title" tag. I say "soup.title".
So I have "title" tag here.
Now what I want to do is I want to move up to the parent
of this "title" tag, which in our case right now
is "head". How can I do this? I can say "parents"
is equals to "title.parent".
And if I print
"parent.name"... If you remember, we have a method ".name"
of a tag which gives us that tag's name.
If I run this, it says "head".
And if I remove this ".name"
You can see it returns this, the "head" tag, or the
parent of this "title" tag. We can do this for any tag.
I mean I am going to show you this with this "p" tag here.
I am going to say "p" is equals to "soup.p". And
if I print "p", it gives me this "".
So it is giving me this "p" tag.
Now what I'm doing is I'm going to say "p.parent".
So it actually gives me this "body" tag.
And as you can see, this "p" tag has this
"body" tag as its parent. This "b" tag and this
"p" tag and this "p" tag, they're its siblings.
So the relation we have between "body" and "p" is that
"body" is a parent tag and this "b" and other "p" tags
are siblings of this "p" tag here,
this "p" tag which has its "class='title'".
So I could just say "p.parent.name".
And you can see it gives me "body".
So, as you know, our tree starts from "soup",
and after "soup" we have its child, "html", and
after "html" we have its children, "head" and "body",
and so on.
I mean it depends on our document.
So if I say "html" is equals to "soup.html",
the question is: Who is the parent of html?
If I say print "type(html.parent)"
it says beautiful soup is the parent of HTML.
OK, so hierarchy is: we have Beautiful Soup at the topmost level.
It is the parent of every tag in parse tree.
And then we have the "html" tag and then as a
document, I mean depends on the document. If we have "head"
and "body", then it has two direct children,
"head" and "body" and then further.
So the first one is "bs4", next one is "html".
So at the very top level,
we have Beautiful Soup as the parent of each
bag, each object we have in our parse tree.
So now the question is: Who
is the parent of Beautiful Soup?
I just said that Beautiful Soup is the parent
into every tag or object in our parse tree.
So this method, if I say print
"soup.parent", it returns me "None".
Just going to comment this so this is clear.
You can see it returns me "None".
It says that there is no parent of Beautiful Soup.
So the hierarchy is: Beautiful Soup is the
parent of each tag we have in our parse tree,
then the "html" tag and then it depends on the document.
In our case we have two children, two direct children for "html"  tag.
They are "head" and "body" and then "head" has
"title" and "body" has further four children.
I hope this is clear to you.
That how we can access a tag's parent with ".parent" method.
In the next video, we will be discussing the ".parents"
method which returns us a list of the parents and we can
iterate over them.
Thank you very much.