Hello everyone! In the last video,
we discussed how we can move up our
parse tree.
A quick preview, if I have this "p" tag,
how can access this "body" tag here,
its parent.
In this video, we are going to discuss the ".parents" method.
The ".parents" method basically is that
how we can access all the parents of a particular tag.
So this method returns us a list of parents.
By list
I mean it returns us a generator and you can
actually iterate with this generator to
get the parents, all the parents, of a particular tag.
So let's say I'm going to access this first "a" tag.
You can see this "a" tag has its first parent as this "p" tag,
the story one, and then this "p" tag has its parent as this "body" tag.
And then this body has this "html" and "html"
has this Beautiful Soup of the document as its parent.
So I say "link" is equals to "soup.a" which
gives me this "a" tag here because this always
gives us the first occurrence of a particular tag.
So we have "link" is equals to "soup.a".
And if I print "link",
You can see it gives me the first "a" tag I have.
So this one. "id" is equals to "link1", so you can see the match.
So if I say "link.parents",
it says it returns us a generator object.
It says "generator object parents at"
this address.
And if I use "link.parent", it returns me the "story",
this "p" tag which has its "class='story'". So
let's just use ".name". So the direct parent of the
"a" tag is this "p" tag, you can see that here.
I wrote "link.parent.name".
So now what are we going to do is we are going to iterate
for this parents of this "a" tag and who are they.
So I say "for parents in link.parents", I say print
"parent". So this "parent" gives me the tag and if I print
this it is going to give me the whole values
for these tags which would be like
printing basically the whole document.
So I'm going to say "parent.name".
I hope you remember the ".name" method returns
the name of a particular tag. If I run this now,
you see it gives us the first parent which
is the "p" tag because this "a" tag has the
"p" tag as its parent and then this "p" tag
has this "body" tag as this parent.
You can see that here.
And then this "body" tag has "html" as its parent, you can
see that here. And then "html" has a document or Beautiful
Soup as its parent. So the ".parents" method returns
us a generator which is a list of all the
parents we have for that particular tag will ring
till we reach the Beautiful Soup or the document object
in our parse tree. I hope this is clear.
In the next videos, we would be moving sideways
in our parse tree. We have covered how we can move
down our parse tree like if I'm at the document or if I am
at this "html" tag, how can I access any of this "a" tag
or this "p" tag or any other tags, we've done that
and we've also discussed how we can move up our parse tree.
I was at this "a" tag and I wanted to move to
this body tag, how can I do that.
We can move through our parents using this ".parents"
method and then we can do whatever we want
to while moving
through them and we can manipulate the tags or we could get the data.
I mean we can do whatever we want with them this way.
And now we're going to discuss how we can move sideways in the parse tree.
Thank you very much.