Hello everyone! Today we will discuss how web sites are hosted on servers and how do we access them.
So let's go with a very simple scenario.
What happens is that a user opens his browser and then, let's say, he inputs there
"Google.com".
So what the browser does is: browser sends the request to Google server.
Server receives this request and processes it and then server returns response to browser. Browser
displays the response the server sent and then Google home page opens which the user can now see.
So the basic workflow is: user sends a request, server gets it.
Server processes it and then sends the response back to the user.
So the user is able to see what the server has sent which in our case right now is the Google home page.
So this is how web sites are basically hosted on servers.
I mean like a very basic view of how this works.
A request to send by user, server receives request, processes it and then sends back a response.
I hope this is very simple and I hope this is clear to you right now.
Thank you very much.