Hello everyone! In this lecture we're going to discuss HTML.
HTML, or HyperText Markup Language, is a format system which is used to display graphics, text, audio
over the internet.
I'm sure all of you are familiar with HTML and I'm just going to put a review to the most basic
elements in HTML.
So in HTML have tags. A dog is a hidden keyword which sets the layout, how a browser
is going to display the content in that tag.
So here in this sample HTMl page I have one, two, three, four, five, six, seven tags.
So if I open this "tags.txt", I have written them down.
I have html, head, meta, title, body,
p and p. So if I run this on the browser, you'll see I get this here.
So this  tag here is defining that whatever comes here, whatever comes between these tags has
the color blue.
So if I see it here, I have this text here, the string here.
It says some text here and it's in blue.
So the next  tag I have has a "font-style: italic" and you can see that this text here is italic.
So the style thing, that's an attribute of the p tag, we call these attributes.
This is an attribute.
So the  tag here has a attribute style is equal to "color: blue".
And its font-style is italic. You can think of a HTML page as a tree, or having a tree structure.
For this file,
the tree would be that on the very top. I have HTML and then it has two children's: head and body. Then
heads for the two childrens: meta and title. And body has again two children P and P.
So this is a very basic summary of what HTML is and how we can interpret HTML
so that in future we are able to parse it efficiently.
I'm sure I've made myself clear and thank you very much for your time.