Welcome everybody to this course.
Merely glad that all of you are here.
Thank you again for checking out this course.
So I'll start up explaining what scrapping is as this course is all about web scrapping.
So in simple and brief terms, scrapping is extracting data from the Internet.
Why do we need to do that?
That's a valid question.
Why do we need to extract data from the Internet?
So we live in an age where everything is being uploaded on the internet.
Like daily terabytes of data is being uploaded on the Internet.
And with such amount of data you could to perform analysis and you would actually improve a lot of things
that if you're a businessman and if you're launching your product, you can learn more about the market
like "OK, what do people like?" How they...
How early, you know, how will they respond to your product launch or how can you improve
your product.
But all of this information is on the Internet.
So you need some tool, you need some way to actually get that information out of the Internet.
One way would be too hard.
Hundreds of persons to do this stuff or the other way, the smart way, would be that he'd write a computer
program which does this for you, you know, and conserves your resources.
So this is what web scrapping is about.
So the next question is what is this course about. This course is about like how can we access web pages
programmatically, you know. We'll be using Python for this course.
So this course will teach us how we can parse a web page, extract required data,
to extract data from that page. Like let's say you want to get photos from some web page you
know how are you going to do that.
Let's say there are thousands of photos.
Don't tell me that you're going to download each of them individually, you know.
I mean that is going to take a lot of time.
So we will learn how to parse a web page and extract our required data from our web pages.
So we will cover this stuff in this course.
And next, you know, Python has this module which is known as Beautiful Soup.
This is a parser for parsing web pages.
We'll learn this too in this course.
So in this course we'll also learn how we can interact differently with our pages and how we can move
around.
And later on with them you know do different stuff.
So we'll also learn that and you could say that it is an introduction to
automation, in automating different stuff on the Internet.
You can say that in simple terms.
So we'll be using Selenium for interacting with web pages in this course.
So to like, you know, to sum it up, to sum this question, you know, like for daunt of this question.
I can say that briefly that's about how we can extract data from any kind of web page using a programming
language.
In our case, it is going to be Python.
So the last thing is that what will you learn by the end of this course.
At the end of this course you
will have a deep understanding of how web sites and servers function. Like how are websites hosted and
how do they send requests to servers, what are servers, what are Web sites and how does this
communication take place.
So you'll have a deeper understanding of how this works, how all of this works.
Then you'll learn different extraction techniques which are being used worldwide, you know, the best
practices, the worst practices, things you have to worry, things you have to keep in mind while you
are scrapping data, you know, and how can you do this in an efficient manner.
You'll learn this by the end of this course.
So and, you know, like we will also learn how to
handle a lot of data and how we can actually parse that data.
And, you know, get it in the required format we want.
So I really look forward to.
I really look forward to teaching in this course. So I hope that you're excited about this.
So I think let's get to our first tutorial so I'll see you soon in the next video.
Thank you.