Hello everyone! For this course we are going to use an IDE for Python which is PyCharm.
So what you do is you go to Google and you write "download pycharm" on the first link which opens here
you open it up.
I've opened it and it's here.
So from here this tab gives me the option to download this IDE PyCharm and
it is provided for different operating systems like for Mac OS, Windows and Linux. It has two versions: Community
and Professional.
We don't need Professional and it is also paid.
So what we do with you know Community works for us.
We download it and you can just download it from here.
I've already downloaded it. After you have downloaded it.
You install it in your system and after doing that you just run that.
So now I'm opening PyCharm. After the installation you open PyCharm and then this window opens
up.
You say create new project and here you give it the bars like where you want your project to be.
So I say, you know, by making a folder on my Desktop, "web scrapping tutorials", and it create a project.
So this has created a Python project on my Desktop. Now create a test file just to test if
my Python file works or not.
And here I say "print('Hello world')".
So I run this and you can see that it works.
I can run it again and it works.
So this project is working.
So this is where, you know, we will continue our whole course.
And before we move forward with our course what I want you to do is I want you to download some of the
necessary modules which we will be using in our course.
So how do we do that.
You go to this this project, double click on it and then this opens up, you say "new",
"file" and here you make a file "requirements.txt".
So what I'm gonna do now here is that I'm going to list all the modules which I'm going to use in my course and
PyCharm is automatically going to download and install them for me.
So I've made a list here, it's there. And I say Command-C
and Command-V so I'm sorry for this.
OK.
So here are the modules which we will be using for our course.
So what PyCharm is going to do now is it is going to download them install them for you itself
so you don't really need to worry about them anymore.
And in the next video when we start our course and I hope up till now that this is clear you and you
successfully install these modules as you will be using them extensively throughout our course.
Thank you very much.