Hello everyone!
In the last video we discussed user agents and how we can imitate our browser.
In this video we are going to start with Beautiful Soup.
Beautiful Soup is a parser which we use to parse HTML data.
If you remember, all HTML files can be thought of having a tree structure
like the file we had when I discussed HTML was this.
We had this HTML file,
we had this HTML tag and then it had two children, "head" and "body", and then "header" had further
two children and "body" had further two children.
So if I make that tree, it would be like HTML, would be the parent. HTML has two children, head
and body, and head has further two children, "meta" and "title", and "body" had further two children,
two paragraphs tags. So what we do is we have a parser which is known as Beautiful Soup in Python
which parses this tree and we can access each tag individually.
OK, so for this you need to install two packages, bs4 and lxml.
bs4 is a Beautiful Soup package, and lxml
is another parser and external dependency.
It works
if you don't have lxml but it's prefered if you have it.
OK.
So what I do is I have this file here, this HTML file here.
You can see it has these tags. In the "body" I have two div's.
In the first div
I have further a "p" tag and then in the another "div" I have another "p" tag.
OK, so what I do is I have a function which reads this file, this HTML file, and gives this file back
to me.
So I read it, I say "html_file" is equal to "read_file".
And if I run that.
You can see I have my HTML file here.
This one.
So this function is just reading this HTML file.
Nothing else.
This one.
To be clear of this.
OK, so what we do is we make a soup out of this HTML file. By soup
I mean we make a tree out of this.
And from that tree we can access each element individually.
So the syntax for making a soup or a tree out of an HTML file is we write "BeautifulSoup", this
class we took and its constructor
takes two parameters:
the HTML file which we want to parse and the parser.
So I write "soup" is equal to "BeautifulSoup".
I give it a HTML file
I am parsing and here I give it the parser which is "lxml".
If you haven't installed "lxml" you can just write "html.parser".
OK.
OK, so this will create a soup, this line will create a soup of this HTML file.
So if I print soup
I get the HTML file which it has parsed.
OK so there's a method the soup has which is "soup.prettify". What this does is this...
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't print that.
What this method does is it prints the HTML file using the correct indentation.
So I mean it is more neat this way.
OK. So I want you to identify some tags here, like which tags are present in this HTML file.
First we have this one, then HTML, then "head", then "meta", then "title".
Then I have my "body", then "div", then "p", then another "div" and another "p".
And there we go.
So these were tags here and this is how we make a soup out a HTML file. In the next video
we will discuss how to use requests and Beautiful Soup together, how
to make a soup out of a website HTML.
So thank you very much.