Hello everyone!
In the last video we discussed how to make
a soup out of a HTML file. By soup
I mean the way we parsed our HTML file and the tree. OK, so in this video we are going to discuss how
to make a soup out of any website
HTML. In our case, we are going to send a request to Google to receive the HTML version of Google,
I mean the response Google servers send us back, and we have to make a soup out of it.
So right now I have this header which is basically saying that I'm Crome and I'm sending a request
to "Google.com".
So if I print this "google_page.content", this response content, you can see this sent me the HTML
for the home page of Google.
That's the string here.
OK, so how do we make a soup.
We say "soup" is equals to "BeautifulSoup".
And the first parameter was the HTML file which in our case is "google_page.content" and next parameter
is the parser I'm using. I'm using "lxml" and if you don't have it installed you could use the "html.parser".
Just write it down.
OK.
So now I have made a soup out of this HTML file and a if I print it.
Pretty print it.
Sorry.
You can see
that I have the Google home page HTML here.
And just to quickly go now, I just want to quickly go over some tags here so that we are familiar what
tags are and how this tree is structured.
We have HTML tag, we have "head" tag, we have "link" tag, we have "script" tag and these are all tags.
OK.
And the tree is structured like HTML is the parent of everyone here.
And it has two children, "head" and "body". Normal too, I mean almost each HTML file is structured this way.
OK, we have here that body structure and then body as for the children and similarly had this for the
children.
OK, so I think you're more familiar with how we can make a tree out of any website HTML and how to pretty print
this. Next we are going to discuss how to access these tags like a very basic version of it and how
to access some attributes of these tags and how the different tags methods work.
Thank you.