Hello everyone! In this video we will be discussing how we access tags, their attributes and how we can modify
them.
OK.
So for this file, for this video, I'm to use this HTML file.
I have this "html", this
"head", this "body".
I have two "div"s and have two "p" tags in them.
OK, so an attribute of a tag is this.
This here. This "class" is an attribute of this "body" tag.
This "charset" is an attribute of this "meta" tag.
The "styl"e is an attribute of this "p" tag.
So this is an attribute.
And they can have multiple attributes like a "class" and also have "style". So, OK. So you know.
OK, so how do we access tags.
The very basic method is that, let's say, I want to access this meta tag here what I'd do is I
say "meta" is equal to "soup.meta". What this is going to do is this is going to give
me this meta tag, the first occurrence of this tag.
And if I print meta begin, we can see I get that tag here, the exact thing.
That's one.
So again, what this does is this gives me the first occurrence of the tag I am trying to access.
So I mean I have two div's.
All right let's I want to get to this div.
What am I going to do is to say "div" is equal to "soup.div".
And if I print "div" I get this here.
Div, in first div, but if I want to get the second "div", it's not that simple. I can't access the second "div"
using this, only this "soup.div".
This won't give me the second "div".
This only gives me the first occurrence of "div" and in our case it's this one.
This one here.
It's the first time this "div" occurs in our HTML document starting from the very top.
So when we write "soup." some tag, that gives the first occurrence of that tag.
OK, so I was accessing meta tag here.
I said "soup.meta" is equal to "meta", and if I print "meta"
I get that tag here, that meta tag. Ok, so some commonly used tag methods are if I want to get the
attributes of meta tag, it has, you can see, an attribute "charset".
So if I say print "meta.get('charset')".
This is going to give me the value of this attribute.
As you can see "charset" has the value "UTF-8" and if I run this get method I get this.
So get method can be used to get the value of any attribute.
OK.
And let's say I input an invalid key, an invalid attribute.
So what it does is it says none.
It didn't get it.
None means that this attribute didn't exist.
It did not get this attribute.
OK, so you can also treat this as a dictionary.
I could write
"meta['charset']".
So it gives me "UTF-8".
So like there are in general two methods in which you can access any tag attributes. One is "get()" and
other is treating it like a dictionary.
OK.
So we can actually modify these attributes at runtime.
Let's say I want to change the value of this "charset".
Or maybe let's make it interesting.
I want to input something here in "style". You can see body style has nothing right now.
So what I do when I say "body", first I access my body tag, "soup.body".
This gives me the first ocurrance of body  and fortunately only have one body in the document.
OK.
So if a print "body",
you can see I have the whole "body" here, the whole "body" tag and what it contains. OK, so now I'm going to
access this "style" tag. I'm going to say "body" and "style".
And if I run it and it gives it blank because I don't have anything
in "style". Now I want to set something for the style tag.
I can say "body['style']" is equal to some style.
and if I print it now
you can see it gives me "some style". So at runtime it has changed the value of this style attribute. It is
very helpful
When you are trying to parse something, like parse different tags and you want to maintain
the check, so you could have your own tag attributes.
And it would keep checks this way by changing their value that "yes, you have already fetched the contents
from there".
I mean it depends on what you are doing.
So this is how we modify a tag attribute.
OK, so now there's this concept of multi-valued attributes.
As you can see body here has an attribute
"class" and it has two classes. The attribute "class" has two classes, the first and second.
If you're familiar with CSS, you know we can have a lot of classes here.
I mean all of these classes would apply to this tag, to this "body" tag.
So this is a multivalued attribute.
So how do we access this it's same, it's not different.
I say "body['class']".
But what's different is this time it is going to give me a list.
It will return me a list and not a single value.
So if you have a multivalued attribute that will always be a list and not a single value. You should
keep this in mind when you are accessing tags attributes and parsing them.
Ok ,so today we discussed how to access tags, the very basic version of tags, and how we can access the
tags attributes and change their values or modify them.
I hope this is clear.
Next we'll move to some more
advanced stuff and navigating our soup and how we can access
different tags, and their children, and their
parents.
Thank you very much.