Hello everyone! In the last lecture we talked about tags
and how we can access our tags attributes and
modify them.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about bits of text
that are present in some of the tags. Like this "title"
tag here contains this text "Intro_to_soup" or the
"p" tag here, it contains "In first div".
And the second "p" tag contains "In second div".
So I want to make you more familiar with these tags.
In Beautiful Soup,
We call them navigable strings.
We call them, I will write this down, navigable strings.
They are parsed as objects.
So how do we access these strings.
Let's say I want to get this string inside this "title" tag.
So what I do is I get the "title" first.
I say "title" is equals to "soup.title",
then I say print "title.string". And if I run it,
it gives me "Intro_to_soup".
And if I run "print(title)", it gives me the whole tag.
So to get the string enclosed in a tag what we do is each tag has a method ".string".
And if that tag has a string object or it is enclosing some kind of string,
some navigable string, it prints it like as it did here.
So this navigable string object has another function which is ".replace_with".
So what we can do with this is we can actually replace the contents of the string.
I'm just going to show you an example here. You can comment this first to make it more neat.
So I say I have the title here.
I can say "title.string.replace_with" and
"title has been changed".
So what I did was I said "title.string".
Now I got the navigable string object here and now I say ".replace_with" and "title has been changed".
And let's print "title" now to see if there is any change in the title tag or not.
And if I print, it says "title has been changed".
And before doing this if I print "title", it says "Intro_to_soup".
So this function ".replace_with"
is a function of a navigable string and what it does
is it changes the contents of the navigable
string.
So you can actually change the contents of any navigable string
in Beautiful Soup using this
".replace_with" function.
I hope this is more clear to you and I would like
you to go through this yourself and practice,
you know.
Just play with this and access different tags and
try to access the strings and then modify them.
Thank you very much.