Hello everyone!
Today we will discuss requests.
Like how we send requests to a server and how we receive an object response back from the server as
we discussed earlier.
When you open a website on a browser, what happens is that a user sends a request which is you typing
a URL of a website that you want to open and hitting Enter.
Server receives that request and then sends back a response to the user which, in the browser scenario,
the website opens
once you press enter after you are in.
So how can we emulate this
in Python. In Python we have a module Request which lets us do this.
There are four types of requests.
So by that I mean that there are four different ways in which I can send requests to server.
Only two are more commonly used.
The most commonly used ones are GET and POST. The GET type request is mostly used to retrieve information.
Whenever you want to fetch some data from server,
use a GET request. And a POST request is normally used to send information to server.
Again I'm saying they're normally used for this purpose.
I'm not saying that this is the only purpose they use for.
So just to keep it simple, GET is used to retrieve information and POST is used to send
information and requests.
Let's assimilate all of this.
So how do we do this.
We have a method "requests.get()". Let's assimilate a GET request.
So what it receives in its parameter is a URL which you want to open.
OK.
And this line return us our response object.
I'll just show you this within an example and I hope things will be more clear then. I say
"request.get()".
And I'm going to open Google using requests. So if I print response
now
you can see what happened.
What happened was that when I typed this is the same as typing Google.com in my browser.
So the Google server
receives a request and then sent back a response which is this object here this response with even
alike name.
I've named it response. And if print it says me "".
I'll just explain what 200 is, the status code and I'll just get to them.
So our response, whenever we send a request we'll receive a response and to see what the response is,
the contents of response are, what we do is there is a method which is "response.content" and print
response.content. So run that. You can see I have the HTML which the Google servers have sent to me if I
copy this in an HTML file and run it, you'll see that I have the Google home page with me.
This is in the single line right now.
I mean it is not formatted so it means you may not be able to understand this but
you can see the tags, the starting backs and "doctype" and then the HTML tag.
And if you move further, you can see this meta tag here and this goes on.
So what I received was like as soon as the sent a request to Google server,
the Google server sent me back a response. And to see the content of the response,
I have this method "response.content".
And if I print this I get this. This HTML which the Google servers have sent to me.
OK.
So what are this codes.
Whenever a server sends back a response,
it also sends back a status code. This code is a three digit integer value.
And that indicate how the server processed
our request.
So let's say you open some pages which is just not there.
And whatwill happen there is it will send back an error status code indicating
that
there is an error.
So if I run, I say "print(response.status_code)".
and I ran that and I guess it says 200.
So I mean like from 100 to 199 status codes mean that the service
is sending us back some information, like it could be anything related to the information
like the request we send to the server. From 200 to 299,
this status code indicates that our request was processed successfully. From 300 to 399,
is that whatever the request was,
it has been redirected either to another server or URL,
it has been redirect. And 400 to 499 are client based error code.
This indicates that there is some error on our side and we sent the wrong request or maybe we
didn't have the privilege to send such a request.
And so it goes from five hundred to 599 indicate that the server when processing
on request had some error and it sent us back
this status code that OK that the fault this time was at the servers end
and not at that side.
So I mean each time you send a request, you can check back this status code of the response object to see
if you received a... like
if your request was one of success or not.
OK, so the way to do this is like I have this method "response.status_code".
It gives me back the status code which the server has sent to me OK.
So there there are also headers encoded in their response which the servers sent us back. By headers
I mean I'll just show you.
So that will clarify things more I think.
So the method for headers is "response.headers" and headers are basically a dictionary which
the server returns us and I can say print
response.headers and if I run this now
you can see it as a dictionary and if you remember a way to iterate what a dictionary is you say
"for key, value in
response.header.items():".
Print
and then value. You run this now.
You can see I have the date.
This is the day the server sent us back our response.
It says when this is going to expire. By expire it means like, you know, there are
cookies there and how they work and this "expires" is for that.
So here we have "Cache-Control".
This "Content-Type" and a whole lot of other things which I don't think you really need to
know about them but it's good to know that these are returned with our response
object.
So today we learn about three things: how we send a request to server and hopefully receive back a response
and how the different methods of response like the content method, the status_code and the headers.
I hope I've made myself clear.
And if you have any issues please let me know.
Thank you.