Hello everyone! In the previous with you, we discussed how to send a simple GET request to the server and
receive a response object, and how to interpret that response object.
In this video we are going to discuss user agents. A user agent is a software which act on the behalf of a user.
By that I mean when you open Google through a browser, your browser which you are using, let's say
Google Chrome.
So your Chrome browser is acting on your behalf and sending a request to the Google server saying that
my user wants to open "Google.com" and Google receives this request and then sends back a response
object.
So when it does that, when it sends that request.
What it does is it adds a header to that request which shows like
it states that it is a Google Chrome browser which is sending that request on the
behalf of the user.
So when we normally send requests to a server when using this request
module we're not adding any header there which indicates that a robot or a program is sending this request
to a server, let it be sending a request to Google server.
So the Google Google will know that a program or piece of code is sending this request to its servers and
as we saw previously when you send a request to Google, it did return us a response.
But there are some sites which have a very strict policy and they don't allow programs to
send requests to the server.
And fear that their servers may crash
if you do this in a loop.
So the servers may crash because they would be excess traffic and they wouldn't be able to handle
that much traffic by sending response to each one.
So what they do is they block out codes or robots this way.
So what we can do is we can fake our user agent, we can fake this,
we can show to the servers that basically we are a browser which is sending a request and
not just a piece of code.
So how do we do this?
There is this package, fake_useragent.
You can install it by having a "requirements.txt" file in your project, which I have made here, in your
Python project.
OK you make it here and then you write "fake_useragent"
and you press Ctrl+S or if you're using Mac OS you could press Command+S. And then you get
back.
I've already installed fake_useragent so it doesn't ask me to install it.
But if you haven't done that, it will ask you to install fake_useragent and you can just click
yes and it will install it automatically.
So what you do is you get this module fake_useragent and then you import
this class UserAgent from this module.
After doing that what we do is we write "ua", I mean I'm using "ua,
I say UserAgent and then make an instance of this class.
After that I make a header, I say, "header" is a dictionary. I say "user-agent",
"ua.chrome". Let's say I am emulating Chrome here.
So our dictionary, the key is "user-agent" and the value is "ua.chrome".
So if you just print this, ua.chrome, you'll see
it says me Mozilla this, this, this, this, this. This is the required header which Chrome sends
every time it sends a request to the server, to any website it's opening.
So this time we are going to send a request to Google. We say "requests.get" and
now I'm going to add a header here, I say header.
Header is basically a dictionary which you're adding here.
OK.
And I can print it now.
I'm sorry it's "headers", it's
not "header". I'm sorry.
OK.
So you can see it send back its response.
But this time Google servers think that it was a Chrome browser which is sending a request and not some
piece of code or a robot.
OK.
So I'm just going to tell you something about time outs quickly.
Whenever you send a request to servers sometimes you may have seen in you are opening websites in browsers
they don't load and you wait forever and ever and they don't ever load,
because there has been some miss process, they had in some processing
error or maybe your request didn't reach the server or maybe it did and somehow it got dropped or
something and so rather than be able to process.
So you hang there indefinitely and server doesn't send you back a response.
So what do you do normally in a browser is that you just read the URL and press
refresh or press Enter.
So we can do the same thing and in a request module you don't want your code to
hand indefinitely
at some point, if server sends you back a request.
So what you do is you say "page" is equals to "requests.get". I'm going to send a request to Google
but this time I'm going to include a timeout.
Timeout means that after this time, my code won't wait for a response from Google servers and
it would move on.
So this basically ensures that my code is not waiting for the server to send back a response object
indefinitely and it won't hang in there forever for eternity.
So this is how timeout works and preferably you should have them in multiples of three.
OK.
I hope this user agent stuff is clear to you.
And next we'll move to Beautiful Soup which is a parser and I would explain how we can process
content which the server sent us back.
Thank you very much.