Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to discuss
your final project and I'm going to brief you about what
we are supposed to do in your final project.
So I'm sure all of you have used Instagram before and
I mean it must be like let's say you
have uploaded 400 or 500 photos and now you want to
have a copy of each photo on your PC or somewhere.
So what are you going to do?
Don't tell me that you are going to open each photo and then
you're going to download them separately and
then using your phone.
So what do you suggest.
Like what can we do now.
So the task at hand is that
we are going to write a scraper for downloading
images from Instagram for any user
with we are friends with or with open
privacy like you can access the profile
openly.
So how can you go about this.
I'm just going to give you an overview. So you know
the first thing you do is you log into Instagram
and then you will say "dataminer2060".
I mean these are the credentials I'm
using and I'll provide them to you
but you can also use your own account if you want to.
OK, so and I'm going to log in now.
So this is what you are supposed to do. You are going to log in to Instagram.
Then you're going to open your own profile.
OK.
You need to open your own profile.
You're going to see how many photos are here.
So here they are 30 photos.
And if I scroll down, you see I don't get 30 photos
at once so I have to click this "Load
more" button. Ater doing that,
I have to scroll down because all the photos are
present, AJAX is being used here.
So then I scroll down and after I'm done
with that, after all the photos have been loaded
what I do is I download them, I download each photo.
And with that I also want to get the
status for each photo, the caption for each photo.
So this is the caption here.
This is the caption here.
I also want that.
So this is what you are supposed
to do for the final project.
So the user can give any username. OK.
It could be like your own username.
I mean the one who's using it.
So if he wants to get his images and stuff, he can
do that like it can be anyone's
username.
But
the privacy should be open to
that person who's accessing
their Instagram. So let's say if you
want to download my Instagram photos
but we are not friends on Instagram.
My privacy is private.
You can't download them so that you actually
need to be friend, you need to follow them.
OK.
And they have to give you access.
So if that's done then you can download their images.
But we'll stick with downloading our own images right now.
OK.
So this is what
your final project is about and I wish to use the
object oriented programming approach for doing this.
There would be many things we learned along the way.
Many more things, little things that we haven't really
covered so I'll see you soon
In the solution videos. Thank you very much.