Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to
move forward with implementation of the Instagram scraper
we discussed.
So the idea is to log into Instagram, open target's profile
whose photos we want to download and once
we have opened that profile, we
download the photos then of that user.
The only condition here is that you should
have access to that user's profile. If you don't
have that,
you can't download photos for that user.
OK, so I've just written some code here.
I'm just going to walk you through it and
then you can move forward with the first part of
this project which would be logging us into Instagram.
OK, so at the very start, the lines I highlighted
you can see that these are the "import" statement. I'm
importing the webdriver from Selenium and this is
what I'll be using to make a Chrome instance.
OK, and now I have imported sleep here.
I'll explain why I have imported sleep here as we move forward.
So I've created an upper class "app" and this
is the constructor of this "app", this class.
So in the constructor, I have username and password.
So this is supposed to be your username and your password.
I've created an account here whose username is "dataminer2060" and password
is "WebScraper", "target_username" is the argument for the
profile you want to open and download photos from.
So right now in our case, it's "dataminer2060", I haven't changed that.
You can have it for your friend or who have the
photo you want to download and this path
is where I want my photos to be downloaded.
So right now if you see my desktop,
we don't see any folder here named in
"InstaScraper".
You can see it here.
But here I have written
"Users/waqarjoyian/Desktop/instaPhotos".
So when we move forward to the downloading part,
I'll show you that if this path exists in your system,
OK, then the photos will be downloaded in that
path.
If it doesn't exist, we are going to make that
directory and then download that element photos.
OK, so this is our main function here and
we are creating an "app" instance here.
Now we are not passing any argument here to the "app" object.
Why is that?
Because you have declared default arguments for the username,
password, target_username and
path.
So here I have just created class variables and I have assigned the values to them.
Now here it is line number 13.
This is where I create an instance of Chrome.
So for some of you, who even added the Chrome driver
path, to the Python path in their systems,
this statement
won't create a Chrome object.
So what they would have to do is they would have to
manually enter the path for their Chrome driver.
So it could be any and then it would be
something like this for Mac and Linux
users and for Windows it would be ".exe", something like that.
So I've added Chrome driver, the path to the
Chrome driver to my default Python path
so thats why it is not going to cause me problems and
the statement is going to execute gracefully.
OK.
So this is the main URL we want to open, "Instagram.com".
And here I say "driver.get", "self.main_url".
That sounds like pretty simple right.
Let's just run this and see what we get.
OK, so you're running this. You can
see that open Instagram here.
OK, so that's that.
Now what we have to do is we
have to write the "log_in" function.
Let's get started with the "log_in" function.
What do we need here, what do we have to do to login.
So this is what opens up when you open Instagram
so this is where you sign up and then
there's this button that says "Have an account? Log in".
What we want do is we want to click this button
"Log in" which displays.
So I click on inspect here, I check it's like the class here.
Anchor tag I have.
I want to
have a reference to this button.
And so how do I get this button on with Selenium.
So what I do is I say "log_in_button" is equals to "self.driver
.find_element_by_xpath".
And so this button is basically
an anchor tag. Can you see this here?
And it has this class and to
copy the class here I say "a"
The attribute is class.
So now that I have this just to be sure that
I'm not getting some other anchor tag,
I can also include this the "p" tag here and
the copy its class and we are going to say "p".
So this is going to give me access to the login button.
Now what we want to do is we want to click the
login button and we say "log_in_button.click".
So this should do the clicking part and I'm
going to say "input('stop for now')". That line
in going to say our program has stopped executing.
Why is that?
Because I have writeen an input statement
which prompts you to give some input.
I'm just using that temporarily to let you know to walk
you through how we're clicking
the button.
Ok, so I run this Python log in.
Let's see if it clicks the button on not.
So it's opening Instagram.
OK.
Oh, I'm sorry.
We didn't call the "log_in" function.
We did write it but it won't run obviously until we call it.
So I'm running it now.
So you can see it did click the "Log in" button and now
I have these fields here: phone number, username and
password.
So OK, perfect. It says "Stop for now".
So we have been good. Okay, perfect.
Now what we want to do is we have clicked
"Log in" button we want now to input a username here
and password here and then click "Log in".
So let's find the HTML for this username section.
So this is an "input" tag which has its placeholder
value this. Let's copy the placeholder
value.
And I say "user_name_input"
is equals to this.
So what I've done now is I'm going to find this
element here, this "input" tag
here. I'm going to find this "input" tag and how I'm going
to find it is I'm going to use XPath and then
use the placeholder value for this "input" tag.
So I'm going to say "user_name_input", so the function to
type something into an "input" tag is ".send_keys"
and what I want to send is
I want to send the user name here.
So I just did that.
So let's move to the password one.
What do we have in the passwords.
So if you see here, it is another "input" tag and it's place holder is password.
So I'm going to do the same here, "password_input" here
is equals to "self.driver.find_element_by_xpath"
I say "input".
Now let's send it.
So "self.password". OK, so "input"
"stop for now". OK, so now when I run this, I should
have the password here
and the user name here.
We're going to discuss how we login after this part.
Let's make sure that we have reached out
to line the 31.
It is going as expected.
I'm running this now.
Let's see what happens.
OK, logging in.
So the settings tab which you're seeing right now this.
OK.
I'll explain what happened here.
The did the setting tab open.
But before that, before explaining that, you can see
that we have "dataminer2060" here and the
password here.
Right.
So we are going good.
You know the code we wrote for this, for finding
the user name field and the password field
it's working and the password and the user
name, they are in the relevant fields.
OK, so now I would like to know
why the settings tab is opening up.
So the reason behind this is I'm using Chrome version
62 and the Chrome driver version is 2.3 3.
I've just updated it to the latest build and this
is why the setting Stabb is opening up. There's some
bug here with the Chrome driver.
So if your Chrome version right now 62 and
you're experiencing the same issue
you might want to downgrade it to 59
because at 59 it works perfectly for now.
I'll explain in the next video how
we can move forward without
experiencing the settings issue.
You are going to experience it but there's a
turn around for this and alternative to how we
combat this bug here through our code.
But if you don't want to do that, if you don't
want to get into the technicalities of it.
It is not that difficult though.
But still if you don't want to do that, it's OK.
You can just downgrade your version to
Chrome version 60 or 59 and maybe for
many of you, this might not be happening.
So this is just a bug because of the
updated versions of Chrome driver and Chrome.
Maybe like soon they might release
another version which covers this bug
so you might you might not experience it
even.
Ok, let's complete our login. In the next video, I am going to
explain how we are going to combat
the setting Stabb issue we face.
OK, so coming back to log in, you can see that we have
the user name, the user name field and the password
and the password field.
Now what I want to do is I want to click "Log in".
Now there is this Selenium function.
What it does is
it says like "password_input.submit".
What this means is what this is going to do.
I'm sorry.
Let me just write this.
OK.
So "password_input" is basically a child of a form.
Right.
So in HTML you can't have "input" tags without a "form",
you can't send data without a form to the server.
It's like speaking generally, I'm not speaking about
specific instances really using AJAX requests or
some other method to send data at the server.
So.
OK.
Coming back to this.
So you know what happens is an "input" tag is
generally it's a child of a "form" tag, at some
point it's a child or "form" tag.
So what we do is, what we want to do is we want to submit that form.
So if you if you see log in here, it's a button and when we click on it.
It is in the submit this form here which I've highlighted
in the screen. Can you see this in the HTML?
This is going to submit this form.
So there is a quick way to do this in Selenium,
is that if you have access to a
single "input" tag in Selenium what you do
is just say "password" and "input.submit".
So it would also work if I say "user_name.submit".
It's basically the same thing.
It doesn't make difference.
I'm going to run this now.
And let's see if I were able to log in.
OK.
OK, so it opens up Instagram.
Cool.
Log in. Ok, the settings issue. Oh, so we're logged in.
You can see that there's a pop up here and
basically we are logged in, you can see that.
OK.
OK, so in this video I walked you through as to how
you can log into Instagram using Selenium
and Python. In the next video, we are going to
discuss how to combat the Settings tab issue.
It may not be occurring for you.
So if it's not coming for you.
Just keep that video and we are good.
We're going to write a code for this.
Like a single line code.
And next video, we can skip that code.
If this issue is not happening for you,
you can skip that or even if you have
it's not going to cause any problems.
I'm sure of that and I will make sure you of that.
OK, so see in the next video then I hope the "log_in" function is clear to you.
Thank you.