Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to discuss
how to resolve the settings tag issue which we faced in
part one when we were trying to log in.
So the issue was that when we logged in a new tab
open up, a Settings tab, and my main window,
my Instagram window, it went out of focus.
So I'm just going to run this so we have the issue
in front of us and then we can discuss how
to resolve it.
OK.
So it is going to log in now and
setting tab is going to open any time now.
And there it is.
OK so the reason why.
Why does this occur.
This occurs because we are at version 62 of Google
Chrome and the Chrome driver with engine is
2.33.
So these are both the latest versions for the Chrome
drivers which I have right now and the Chrome.
So there's a bug in these builds and that's
why this issue is coming right now.
So many of you this might not be happening
if you don't have the latest versions of Chrome
and Chrome driver.
If you don't want to resolve this with your code, you
can just downgrade your Chrome to version 59 and
everything should be fine.
If you don't want to do that and you want to resolve
this with our code, we are going to discuss how they are going
to do it.
So if this issue is not happening for you, don't worry about it.
It's good.
If it's not happening,
you can just skip this video and move for the next ones.
And for those of you this issue is occurring just hear me out.
You can just implement the solution where this issue occurs
for you because the location might change for you.
For some it might happen after logging in, for some it
might happen at a later stage or even
at an earlier stage.
OK.
So let's move forward and just discuss the solution
we have. So right now, in this Chrome instance we have
two windows, the first window is Instagram
and second window is settings.
OK.
Two windows, windows 0 Instagram, window one settings.
So in Selenium we have this variable known as window handles.
It is a list and it contains references to
each window in that Chrome instance.
So this window handles object
at zero index it has Instagram and in that one index it has settings.
Now what we want to do is we want to close this Settings tab.
And where is this our Selenium window handles list.
It is at index number one.
Now let's write some code and you'll
have a clear idea of what I'm saying here.
"close_setting_tab". I'm going to write this and "try except".
And the reason is that for those this issue is rising,
they have this code in their "log_in" function or
"profile" function, it is not going to hurt
them if they just call this function.
Ok, so I say "self.driver.switch_to_window".
Now which window do I want to switch to, I want
to switch to the settings window. I just want to make sure that
I'm actually there.
OK.
And then I'm going to close this tab.
So I say "self.driver
.window_handles". This "window_handles" is a list.
I tell it "Open window_handle[1]".
So now this line which we just showed,
it ensures that I am at this settings tag.
Then I say "self.driver.close".
This means that I've closed
the settings tab. OK, perfect.
Ok, so now what I want to do is I want to my Instagram window
be the main focus of our code right now.
So now I shift the focus back to Instagram, I say "switch_to_window",
say "self.driver.window_handles[0]"
because Instagram was window number zero or the first window.
And in Python we start counting from zero and
it's the same for most programming languages. OK.
So now let's call this function "close_settings_tab".
And let's see if it actually does that or not.
I'm going to run this now.
So Instagram log in.
So that was really quick.
OK.
The settings tab didn open up and they closed it fairly quickly.
So this bug has been resolved.
And in the next video, we are going to discuss how
we're going to open our target users profile.
I hope you understood how we did this.
Thank you.