Hello everyone! In this video, we're going to
discuss how we're going to open the targets profile.
So by now all of us should be logged in.
And if any of you isn't logged in then you should check
out the previous video in which we did a login for
Instagram.
So as soon as you log in you can see that this dialog box appears.
So now this may be appearing for some of
you and for some of you it may not be appearing.
So for those people who are seeing this dialog
box don't worry, we're just going to
see how are we going to handle it with our code and for those
who are not seeing any dialog boxes,
well we're going to move forward with
opening the target's profile which we will discuss in
a few minutes.
OK.
So the question is how do we close the dialog box.
Very simple answer.
There is this cross mark.
So what we do is we find that HTML for
this cross and we're going to then
click on this button and it is going to close the
dialog box. So we can see that this is a button which
has the class "_dbnr9".
OK, so let's write a function now which is going to close dialog box
and I'm going to write this "try except". The reason is that
if there is no dialog box it
may disappear or it may not be appearing for some people right now.
If they have this code running with their
script it isn't going to come
and crash down things that have come crashing down.
The script is still going to work so that's
why I'm just having the "try except" block here.
OK, so I need to do this "sleep" first and then I say
"close_button" is equals to "self.driver.find_element_by_xpath"
We are looking forward for a button with class.
Ok, and then say "cloase_button.click" and
I can introduce another sleep for one second.
OK, so now I'm going to close this function
and let's see if this works or not.
OK.
I'm running this now.
Insta
and now we are logged in.
And it is.
OK.
So great.
This work, it close the dialog box.
OK, so now that's done what we want to do
is we want to open our profile.
So in our case, the guy whose profile we want
to open is "dataminer2060".
So we're going to type it here.
And now we are going to type it here.
And then as we move forward to "dataminer60" profile,
we can see the URL of Instagram
is "instagram.com/" then
it's the username of the profile you're trying to open.
And then another forward slash.
So now what we are going to do is first
we're going to write that "dataminer2060"
here and then going to click Enter
because it might display multiple
results and there might be some other guy who has his name "dataminer".
So it is possible that it might display
multiple results for some other user names.
So what we do is we find a fail proof
method which is that we add the user
name after "Instagram.com".
I'll just show you how this is going to be done.
But first let's input our desired to user name here.
So let's check out the HTML for this search bar.
So it's basically
"span" and it's basically this "div".
No, it's a simple tag here.
OK.
So you can see that this "input" tag has this class and
I'm going to find "def open_target_profile"
I'm going to find this
and here we go. OK.
So I say "search_bar.send_keys" and
that is going to be "self.target_username".
And let's keep to that for now.
See if we're able to input anything there.
So "self.open_target_profile". OK I'm running this now,
let's see if we're able to input target's
username in that search bar.
OK, so we are logged in.
It should close the dialog box now.
And yes, there we go.
You can see that it has successfully inserted
the target profile's username into the search
field.
So this is working.
What do we want to do next
is if I write "dataminer2060" here, and I open it
you can see that the URL of Instagram
has changed. It is now "instagram.com/dataminer2060".
OK.
So how am I going to open the target's profile.
What I to do is to say "target_profile_url"
is equals to "self.main_url".
Now you can see that the "main_url"
is "https://www.instagram.com".
OK.
And what we're going to do is we are going to
insert a forward slash here and then "self.target_username"
then
another forward slash.
Now I'm going to say "self.driver.get",
"target_profile_url" and let's introduce the sleep
for two seconds.
OK.
And I'm going to run this now and this
should open our target usernames profile.
So it's going to close the dialog box.
There you go.
So you saw that what we did was we
added a forward slash to the main URL,
our main URL was this, the portion I've highlighted.
I added a forward slash and then there's this target
profile username and then the forward slash and
it opens up our target username's profile which in this case is ours.
In the next video, we are going to discuss
how we're going to download the photos from
a target's profile here.
See you in the next video.
I hope this video makes sense.
Thank you.