Hello everyone.
So in the previous video, we discussed how to open
our target profile. In this video, we are going to discuss how
we're going to actually download images from
my target's profile and what is the logic we are going to use
behind it.
So the first thing is that I'm opening
this National Geographic Channel here, National
Geographic's profile and I have it open and you can
see that it says 15,482 posts.
OK, so now the thing is that I clicked
on refresh and the page almost instantly
reloaded.
It didn't take a lot of time.
So what do you think.
If I was actually loading 15000 photos at once on
this web page it wouldn't be taking you like a second
to load.
It would take maybe a minute or two minutes
depending on the network speed and it would also be really
very burdensome for National Geographic to
actually make this happen that each time you open
a profile you load all the images that person has.
Now as I've opened National Geographic obviously I don't
want to see 15000 images at once. It does one make sense.
So what they do is they load a few images and
if you want to see more images from National
Geographic. What do you do is you scroll down.
You can see as I scroll down more images load, you can
see there's a circle here and it loads more images.
So as it keeps scrolling down, it keeps loading photos.
OK.
Now the thing here is that I don't know
how many times I have to scroll down before
actually all the photos are loaded.
That is very essential for us to know because
obviously we want to you know download all the
images for the given profile and we can't do
that unless we know how many times we have to scroll down.
If I say I have that for a thousand it is very
much possible that maybe not all the images are loaded
if the images are a lot and it is also possible that
a guy only had 50 images and for no reason I'm
just scrolling down thousand times. It just wouldn't make sense.
So how do we figure out the right number through which
we're able to say "OK, this many
times we have to scroll down."
Now this was what I wanted to discuss with you in
this video but before I get into that I just
would like
you to have an overview as to how
we are going to download the images.
So the idea is that once we have all the
images loaded in this web page, in this document,
what I'm going to do is I need to get all the images
tags out of this page.
And after that, you can see if I click on inspect here...
Just give me a sec please.
OK, so as soon as we click inspected here,
you can see that this is a "div" and...
Just stay with me.
So
as it moves down you can see
that this "div" has this "image".
So this "image" you can see that it has
a source attribute here.
OK, I have to cancel this.
OK, so if I want the source tag what I do is. Sorry, this source attribute
actually contains the link for this image.
So if I have this, if I have the source and I open it
and then the new tab. If I open this here,
you see that I have this image here.
Right.
So the idea is to get all the source tags like
the source attributes for all the image tags.
And then once I have them, we can just download them.
We can get the images then. That's the idea of
this whole exercise.
But before we get into that we need to understand the scrolling issue.
Now I've told you why it's necessary to scroll
down and how we're going to actually
scrape the images once we've scrolled down to the very end of the page.
The first thing we need to know is
we need to know the number of posts.
OK.
And I'm going to open "datamining" right now.
Because 15000 is a lot of posts.
I wouldn't be able to open that many posts right now.
So we have "dataminer" open now.
Now, you can see "dataminer" has 30 posts in total.
OK.
So as soon as I open "dataminer", I'm going to refresh it.
So you can see this in real time.
OK, so you can see that as soon as I open up
all of the posts have been loaded into the page.
So how many are they.
Let's count them.
One, two, three, four.
So there are four rows and each of them contains three images
so in total 12 images had been loaded
as soon as the profile page was displayed and
as I scroll down more images are
loaded.
OK.
One, two.
So right now two rows loaded and I'm
to refresh it right now and then we are going to see how many
rows are loaded with each time I scroll down.
OK.
Now we know that three row are already there
when you open someone's profile. One, two, three, four.
Sorry, four rows and one, two,three,four and
four rows are there. OK.
When I scroll down, each time I scroll down, four
rows they need to be fetched
from the server and so if I have 30 posts,
how many times I have to scroll down.
That will mean that I would I have to scroll down know 30 - 12.
That is 18.
OK.
Because the reason I'm subtracting 12 at first,
here is that twelve have already been
loaded into the page so I don't really need to add
that 12 to number of times I have to scroll
down so I subtract that and I have 18 posts.
So each time I scroll down 12 posts are loaded.
OK.
So how many times do I have to scroll down.
That is 18 divided by 12.
And that would be two.
Like once I go down and then only six photos
would be left and then the time
I scroll down, the other six photos are there then too.
Let's see how many times I have to
scroll down and if the little math
we did
is it OK or not.
Oh, I'm sorry.
So Instagram,
dataminer, Ok.
So this was once one,
two and three.
So the number we calculated was two and it was
two because later we have 18 posts.
And if we add the first 12 then it becomes three.
So my calculation was correct essentially.
OK, so before we actually do the scrolling part
and see it in action we need to know the number
of posts for any given profile.
Now if an open National Geographic again
you can see that this contains 15,483
posts.
OK.
We're going to get this figure now.
And you can see that this figure is in this "span" and its class
is this which I'm just copying here.
OK, so here's some code for scrolling down.
OK.
"no_of_posts" is equals to self.driver.find_element_by_xpath".
It's the same "span" and it has the same class.
And I say "no_of_posts" is equals to "no_of_posts.text".
And then I'm saying print "no_of_posts". Now I'm
going to run this and we're going to see if this works
or not.
OK.
This should display us the number of post for our dataminer
profile. I'm just going to have an "input" tag here
to stop the execution of the program.
"stop for now" and let me call
this function now, "scroll_down".
OK, I'm running this and let's see if we're able to
extract the number 30 from dataminer's profile because
that's the number of posts dataminer has.
It's opening up.
OK.
So "scroll_down". Everything seems in order.
That's logging in.
It is gong to close the dialog box.
It didn't close the dialog
box.
OK, let's see where we're getting this error.
Because they apparently got an error here.
OK, it was "open_target_profile".
Before we get to that, it should have...
OK, I'm just going to increase the sleep here.
Maybe it wasn't able to find this button,
this dialog button in this dialog box
we have "Experience of best version of Instagram."
And the reason might be because it just
hadn't loaded into the page while it checked.
That's it.
Let's run this again with a greater delay and see if
this works or not. Let me check my internet connection.
It's good. Ok so Instagram
and it's going to log us in.
Good.
It closes the settings tab and now it's opening the news feed.
And now I have.
OK.
So great.
It worked now.
I increase the delay.
There you can see that you're at dataminer's
profile and we should have a number
30 here.
Great.
So we have the number 30. Ok, so the thing here is
that we should know down is that we have the number of
posts 30 here but if you see National Geographic It contains
15,483 posts.
And you see a comma here after five.
So how do we handle this.
I mean I can convert this number to an
integer without creating an exception.
So the way I'm going to handle this is and we say
"no_of_posts.replace" and if there is any comma
I'm going to
ask Python to replace that with nothing.
So if there is a number
15,483 this is going to convert it
into 15483 it is just going
to remove the comma.
So essentially I'm going to have an integer.
Now OK.
So now I have the number of posts and
it's working. Ok so in the next video,
we are going to discuss the scrolling part
as to how we are going to scroll down
the profile with code and I hope
this is clear to you as to why we have
this number here and the ideology behind
all of this, as to how we're scraping this
and the reason we have to scroll
down to find out all image links.
I hope this makes sense.
Thank you.
I'll see you, in the next video.