Hello everyone.
In the last video, we discussed how we are going to extract
the number of posts from my target's profile. In this
video, we are going to discuss how we are going to make
the relation between the scrolling and the number
of posts.
And how we are going to implement the scroll down procedure.
OK, so let's open our dataminer profile.
So here we have 30 posts as discussed before in the previous video.
Twelve posts had already loaded as soon as we
open this page and as I move down,
more photos start to load. They load in chunks
and each chunk contains 12 photos.
OK, so right now all of them are here.
I'm just going to run this again and
let's see how many we have right now.
So row number one, row number two,
row number three, row number four.
So four rows loaded right and then
these two load again as I scroll down.
So essentially what's happening here is that as
I scroll down 12 photos are being loaded.
And initially there are 12 photos on the
page as soon as you open the target's profile.
OK.
So if we have two reports and we want to make
sure that all of these images are on a target's
profile, what can we do here.
How do we ensure that.
So how we can show that is I can divide 30 by 12.
OK.
And I'm going to round to the next integer.
If I divide 30 by 12, 30 divided by 12 that
means 2.5. I'm going to round it off to three.
OK, so if I scroll three times that is
going to ensure that all the images have been loaded.
Right.
So here I was with Number of posts and they were like 12 here.
So I say "slf.no_of_posts" is equals to "int(no_of_posts)".
OK.
So the first condition is that if the
number of posts is let's say five or three.
So there's no need to scroll down.
Right.
So I say if "self.no_of_posts" is bigger than 12, only then scroll down.
Now how many times do we have scroll down. Then I say
"number_of_scrolls" is equals to "self.no_os_posts"
divided by 12
and I need to add three here.
It's just for good measure.
Just to ensure that there's no discrepancy.
And we are not missing out anything. So
even if I don't add three we are good.
So OK.
Let's move forward.
OK, so now how many times I have to scroll down.
So what I do is I say "for value in range". I'm
just having a loop here for "value" and "range(no_of_scrolls)" and
I say "self.driver.execute_script".
Now what this command does is this
command executes some JS code, some
Javascript code.
So we're going to scroll down
Selenium browser via javascript.
OK.
So let's write that. "window.scrollTo"
and I say "0", "document.body.scrollHeight".
Perfect.
So what does this script should do
is this script
should scroll down our target's profile to make sure that
all the images have been loaded.
I'm just going to print the value here
so we know how many times this does it.
OK.
Let's run this now and see if this works or not.
And if you're missing something or not. Ok I'm just going
to introduce a "sleep" for one second because it's
you know just to make sure that all the
data is there and not just scrolling down
and
nothing is there and nothing loaded.
The delay value is going to vary with
the connection you have, with the Internet
connection you have. So it's really
good maybe one need delays at all.
OK.
And now we're opening up Instagram.
It has log us in. Now our news feeds should come up.
And there it is. We are going to close the dialog box
soon as soon as everything in the news feed has loaded.
That's being done now.
Now we're opening target profile.
It's open.
We should start scrolling down now.
OK.
So it's crawling.
Can you see this?
And we have ensured that we were able to scroll
down our user, our target user's profile.
So now you can see that all the images are loaded.
You know there is no image has been skipped.
And if I take out HTML for this page now, I am going
to find image tags there where the source attribute
set for all of these images which we're going to get.
And then when we are going to use that to download these
images in our system. I hope this video made sense to you.
And if you have any questions please leave
them there and I'll try to get that get answers
for them as soon as I can.
I hope this was clear to you and in the next
video we're going to move forward with the
downloading part.
Thank you very much.