Hello everyone. In this video, we are going to discuss
how we're going to add exception handling to our code.
The first thing is why do we need to add exception
handling to our code. Now things change with time.
I have Instagram here.
What they're going to do is maybe moving forward,
they're going to change the layout of their
log in page.
That is very much possible.
So when they do that the script is going to crash down
and you'll have no clue what happened and of course
you debug.
So what do you do
is you make sure that the application doesn't crash
and you have "try catch" blocks to catch
every exception that is being raised by
some particular line of code which went wrong.
So you should add exception handling in all
your code so that your code exits gracefully. OK.
Let's start with the first function we have which
is the "og_in" function. The first thing which
can go wrong here is that we
are unable to find the log in button.
So when that happens what we can do is we
can have this in a "try catch" block. I say "try",
"except Exception",
let's write print here.
"Unable to find login button".
Ok, so before I move forward with this, I'm declaring
a variable here, "self.error" is equals to
"False" which indicates there driver now there is no error in our code.
Whenever an exception is raised we can set
this variable to "True" which means that some error
has occurred and we can't move forward.
OK.
So now this XPath I have, this works.
Let's just change. Let's say instead of "p", I make it "a".
OK.
And I comment this line.
Let's run this
and see if our code exit gracefully.
But right now,
OK,
Before I actually run this, let's just
have a dride through this code.
But what's going to happen is it's going to come to the constructor.
It's going to set the values.
So "self.error" is equals to "False".
And then moving forward, it gets Instagram URL then
it goes to "log_in" function and once we're
there, this line raises an exception which says
that it is unable to find this element, this "a" tag we know
doesn't exist because it's a "p" tag and not an "a" tag.
So it comes here it says "self.error" is equals to "True".
It says print "Unable to find the login button".
So then it moves back and it says "close_dialog_box".
When it's going to come down here you see that
we already have this in a "try catch" block.
And the reason for that was that for some of you,
you might not be experiencing the dialog
box issue at all.
So, OK, we are going to pass the dialog box.
We are not going to face the issues there.
So when OK when we get to this function here, "open_target_profile",
what's going to happen next is that there
is that there is no "try catch" block here.
It is not going to find this element.
This "find_element_by_xpath" even though exist, it only
exists if you are log been, we weren't logged in
because we weren't able to find the log in button in the first place.
So what do I do.
Like what can we do to make sure that this isn't called.
This is the reason that we declared this variable
here, "self.error" is equals to "False".
So I say if "self.error" is "False", only then you do this stuff. OK.
And same goes for scrolling down.
So "self.error" is "False"
then you do this.
Now you might be wondering why
haven't I copy pasted this here,
"self.open_target_profile",
and why do I have a separate condition for this.
The reason behind that is say some issues raise
in "open_target_profile", maybe I am unable to find the search
bar.
OK.
That's an error
now. Obviously I'm in my news feed if
I haven't opened my target's profile.
So I'm right now on my news feed.
So what happens then is that the scrolling function
is going to be called and it is going to be called on
the news feed, this is not going to find the number of
posts because there aren't number of sports in news
feed. I mean you can just scroll endlessly on your news feed.
So that is going to raise an exception
and your code is going to crash down.
So that's why a separate "if" condition for this here.
Ok, let's run this and see what happens.
OK,
so here we go.
It's opening Instagram.
It says "Unable to find login button".
So the "stop for now", it's an input tag
which I have here just to stop the code execution.
I press Enter and it exits gracefully.
OK, so let's complete our exception handling. So now
I just gave you an introduction as to how
this process is going to work.
Now let's assume that there was no
error at line number 69, the line we are
trying to find the log in button which I've just highlighted.
What I'm unable to find is a user name input,
this element which I'm trying to find.
What happens then.
Obviously it's not "log_in_button" so
I wouldn't know. If it is unable to find that, it
is going to raise this exception "unable to find login button". OK.
So what we do is we have this in another
"try catch" block.
OK.
And the reason I have this like the
password field and they user name field in a single "try
catch" block is because I'm printing "Some exception
occurred"...
"Some exception occurred while trying
to find user name or password field".
If you want to be more precise, you can have "try catch"
blocks separatedly for each of them so it is not going
to change anything.
And I say "self.error" is equals to "True". So that is
exception handling for the "log_in" function. Moving
forward we have "close_dialog_box".
We have "try catch block".
So there is no need for that.
Let's go to "open_target_profile".
OK.
So what can raise an error here.
This is what can raise an error like
it is unable to find this element, the search bar.
So let's have this in a "try catch" block.
The whole of it.
I say "except Exception" and I say
"self.error" is equals to "True".
And print "Could not find search bar".
Ok, so moving next.
What do we have scrolling down.
Ok, so when it come to this function here, you can
see that this is the thing we're trying to
find first find element by XPath.
This is the element which gives us the
number of posts for a particular profile.
So that is one which is going to raise the first exception.
OK.
So let's have this whole in a single "try catch"
block.
I say "except Exception" and I say print "Could not find
numbers of posts while trying to scroll down". And I say "self.error"
is equals to "True". OK, so the next thing which can
go wrong is that by just trying to scroll down something
goes wrong.
Right.
So now it's basically up to you if you want to have
this in a single loop like in a single "try catch"
block the whole loop.
Or you can have the "try catch" block in the loop.
Ok, so I say "self.error"
is equals to "True".
print "Some occurred while trying to scroll down".
OK, so now if you want to see what exceptional occurred
what we can do is you can say "except Exception as e"
and you can print it, print "e".
This is also going to the print exception.
And it is not going to force the code to close down.
So you'll see the stack trace like what caused the error
and your code is going to exit gracefully this
way. OK, so now we have done this
for scroll down and this is it.
OK.
So for now, for this video what we did was we introduced
exception handling to each of the functions
we have written for this class.
And the reason behind that was to make sure that our
code exits gracefully if there is any change in
the structure of Instagram's website and I
hope this made sense. In the next video,
we're going to continue to how we are going to download
the images from my target's profile as you scroll down.
Thank you very much.
I hope this makes sense. Thank you.