Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to
discuss where we are going to download our photos.
Now we have this parameter coming "path". This argument.
So it tells us the location of where are going to
download our photos here.
OK, so to ensure I'm downloading in the right
directory I have to ensure this path exists.
It is a check which I have to ensure, right.
So if I open my desktop, can you see any folder name "instaPhotos"?
It is not there but here in the "path"
it states that "Desktop/instaPhotos".
But I don't have any folder "instaPhotos" in my desktop.
So what do we do now.
The first thing which needs to be done is to
ensure that does this path exist
which the user entered.
So I am going to import "os" here, "os" is a module.
It's a built in module. You do not have to download it.
We have "pep".
So it's it comes with Python.
OK.
So what we are going to do is we're going
to use "os" to see if this path exists.
This path which we have and if it doesn't exist
we're going to make sure that it exists now. And how we
are going to make sure that, we are going to create it.
OK, so what we are going to do is I'm going to open to
Selenium and go to this that whole process. I'm just
going to say "input" this is just to stop
the execution of the program. "stop for now".
And before that I say print
so the function that you're going to use is "os.path.exists"
and here I give it "path".
So this going to return me a boolean value, true or false.
If the file exists it is going to return me
"True" if it doesn't it is going to tell me false.
I'm going to run this.
And let's see what we get.
So it says "False", can you see the that? That means
that this path doesn't exist and that is very true.
We don't have any folder "instaPhotos" in my desktop.
So how do we take care of this?
So how we do that is is it says "os.mkdir".
And then you give it "path".
I'm going to run this now this like here
with this like we we're supposed to run this.
It is just to show you walk
you through the function here.
So make directory, "mkdir", what this function
does is it is going to create this directory
here, this "instaPhotos" directory here.
If it doesn't exist already on the desktop and
how we're going to do this is we are going to sat "if not
os.path.exists"
then "os.mkdir(path)".
Now what this line is going to do is this line is going
to ensure that this directory does exist in our
system and if it doesn't exist we are going to create it.
OK.
And I'm going to copy this and I'm going to say if "self.error" is "False".
Here you go.
Now let's run this and see if we get the directory.
OK.
With this specified path, I hope this is making sense to you.
I'm going to run this now.
There we go.
The reason I have this after all this is that say
that I got an error while logging in then it's
no use making a directory which is not going to be used.
Right.
We only make it until it's absolutely necessary to do that.
OK.
So now we're logged into Instagram
opening target's profile.
Scrolling down, scrolling down
and we should have our directory any time now
and here it is, "instaPhotos". Can you see this?
"instaPhotos".
So our code created this directory because it found that
it doesn't exist already in our system. OK.
Great. So in the next video, we're going
to discuss the downloading part.
Now as we have the directory the location of where we
are going to store our photos and we have ensured
that location exists on our system.
OK, I'll see you in the next video.
Thank you.