Hello everyone! In this video, we are going
to finally move on to downloading the images.
We have everything necessary in place to do that.
We have the folders, we have scroll down.
We have ensured that all the images
are loaded on our page. So moving on
to the final part.
Now what do we do here?
So if you see that I have these image tags and
they contain the image here, pretty obvious.
So one way can be you we do is we we get
all the images on this page which are going
to be...
So we have three images in a single row and we have one,
two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
We have 10 rows and this is the 11th image the display picture.
So OK.
Ten three, thirty.
And this makes it 31 right.
OK, moving forward I'm going to
write a function "downloading"...
"downloading_images".
So what do we do here is I say
that I'm going to make a soup now.
Let me first have
the necessary library imports.
I say "soup" is equals to "BeautifulSoup"
and "self.driver.page_source" and then I provide a parser.
Ok, so now we want to find all the images
so I say "soup.find_all".
And I got the image tag.
I can say print
"Length of all images" and I say "len(all_images)"
"for img and all_images"
print "image['src']".
So we have the address of this image in the source
attribute. I'm just going to show that to you.
You see this here like we have this source
attribute and it contains the image itself.
If I copy this, just to show you how
this works, it get the image. Right.
OK, so what what we basically need is we
basically need the source attribute of the image.
So once I have all the image tags, I extract
the image source attribute. I'm going to run this now.
And we'll see how this goes.
OK, I'm sorry I didn't call that.
I didn't call the downloading function.
So we have to do that obviously, "downloading_images".
OK, so now it's opening Instagram.
It's going to log us in now.
So now we have the dialog box, it closed
dialog box, opening our target profile.
It's going to move to scrolling now.
So now that we have scrolled down, let's have our
PyCharm here and see how this goes with the images.
OK.
So there you go.
We have all the image links and the
length of all images is thirty one.
Just as we calculated, right. Ten rows that
make 30 and 30 first images a display picture here.
If I copy any of this like if I copy this
and just try this out here.
You see I'm getting a picture which I
have on my target's profile, right.
It's this picture, you can see this. So basically
we have the image attributes now, the image sources like
we have the image tags and the necessary attributes
that come with the source and the caption.
We are going to discuss more about captions
in the next coming videos.
And next video, we are going to discuss how we going
to actually download this image onto our system
now like we have access to the image, we have necessary links.
Now what we want to do is we want to download this image on our system.
We are going to discuss that in the next video.
I hope this video made sense and if anything
isn't clear, you can always leave questions. Thank you!