Hello everyone! In the previous video, we discussed how
we are going to get the links for all of the images
by accessing the source attribute of that image.
In this video, we are going to discuss
how we are going to download that image into our system.
OK, so moving forward this
is the code we have right now.
I am going to introduce an index counter
and I'm going to put this enumerate.
So what
enumerate basically does is say that I have a
list of three items, let's say "a", "b", "c".
So these are the elements in my list.
So what enumerate basically does is it is going to give
me index for each item so "a" is in index zero
"b" is on one and "c" is on two.
So image would then contain the first iteration of
the loop and would contain "a" and index would contain
0.
And similarly next iteration image will
contain "b" and index would contain one.
Now this ABC explanation is just
to make explain how enumerate works.
OK.
This explanation has nothing to
do with the fact about downloading
images.
Don't mix that stuff up.
It's just explaining how enumerate is working and
what this index is. OK, so that being clear what we
want to do now is first we want to know
what what file I am going to have for our
image here, we need to decide that
obviously before we download it.
So a suggestion is that what we can do is "image_",
"str(index)" because this index is going to be unique and
we can just append this image before that,
not append it actually we actually append the index
count, this string here, this image one,
and then we have our file.
Now that we have a file name what we want to do next is
we want to download this now. Before we finally
download this,
we have to know where we are actually storing this image.
Right.
So the main directory is this
which I just highlighted, this path.
"/Users/waqarjoyian/Desktop/instaPhotos".
But what is going to the "image_path" in total.
So that is going to be something
like I am going to use...
OK, before I use that function let me just explain
to you what the image path is going to be like. It
is going to be something like this
and let's say "image_1" and this is
going to be like the image path we have.
Now how do I actually make this path.
Obviously, one way is that I say "image_path" is
equal to "self.path" and then I add
file name to it and before adding filename
I should also add the forward slash here.
So this is the "image_path",
this is one way to do it.
Excuse me.
OK.
So a better way to get this done is to use
the "os" module and the method is
"os.path.join".
So that is it, "image_path" is equals to "os.path.join".
And here we give the first part and here
we give "filename" in and this creates us the image path.
OK.
So the method is "os.path.join" and it is
going to do what we just did here, like this
line here. It is going to do that for us but
it is going to handle the forward slash.
Like here we were inserting that ourselves.
Right.
And we also want this to be platform independent
like for Windows this might be different,
for some other operating system it might be different.
So just to ensure cross compatibility.
You should use
"os.path.join".
It's better that way.
OK, so now that we have the image path.
Let's finally move to downloading that image.
Let's create another variable "link"
and save the link of the image there.
OK, so now what we are going to do is we are going to
use that "request" module to get this image. I'm going to import
"request" here.
So what I do is I say "response" is equals to
"request.get(link)" and then I say "stream" is equals to
"True". OK.
Now the next thing is that I have this image and I have this image
in this response object here. What I want to do
now is I want to save that image to my hard disk.
What do I do now.
I have the binary contents of that image and I want
to shift those binary contents to my hard disk.
What we are going to do is going to use
another module here it is known as shutil.
OK, so you may pronounce it differently but it's ok.
I mean you don't actually have to pronounce it
in your code you just have to write it down.
So, OK the method for that is... What you're going to use is...
First let me open the file.
I say "image.path" and lets's open it in binary
mode, "as file", and let's say "file.write", "response". Oh, I'm
sorry.
So this is the method which we
are going to use, "copyfileobj".
And the first thing is from resource and the
next thing is the destination source. Right.
We're going to write it down.
Right.
So the first parameter is going to be "response.raw".
This is going to give the binary contents
of the image and where we actually want
to get this content are at "file". Now this
should write that image to our location
here which is this "instaPhotos".
OK.
I need to have this in a "try catch" block.
So if some error comes, we'll know what happened.
And our program would just crash like that.
You would actually have a good reason for it.
Like as to why did that and where did that.
So I can say "as e", I'm going to print this and then
I'm going to print "Could not download image number "
and here I can give the index and I could also
print the link for that, "Image link" so that will "link"
here.
OK, so now let's run this and see what we get.
And actually before doing that let
me just print this too, "Downloading
image".
And here we go.
OK.
Now let's run this and see if this works or not.
And we are on the same page here, "shutil.copyfileobj".
What it does is the first parameter
expects the from destination and the second is...
Not the destination, the source.
Ok, the next is destination. OK.
So now let's run this and see what happens.
So moving forward.
Instagram, it is opening Instagram.
We have our target's profile open,
scrolling this down.
You can actually get rid of this here, these numbers
which we are printing while scrolling down.
That's not really necessary. Ok, to it says
the length of images is just 31.
It is downloading them right now, you can see that
here. Let me open the folder and see are we getting anything.
And so we are getting the images.
But there's just one problem here that we
didn't said the extension for these images
and that is creating an issue.
Now you can see that they're not
giving me a default format here.
So if I rename an image to say ".jpg".
I say "Add" and I'll be able to access
these images. So we forgot that and we
are just going to fix that.
Now we should add this here.
That would be "jpg". I'm going to stop this and
I'm going to run this again and we should have the images.
Now, I'm to delete everything here.
OK so now you can see that our instaPhotos folder
is clear, you don't have anything here.
OK, so the scraper is running, it has log us in.
Instagram.
Any time now.
Ok.
So we're at the end of our target's profile.
Let's see when we start the downloading process.
OK, so we're actually downloading all the images now. It says
"downloading image zero". Let me open instaPhotos.
So there you go.
Now we have add an extension.
And you can see that I'm getting
all the photos in the right format.
Right.
So you can see that this worked, just to
walk you through the process again.
What we did was we decided the filename for the image.
It had to be unique.
That's why I introduced the index
attribute here. Not an attribute,
it's like the count here.
And we added the file format.
What do we want it to be, we added "jpg" here.
Then we decided the image path, we had the
link then we use request to get the
contents from that link and then after we had the binary
content we used "shutil" and this method to
write those contents to the file destination
we have decided, the image path, that would be here.
OK.
So we have downloaded image 30 here and we're almost done.
We're done.
So we had 31 images in total.
And the reason it is say 30 here is because we started
with zero and there you go. You see that we have all
the images here including the display picture.
OK, so I hope the downloading part was clear to you.
And if there is anything that you
might not understand, you can always
ask us questions and definitely get back to you.
OK.
So good.
I think this is clear to you. In the next video,
we are going to discuss how to download the captions.
OK.
Perfect.
Thank you!