Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to discuss
how we are going to download the captions for all the images
we have.
So in the previous video, we were able to
download all the photos which are here in the folder
in the desktop. In this video, we are
going to move forward with captions.
So now before we actually download the
captions we need to know where they are.
Right.
So if I open a photo I can see that I have
this caption here, "View" and these smileys, right. OK.
So what do we do now is we need to know
where is this, like where is the location of this caption here.
Right.
So if I just close this.
I use...
I'm at this image right now and you can see that
the "alt" attribute contains the caption for
this image.
Let me move forward to another image.
OK, let's say that I'm here,
at this image, and it contains a caption "View".
And if I open this you can see that this is exactly
what we have here.
Right.
So the image tag contains the source for the
image like we're like the link for that image as to
where that image is on Internet.
And it also contains a caption for that image.
Perfect.
OK.
So now that we already have these image tags
what we're going to do is we are going to use
them to get the captions.
And we are going to write those captions in the directory
where we have our photos. So we are going to make another
folder here and that directory here named captions.
And we're going to have every caption there
for each of the images we have downloaded. Ok.
So let's start with that now.
So what do we do here is I'm going to make a function.
"def download_captions", now what I would expect to
have is images like the list of images we have,
we already have that, we get that here, right.
All images.
So once we have that, what we are going to do is we
need to make sure that we have the location as to where we're
going to store these captions.
So the location is supposed to be a folder in this
directory, instaPhotos, we need to make a folder
here.
Right.
So how do we do that.
First we decide the caption path like "captions".
I'm sorry.
"captions_folder_path" is equals
to... Let's use "os.path.join".
And what we would be using is "self.path".
And then I can write captions.
So "os.path.exists", "caption_folder_path".
If it doesn't exist then make sure it does now.
Right.
We create the directory.
Now we have the directory here.
What we want to do next is we want to get the
captions. So let's have a loop here, "for image in
images" and I say print
"image['alt']" and let's call this,
"self.downloading_captions" and I say then "all_images".
I'm going to run this now and we are just going to see that.
Are we getting all the captions for all the photos?
Or not, right.
So it's going to log us in now.
So we got an exception, "Could not find search bar".
And the reason behind that is the page hadn't loaded.
So I'm just going to increase the sleep
timings for that. Just give me a second.
Ok, so
"close_dialog_box", go to implementation. Ok, I'm
going to increase that to say 10 seconds for now.
So we are opening Instagram.
Log in, logging in.
We closed the dialog box.
We have our target profile open, it
is going to scroll down now.
So basically we are printing the caption here
which is supposed to be in the "alt" attribute
for all the images.
So let's see what we get.
We have scrolled down.
OK, so you see that we're getting a key error "alt". Why is that?
So the reason behind that is some images don't
have captions and images which don't have captions
are going to give us this exception
that they don't contain this attribute.
How do we take care of it?
What we do is we have this in a "try catch" block.
You say "try except", it's a key error and we
say print "No caption for this image". Right.
But the idea is that we're able to
get the captions for all the images right.
OK.
So I'm going to run this again.
Let me close this extra instance
I have of Chrome.
I'm going to run this again.
And we have to make sure that we are able to get
the captions for all the images and the images
which don't have their captions we are going
to get this line for them, that "No caption
for this image" because we have a "try catch" block
which is handling the key error part here.
Right.
Because a key is raised when a specific key is not found in a dictionary.
That's why it's named as a key error
because that key doesn't exist.
OK.
So we have scrolled down and anytime
now we should be getting captions.
OK, so you can see that we've got the captions for all
of the images and the images which didn't have captions were
like "No caption for this image", "No captions for this image".
And it was downloading the images again.
So I'm just going to stop it because we already
done with that part and we know it works. Ok,
So now that we have the captions what we want to do is... Oh, yes.
The thing was this folder here this didn't exist
before and you could see that it exists right now.
And why is that?
Because these two lines they ensure that happens.
This line defines the path as we discussed before
and these lines they ensure that if that path
doesn't exist it makes sure that it exists now
by creating the necessary folders in that path.
I hope this is clear to you.
Now what we want to discuss is how we are
going to write captions to this path.
So for right now the idea is to have a separate
".txt" files for each caption like for each photo
and its relevant caption in that ".txt" file.
We can have the captions for that photo
in that ".txt" file. Let's if we have
31 images, we're going to have 31
".txt" files.
And they're going to contain the link
and the caption for that image. OK.
So we say "caption" is equals to "image['alt']" and
the file path is supposed to be "os.path.join",
"caption_path_folder" and actually before we
decide the file path we need to know the file name.
So let's keep it the same as we did in the images like caption.
And I'm going to use index here and I'm going to "enumerate" it.
So there you go.
I'm going to have this in a "try catch" block
and I'm just going to explain to you why I did that.
OK, so index plus ".txt".
We shouldn't forget the file extension. OK.
And there you go.
"file_name". Now I would like to elaborate as to
why I have this caption in a separate "try catch"
block and why not have all of this in a "try catch" block.
So if I don't have a "try catch" block here like
as I have right now and I was using my previous "try catch"
block what was going to happen was that this
first line was going to raise an exception
any of this code would have been executed. Because
we still want to create a file for those images
which don't have a caption and you can just write
that "No caption exists for this image".
OK. OK, so now you have a file
path. Right, now the next step is to make a file
with the path and just write
down the stuff necessary.
That would be like the caption and the link.
We can also get the link, "image['src']". OK.
Now let's open this, open thi file
path
and "as file" I say "file.write".
So what we want to write is
the link, obviously link, and I say "str(link)" then I add
a next line and then I can say "caption"
and there we go.
OK, so now let's run this and
see if we're able to extract captions.
I'm sorry, we were able to extract captions before.
Let's see if we are able to write this captions to a ".txt" file. OK,
so I'm running this now.
It's opening Instagram.
We have the news feed open,
closing dialog box, opening target's profile,
scrolling down,
we have scrolled down now and any time now we
should be getting captions. We should have included
a print statement here.
So we knew that yes, we are getting them but I guess
I'm just going to open the captions folder and see
if anything happens.
There you go.
Captions here ".txt".
Just saw that we got that.
OK.
So an error has been raised, "TypeError: a
bytes-like object is required not 'str'".
The reason behind that is that if you open the file
in binary mode and you would be wondering why I would
do that.
The reason behind that is that some of these
have smileys
and these smileys can't be encoded
in the regular format we use.
We have to encode them in Unicode.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to save
all of this in binary format to a file.
And it's going to take care of that.
It's like whenever we view it, it might differ from
system to system or there might be some
cross dependency issues, not cross dependency, sorry,
cross compatibility issues but it would work for most
of you.
And in moving forward, we are going to discuss how we
to do this in Exel meaning the ".csv" file or an Excel file.
And that's a different thing
we are going to face this issue there.
OK, so how do we take care of this.
So what I do is all of this
has a string and then I encode it and it
is going to convert this to a byte-like object.
I'm going to run this again
and
let's see if we're able to extract all the captions
now.
Logged in, opened target profile.
So we should be getting captions any time now.
There you go.
You have the captions.
If I open any of this, you can see content "tracking"
and it says the link for this photo and if I open
this you can see "View" and it has these
smileys so it's downloading the images again.
I'm just going to stop this because we've
already done that part and it works.
So you can see that we're able to download all the
captions for all of the relevant images and we also
mapped them, we have made sure that "image_1" is
"caption_1" and also just before to show what you've
done.
You also included the image URL.
So if I open this I would know that this image contained this
caption and for any image which doesn't
have it, which doesn't have a caption
it is going to show us that it doesn't have a caption.
I am not sure which image is that but there are
a few images which don't have any captions.
And for that we have the string
which says "No caption exists for this
image" and would have that there.
I hope this video, made sense to you. In the next
video, we're just going to discuss how we are going
to make an Excel work book, an Excel sheet
for the captions and we can map them there.
It's more neat than opening 31 different files for the captions.
Thank you!