Hello everyone!
In the last video, we discussed how
we are going to download the captions.
And in this video, we're going to move to the final part
of this project which is writing captions to
an Excel file.
Now the idea behind that is that previously when
you were writing captions we had a separate file for
each image because it would just be a messy
if we had all of it in a single ".txt" file.
It wouldn't be really helpful.
So now what we want to do is we want to have this
in an Excel file because doing
analysis on data for a normal human being, for
a normal person, they really prefer
Excel because of the formulas and the tools
you have to manipulate the data in an Excel file.
You can't really do that with a ".txt" file.
To say you want to find patterns or something else.
It is better that you realize that in an Excel
file, not in the ".txt" file. So speaking of the industry standard,
the Excel file is current industry standard for
most people who are not really into tech but they
want to perform business analytics and stuff like that.
So what they do is they use Excel to do that,
manipulate data with Excel and so now I'm going
to introduce you to the module
"xlswriter".
I'm just going to import it, "from xlswriter
import Workbook". The workbook is basically the Excel
file which is going to be made.
I'm just going to walk you through how this is going to work.
Let's make a function
"write_captions_to_excel_file" and
it is going to accept images as its parameters.
OK, so this is the same images which
we're getting in "downloading_captions".
OK.
Now what we want to do is we're going to create a
"Workbook" object. I say "workbook" and here I'm going to
give it the path,
the caption path. Actually I can pass a caption path here.
So we have the caption folder path here.
Right.
So what I do is "caption_path" plus "captions.xlsx".
What this line is going to do is this line
is going to create an Excel sheet at this path.
So "Workbook" takes one parameter, it actually takes a lot.
But for now for simplicity's sake let's say
that it only takes one parameter which is the path
where the Excel file is going to be created.
Now as soon you have an object, a Workbook,
you have to make sure that you close it.
OK.
And the reason behind that is that ensures the
integrity of the data in that Excel file.
Now that we have an Excel file what we want
to do next is we want to see if there's...
I'm sure you must be familiar with sheets if you have used Exel.
So in Excel basically we have sheet, we can add
sheets like we can have in
a single Excel file,
you can have 10 sheets.
It doesn't matter you can just keep adding them.
Maybe I can show you that.
So let's just open up.
Open.
OK.
So this some Excel file I have and you can see that
there's a sheet one here I can add another sheet
here I can have some other data right.
So to work on an Excel file it's necessary that you have a sheet.
OK.
The data comes on the sheet and you can
have many sheets in a single workbook.
So we say "workbook.add_worksheet".
Let's keep it simple and I'm not passing it any parameter.
So that is going to create
one single worksheet.
Now
I have an object of worksheet.
So I'm at row zero.
So what we would like to do is at row zero or
we would like to have say in the first
column the image names and the second
column their corresponding captions.
So that would really increase the readability here.
So say that I'm at row number two
and seeing the image name here I can
see that it contains this caption, right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going
to say "worksheet.write", "row".
I'm going to walk you through this
function I'm using right now.
So don't worry about it.
So the first thing I wanted was the image name,
"row", 1, "Caption". Ok, so "write" basically takes three arguments.
It takes more but for simplicity's
sake let's say it takes three arguments.
OK, so the first one is row number on which roll
do you want to write, then the column number
and lastly the value which you want to write in that
place, in that cell you have selected a row and
column number.
So what we...
Oh, I'm sorry.
OK.
So this is the correct function.
So what I'm doing here is I at row zero and column zero.
I'm adding image name and at row zero and column one.
I'm adding caption to that will be here.
It would be image name.
And here would be caption.
OK.
Perfect.
OK, so now that we have these what we want to do is
we want to move forward and we want to have the image
names and the captions here.
So let's get to that. "index, image in enumerate(images)".
So let's get the filename. To the filename,
we are simply going to use this
based on the image id we had actually.
I mean, get the filename from here.
OK.
So this is the filename.
So this is the filename we have and the caption is
"image".
And how we were finding captions it was via "alt",
the attribute "alt". Now seven images
didn't have captions, so this is going to throw an exception.
We need to have this in a "try catch" block.
"exception KeyError", "caption",
"No caption exists".
OK, so now that we have this what we would
like to do next is "worksheet.write",
row and now the idea is that we want
to write two values in a single row.
How do we manage that. One way, the easier
way is that we just hardcode it, "filename"
and "caption" and then I could add this.
That way would be say like you have a lot of column,
so say that you have 100 columns.
This is not a good idea then.
So then what you can do is you can use another for
loop in this for loop we have, so nested loops
to write this Excel sheet. OK, so this should
write our captions to an Excel file.
Let's run this and see if it actually works or not.
I'm going to comment this because
we don't need all those ".txt" files.
So I'm going to call this now.
"self.write_caption_to_excel_file" and it needs images.
I'm going to give it "images", "caption_folder_path".
OK.
Let me open instaPhotos and delete everything we have in captions.
OK, so that's done.
And we can add a print statement here, "writing to excel".
I'm going to run this now and then would know what we have done.
Does it work or not. OK.
There you go.
So opening Instagram,
our target profile,
it is going to load all of the images now on the page,
scrolling down. Good, we are doing good.
Ok, so anytime now it'll start downloading the captions.
So we should have our Excel sheet printed because
it is downloading photos now. Yes, we have it but
the path is wrong. We have it here
and we're supposed to have in
the caption path and the reason behind that is
that I forgot to add a forward slash. I'm going to rerun
this and we should have this now in the captions folder.
OK, I should have added a forward slash
because the "caption_path" only contained
the caption path of this folder we have that's the
reason you should always use "os.path.join" like
we did here to do this because then you're sure
that this is not going to happen like just
happened right now.
And I think I should do that too.
So "os.path.join" and "caption_path".
There we go.
So this is interesting that not all the images
had loaded because it says lenth of all images is 13
which is not true because the
length of all images is thirty one.
So let's see what went wrong.
I'm going to delete everything we have in this insta folder.
Let's close this Excel sheet.
OK.
I'm going to run this again.
This might have only happened
because of the fact that like
scraping is not consistent. The browser,
may be my netbooks speed.
It wasn't good enough.
That's why the
photos didn't load.
And that's probably the most likely reason for
now because there's this thing, it's not
consistent.
You get problems maybe when the SSL handshake
wasn't being performed, something happened.
So it can vary.
OK, let's run this again.
Let's see if we're able to get everything
now and be able to get everything now.
I've commented this.
And you'd also be able to check this, "os.path.join"
we have included.
So this is going to log us in.
So I think it's probably my internet,
you saw that it's really slow.
It should start scrolling down once the initial
page loads, you can still see the search tool.
So that hasn't happened.
Now it stoped scrolling down. OK, it's going down.
We are good and I think we have all the photos.
Let's see.
Yes, we have all of them.
Length of all images is thirty one. Perfect.
So let's get back to our
captions and if I open captions
we can see that we have all the captions
now.
"image_0",
"change profile photo"
and
moving down.
You should have 31 captions and it says me thirty.
And the reason behind that is because
we started counting from zero. So we are good.
And "image_30" also doesn't have any captions.
OK.
Perfect.
So this is working.
I hope this made sense to you.
There are other ways to get this done.
You can use Pandas to write to an Excel file
but the easiest way would probably be using
"xlsxwriter" for this.
And remember you have to close the Workbook.
Always, OK.
I hope this made sense to you.
And if you find any if you have any difficulty
understanding, this if you think that something
is missing or there's another issue, you can always ask
questions and we'll be happy to get back to you
as soon as we can.
Thank you.