Hello everyone. In this video, I am going
to explain to you your first project.
So I have the site opened here, "codingbat.com".
This website has questions of Java and Python and
it helps you learn Java and Python questions especially
for competitions for different competitions like ICPC.
OK, so you can see that you have
a compiler, you have a sort of thing
where you can type code and then you can say
"Go" and then you can see the solution for it and
there are multiple questions here.
I mean there are many questions you can find.
So the flow for this website is that there are sections.
As you can see for Java you have "Warmup-1", "Warmup-2",
then "Strings" and "Array" and "Logic-1" and "Logic-2", "Array-2"
"Array-3", "AP-1", then "Recursion-1" then "Map-1" and
"Map-2" and then if I click let's say I click on "Warmup-1"
which I've opened here.
So as soon as I open this,
you can see I have questions here.
So for each section you get questions, like
you open the section you get questions.
You can see them here, like "sleepIn" is a question. Each of these listed links
are links to questions.
So when I open "sleepIn", it opens this.
This is a question here.
OK.
So you can see that this is a question and this here,
the three statements here, they are example
inputs and exemple outputs, the required
outputs.
So the question is this one here and the example inputs
and outputs are this one here. So the "sleepIn"
takes "false" and "false" as its inputs and then it returns "true".
It returns us "true" if the inputs are "false" and "false".
So these are sample inputs and this is a sample output.
So once again the flow is like you have sections here.
Then as I open the section, each section has many
questions, so multiple questions and then I open
a single question and I get this here,
where I can type code and everything.
And here I have a question here, a question
statement and then the question examples.
So what I want you to do is I want you
to scrape each question and the examples for that
question and I want you to give
this to me in a standardized format.
Once again we opened the site.
This page opens, this has sections here.
Each section has questions.
These are questions "sleepIn", "monkeyTrouble",
"sumDouble", "endUp, "icyHot", "startHi".
So as soon as you open the question, you get this window
and in this window you can see that this is the
question here.
This is a question and this is a sample input/output.
So basically I wanted the whole of this.
I want this highlighted data.
I want all of these questions that are present here
in this CodingBat for Java, not for Python. Only for
a Java.
So my hint is what you can do is you can
scrape this first like the links for these sections.
Then you can open them in a loop and then
for this page you scrape the questions like the link
for these questions and then you open each question
in aloop and then you get the desired values
and then you can make a dictionary or a list, that depends
on you, but the output should be in a standardized
format.
I hope the project description is clear to you
and I've given you a hand, a big one,
as to how you can do this.
And I'll see you in the next video with the solution.
But I would really appreciate if you do this yourself first.
I am sure you can do this.
Thank you very much.
See you.