Hello everyone! In the last video,
I explained the description for this project which
states that you have to scrape questions from
"codingbat.com".
So in this video, I'm going to show you how
the solution is structured and how we are going to do
this.
And I have divided the solution for this project
in three separate videos so I'll let you know that
how I've done divisions and how we are going to go
about this.
So if you remember here in Coding Bat, we
have sections so I have opened Java.
By default it's Java.
So I have Java here, and Java has different sections like
"Warmup" and "Array" and "Logic" and "Strings"
and again "Array", "Recursion",
and then this "Map", that "Map" here.
So each section contains some questions.
So if I open this section "Warmup-1", it contains some
questions. So the questions are like "sleepIn",
"monkeyTrouble", "parrotTrouble", "nearHundred".
These are all questions, so let's say that I opened this
question and as soon as I open it, I get the question and
the examples with them.
So if you see this way there are basically
three pages that you're navigating from. First you click
on the desired section, the section you want the questions from and
then as soon as you've open that.
So here I have question for "Warmup-1" and then select
the desired question which I want to see or code.
And then when they get here.
Here is the actual question,
the example. So we want this right.
So the way I have structured the solution is that in the
first video we scrape this like is this, the sections
and the links to them, and then in the second
video we scrape questions for each section.
Like how many questions it has and the link for
each question and then in the final video
we scrape the question and the example with that.
This is the hierarchy of solution.
And in this video, I'm going to discuss how we can scrape
these, how are we going to scrape the links from these
sections.
And I'm sure you're familiar with "Inspect Element" of a browser.
So I have sections here.
"Warmup-1", "Warmup-2"...
So what I do is I try to see the HTML for this "codingbat.com".
So I have it opened here and you can see that this
"div" contains this "Warmup-1". You can see
it highlighted there.
Then as I move to the second "td" and it again says that
this is a "div" which highlights "Warmup-2"
and then you can see this for each section I have.
So there's a similarity here.
The similarity is that each "div" has its class "summ" contains a section's
link.
So if I open this, you can see I have a "a" tag here which
contains the link for that section and right now
I've opened "String-1".
So we can cross-check this by going to
the very end and then seeing if this
this is repeated everywhere.
And yes, it is. You can see that here that I'm at this "div" and
it shows me, it highlights the "Recursion-2" section.
So if I open this "div" I get an "a" tag which gives me
this here, the questions of the
section "Recursion-2". So now what we want to do is we want to
scrape the links for each section and then
we can open the link for each section.
And then after we're done with that what we're
going to do is to scrape the questions from each
page other of that section and then open each question
and then scrape the question statement and the examples.
So right now what we do is we're going to scrape the link
for each section. So you can see this it contains
a "href" attribute which shows us a relative link.
So what is the relative link?
If I open this here, which I have open here, you can see
that this contains, the link for this is
"codingbat.com/java/Recursion-2".
And if I see this here, it only shows me "java/Recursion-2".
So what does this mean.
This means that this is a relative URL and this
URL is being added to the main URL
of this site which is "codingbat.com". So now to extract
the original URL what I'm going to do is
I need to add the "http://codingbat.com".
So I'll just show you how this is going to work.
So like what we have seen right now is that all of the
section is contained in a "div" which has its class
"summ".
So let's see if we can make this work.
And if this is true and I hope that we don't get another
"div" which has its class "summ". So let's see.
I say "all_divs" is equal to
"soup.find_all('divs')" and then I say "class_"
So I think it has tow m's. Yes, it has. "for divs in all_divs", print "div"
So if I run this now.
And you'll be able to see that if
you're right or wrong about this. Let's see.
So you can see, it has given me all the "divs" that this page
here contains and you can see that this is
the right approach because you can see that
for each "div" class, I have a "a" tag which
contains the section you are in.
So I start from "Warmup-1", then "Warmup-2", then strings,
array, logic, strings again, array again and then recursion and then map.
So this is it.
This is it.
So what we one now is we wanted this "a" tag,
we want this "a" tag "href" attribute.
So let's see if I can extract the "a" tag for each
"div" tag.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to navigate through this
HTML structure for this "div" which has a "div" and then is a
child of this "div".
So I say "div.a" and I'm going to run it
again and let's see if this works or not.
You see now I have "a" tags for each section.
So what I have done right now is that I
got the divs and then I navigate
to the "a" tags using that "div". So if I remove that ".a"
and if I run it again, you see it gives me "div" and
then it has a "a" tag here.
So to clean this, to jump directly to "a", what to
do with I say "div.a" and if I run that it gives
me all the "a" tags for each section.
Now we're not interested in the "a" tags, we are only
interested in the links for the "a" tags.
So what I do is I say "div.a['href']".
So this here is how we access a tags
attributes. So if I  run this now, you can see it
only gives me
the URL, a relative URL for that sections.
So the first one is "Warmup-1", string, array, logic and string again.
So what was the base URL.
I mean if I open this
you see the base is "codingbat.com" and then relative URL is
"Java/Warmup-1".
In this case, "Recursion-2".
So the base URL here is this, is "codingbat.com".
So I need to say "base_url".
So this is the "base_url" and then remove the backslash here
because this already has a backslash
this relative URL.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say print "main_url" plus
"div.a['href']". And if I run this now, you see it  gives
me the link for each section because this is complete now.
You see what I've done wrong is that this now gives me "java/java". So
what's wrong here.
The thing is that I had this "main_url" variable
which contain this and I should have
"base_url" here.
So let's run it again.
And you can see now that it gives me the exact link
for each section then I can open this is just to
see if this works or not. I'm going to copy this here
and I'm going to paste it here.
So let's see.
So this works, it has given me "String-2" questions.
So I copied "String-2" here.
So you see this.
These are valid link.
So now what we want to do now is that we want to open each of this section.
Now that I have the links for each section, I'm going to
open each section and we are going to scrape the links
for each question.
And after I'm done with that, I'm going to open each question
and then I'm going to scrape the question statement
and examples for that question.
So this is how we're going to do this.
I hope up to now this is clear to
you and I'll see you in the next video.
And I hope that will clear things up more.
Thank you very much.