Hello everyone! In the last video, we've discussed
how we can scrape the links for each section.
So we discussed how we are going to scrape the links of "Warmup-1",
then strings, logic, arrays, recursion, map.
We discuss how we can scrape these links.
And now the next task is that we have to open each
section. So we open each section and then we
get we get questions here for each section.
So the next task is that we have to scrape the links for each question.
You can see it is a link to a question which
contains the question statement and the examples
for that question.
So how are we going to do this.
Now we have developed a script which scrapes the links for each section.
And now here what we are going to do now is we are going
to write a script which is going to scrap the question
links for each section. So we can open this link here.
This link, the link we have scrapped using the
"request" module and then after doing that we get this page and
now what we are going to do is we are going to scrape this
question links and then we can again open them in
a list using a loop and then we can scrape these
question statements and the examples with it.
So now the idea is to scrape these questions and
this is what I'll be doing in this video as
we decided earlier that we are going to split this project
into three parts. The first part is the main
page from where we will be scrapped the links for each section.
Then the next part is where we scrape the question links from each section.
And finally we get the question page where we have the question statement and examples.
So one thing to note here is that there is a structure being followed here.
Let's see if I open "Warmup-1" and it opens up some questions here.
So if there is going to be some "div" here in which these questions are contained.
And if I open another section it's going to be the same "div" which contains these questions.
I mean so like there's repetition here and this
repetition actually helps you structure code nicely.
And this also helps scraping because like if your
HTML is structured then you can easily scrape data from that website.
And as you can see that this website has
structured HTML, by structured I mean that there is a proper
structure that is being followed.
So if let's say I'm just going to use "Inspect Element",
I'm going to show you this what I'm talking about.
So let's say I have this "div" here, "div class='tabin'"
which has it's class "tabin" and this is for "Warmup-1"
So if I open up "Map-2"
and if I see that... OK, you can see that
this "Map-2" also contains a "div"
which contains its class "tabin" and it contains all the questions.
So you can see that there is a structure being followed here.
So that is like when you open the section the questions
that are being displayed for that section, they
are in the "div" which each has its class "tabin".
I hope this makes sense to you.
So now let's get back to our code.
What we did in our last section, in our last
video, was this. We accessed main
"div" and then using the "div"
we iterate that "div"
and then we got they URL using this "div.a['href']"
tag and then we are adding "base_url".
We are using "base_url" into this URL we
were scrapping from the website because
the URL here was relative.
OK, so now to rewrite this I can say "all_links" is
equals to...
So I'm just using list comprehension for writing this, "for div
in all_divs".
So this is basically equal it. OK, so now "all_links"
contains the link for each section which we are going to
open.
So how we are going to do this.
We say "for link in all_links".
Sorry for that.
So now the thing is that we want to get to this page here.
This page which contains the question links,
the links for the questions.
So what I do is I say in "inner_page" is equals to
"requests.get", then I say "link" and I can
add the "headers" here, and I say "user-agent.chrome"
OK.
So now I have sent a request to this page and I have this
open in this response object now I can make
a soup. I can say in "inner_soup" is equals to in "inner_page".
Sorry, I say "BeautifulSoup".
and "inner_page"
and I use "lxml".
OK, so now I've made a soup of this page here.
Great.
Now the question is how do I scrape this question links.
So we're going to observe the HTML for this page and I'm
going to see how we can get to these questions,
the links to these questions. So you can see that there
is this "div" here which has its class "tabc"
then in it we have
a another "navbar" which contains "Java" and "Python"
links, you can see that here. As soon as I come to this
"nav", you can see that that bar is highlighted
then I move down to this "div class='tabIn'".
This "tabIn" contains the questions for each section.
And all of this is contained in "tabc".
So let's open "tabIn" and see what we have there.
So I as soon as I've opened it, you can see that I
have this "span" which highlights the "Warmup-1"
like the section's name and then I have the starts here and
then I have this table here which contains the
links for each question as you can see that
only that part is highlighted now. So this table
is what I'm supposed to be after.
Let's see the structure for that table,
how this is laid out. OK, so this table has rows and
each row contains three questions, you can see
that as I move down. Look next three questions are highlighted.
And if I move down again, the next three questions are
highlighted.
So each row contains three questions.
Each row contains the links for the questions
and as I open the row, I get columns.
So I get three columns here and for the first column
I have "sleepIn" and then this "monkeyTrouble"
then this "sumDouble".
Each "td" contains a single question link.
So if I open a "td", you'll see I have an
image here which is that tick here.
Like that tick mark.
And then I have this "href" like "a" tag.
So this "a" tag contains the link for
that question, a relative link again.
OK.
Now what we want is you want this "a" tag's attribute "href"
so that we can get the link for this question.
So once again, let's see how we are going to get to this.
There was a main "div" which had its class "tabc"
and in that "div" we have the "div"
again "tabIn" and then in that "tabIn" div, we
have a table which has rows and each row
contains three columns which has a "div" tag.
And then each "td" tag contains a single
question, a link for a single question.
OK, so let's start off with this "div".
Let's go with this "div". We're going to get to
this "div class='tabc'". Let's see if we can
get to this. Ok, we are going to use break because
like let's just do this for one section because like this all links
is a list for each section.
You know like I think I have how many sections here?
One, two, three, four, five... Twelve... I have fifteen sections here.
So this all links contains 15 links, for each section.
And as we saw earlier that each sections go into a structure.
The HTML code is structured.
So if you do this for one section like if
I've done a script which scrapes the question links
for one section, that is going
to work for any other section.
So I'm only going to open the first link
and I'm going to see if I can make this work.
So that's I'm using a break here.
OK.
So what we decided right now was that we are
going to access this "div" which has class "tabc".
And see if we can get to that.
Or if there could be another "div" here
which has its class "tabc". So let's see
if this is the "div" like this is how we are
going to access this "div" there which has its class
"tabc". OK, so we say "div" is equals to "inner_soup.find".
And then I say "div", then I say "class_"
and "tabc". I'm going to print this "div"
now and let's see what happens.
OK, so you can see that here, that this "div" has "tabc", that
this have "navbars".
And if I get that here.
OK, so far so good.
We have a "div" and then a "nav" and then you can seen that
now I have this "Python" and "Java".
You can see this here, this "Python" and this
is here actually, this "Python" and this "Java".
So then after that, we have this "table" here which has
its rows and then each row has this "td" tag which contains
the problem link,
is this "a" tag.
So I think it's safe to assume that we have that
right "div" is because you can see that these are the
links for the questions we just saw. OK, so now
what this means is that we have access to this
"div" here which I have highlighted,
this "div" has its class "tabc".
So we have access to this "div".
So what's next.
Now this "div" has a child, a descendant, which is "table" here.
And then this "table" contains here contains "td" tags.
And we want to find those "td" tags because each
the "td" tag contains a link for a single question.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say print
"div.table" to see if I can access the table directly.
And apparently yes, we can access the table directly by
writing "div.table" because "table" here is a child
of this "div" here, this div "tabc", a descendant of this "tabc.
So what we do is we write "div.table" so
gets it searches for the first table
to find at is descendant.
When I write this.
So the first table that is descendant of "tabc" like
this "div" has its class "tabc" is this table
here which contains the links for each question.
So you can see that here that it has rows
and then it has "td" tags in that
and then each the "td" tag contains an "a"
tag which contains a link for a question.
OK so now what we want to do is we want to get to this
"td" here. We want to get to the "td" element.
So what I can do is I can say "for td in
div.table.find_all", let's search for "td"
and see if you can find it. Print "td".
So what I'm doing right now is this
"div.table" means that I am at this this element
here,
this tag here and now here I use the "find_all" function
using this tag.
So this "find_all" function is going to search
within this "table" tag like within the descendants
of this "table" tag for "td" because as we saw earlier each
"td" contains a link for a single question, it contains
an anchor tag which contains a link.
So I'm going to search "td" and I'm going to see
if I can search like this. If I can't do this,
I have to think in another approach.
And I'm going to run this and see if I can make this work.
I think this works as you can see that I've all
the "td" which are present in this "table".
So let's just make sure that this is the right "td".
So I have this "td" then I have this image.
Then I have "a" tag which contains the
relative link for the question
like for each question to that section.
So let's see if this is consistent.
OK.
Then as you can move downwards, you can see the cursor we
are moving, so I have problems and these are valid
problems.
So these are the questions that you want.
These are the links we want to scrape.
So now how do we get to this
"a" tag here. Let's just say print "td.a" and run it.
So you can see that this works. What I did right now
was that we saw that each "td" has an anchor tag.
OK.
So I only wrote "td.a". After accessing "td",
like I said "td.a" and now I am
here. You can see this here.
I have the "a" tags.
And now what I want was I want the relative URL for each question.
I'm going to get the attribute for this "a" tag using
the dictionary method and let's see if I can get them.
Great.
So I have the relative URL for each problem.
OK.
So now the thing is that how are these questions placed.
I mean like that the relative URL. OK, so you can
see that the link that I've scraped
contains...
Where is it?
OK.
So here.
So this contains a relative URL which says "prob" and
then it has some id number, slash some id
number.
And what I want to just see now was that
before this, do I have this "java" here?
Like this "java/Warmup-1" here? Or is the base URL is
something else.
So when I open this question, I saw that this part
I've highlighted, this part has something
which I have.
OK.
Now that "codingbat.com".
This thing here.
This thing here is
the base URL, so the base URL remains
the same which we have here.
It remains the same. So what I am doing now
is I'm going to say "base_url" plus
"td.a['href']".
So you can see that I have the links for
questions like the whole question for
the first section and I'm just going to open
one of this just to make sure that this works.
So I say...
OK, so you can see that I have open this question
which I says the question name is "makes10",
and its from "Warmup-1" section and now I can actually
remove this "break" and you are going to see that it is going
to open each section and give me the links for
the questions that are present in each section.
And if I run this now, this may take a while
but you can see that it is scraping the question links from each section.
And it should be done any time now.
So you can see this here that it has printed
the link for each question here.
And see this there
OK.
So this was actually what we wanted.
Now like we had decided to split our project
into three parts. The first part was that
we scrape the links for each section.
Then the second part was that we scrape the questions
links that are that are present in the section in
each section and then the final part is that we scrape
the statement, the question statement and the examples
for that question.
So we have been able to scrape the links for these sections.
Okay.
And then what we do is we open each link in the loop and
now what we do is we scrape the questions present
in each section and we have also done that.
So I can write it like this.
I can say "question_links" is equals to "base_url" plus "td.a['href']
for div in div.table.find_all".
I'm only writing a list comprehension for this
because this is way more neat than this.
And I can do it like this like "for question
in question_links" to see if this works or not.
And I can use a "break" again, I don't want
to go to each page and see it again.
I mean if it works for the first and that works for the rest.
So yes, it works.
So for the first section like it shows me the
questions for the first section of this list like the list
comprehension returned here.
So it works, it actually works.
OK, so now this is for now we have completed the second
section of our project as we had decided earlier
and now in the final section, the final pardon, we are going to
scrape the question statement and the example, like this
example here which is for that question. I hope that
I made things clear and I hope this makes
more sense to you.
Just look at the code and play with
that and see how it is working.
I'm sure though that you have done this already like
you've coded this already so just think if
you need help or if you're stuck you can just review
this code and you could see how this is working.
Thank you very much
and I see you in the next video.