Hello everyone.
So in the first part what we did was we
got the links for each of these categories here
which we have for Java like "Warmup-1", "Warmup-2",
"String-1", "Array-1", "Array-2", "Array-3", "Recursion".
So in part two, our last video, what we did
was we opened each category and we got the links for
each of these questions here.
Like "sleepIn", "diff21", "parrotTrouble", "icyHot", "front22",
all of this. So what we did was we had
a loop and we opened each category and in
each category what we did was we had the question links.
Like I got all of the questions here, the
links for each of the question here
in this list there.
And then what I'm doing is I'm running
a "for" loop and printing each question.
So this is going to run and give me the
question links for the very first category.
So here they are all of them.
So now the next step is what we want to do is we want
to open each question and we want to get the problem
statement here and the examples associated with that.
So these examples are like the sample function prototypes
which indicate the input data for this function
and the output
this function should return.
So how do we go about this now.
So what we are going to do here now that I have the
question links for each category, now I say "for
question_link
in question_links".
So I'm going to open this "final_page". I say "request.get", I "question_link".
Now that I have the "final_page" and I'm going
to make the "final_soup" of this. I say
"BeautifulSoup", "final_page.content" and then the parser here.
So now that I have made the soup out of this
page then the final step here is actually getting
this problem statement here
and then the example to see it. So let's just
review the HTML structure for this page.
So I say "Inspect Element".
And if I go here, you can see that I have the problem
statement here in this div "minh" and if I move
upwards,
if I move upwards like if I get to here, this "div",
this "div class='indent'", I can see that in encapsulates
the whole screen almost like the part where the problem statement is
and the examples are.
So what I'm going to do right now is I'm going to
try and access this "div" here which
has its class "indent".
And let's see if I can find it or not.
So I say "indent_div" is equals to "final_soup.find", "div",
attributes, "class" and "indent", and then I say print
"indent_div" and I say "break" so because I don't
really want to open this for each question because this is supposed
to be the same for each question.
So let's just run this and see what we have.
Now we know that we are moving to the right direction or not.
Ok, so I stopped this myself because we didn't have a
"break" for this here and then what it was doing
was it was opening this for each category and we don't really want that.
So I'm using "break" here as well.
OK, so maybe I can just run this again.
Just so everything is good.
OK, so you can see now that I have this
"div" class in them and its child
is this "a href" and this anchor tag which has "href" value this.
And if I go here and I see "Yes" like I am getting
the right "div" tag here. So good right now.
Now what I want to do is I want to get to the problem statement
here the problem statement is here and
that "div" we have right now is here.
So how do we to our problem statement.
We can see that this "div" has a "table".
So how about just navigating down our parse tree.
So I can say print "indent_div.table" and let's run this
and see if I can get to "table" here.
OK, so I have a "table" and it has a "tr" and a "td" and
then and another "div" and I guess this is a problem
statement, "the parameter weekdays is
true". Yes.
This is the problem statement.
So we are getting the "table" now.
I mean what I did was I said "div.table" to get it
down my parse tree. So right now I stand here at this
"table" tag.
So now I want to move downwards and I want
to access this problem statement.
I say "table".
How about let's jump to this "div" directly.
I mean there is no "div" before this so we should be good to go.
So I say "table.div" and let's print
this and see if we can get this done.
OK, so I think we are good.
I have this "div", "div class='minh'". You can see
that it is actually giving me the problem statement
so I can just say ".div.string" and this should
return me only the problem statement minus the
tags.
Great.
So we have the problem statement.
So I think it's safe to say the
"problem_statement" is equals to "indent_div.table
.div.string".
And just to be sure, I can just print
this again and see if we're good or not.
So we have successfully scraped the problem statement from this page here.
Now the next step is we want to get these examples too.
So how do we go about this now.
So if I'm able to access this "div" tags and
I want to access these three examples.
So I assume that...
I think it's OK to assume that these are
the siblings of this "div" here right.
Because I mean they're all children of
"td" and there's this "div" and there's this "br" and these strings
are at the same level.
So they're siblings.
So how about I say
"siblings_of_statement"
is equals to
"indent_div.table.div.next_siblings".
So this should return me a generator object
because the "next_siblings" method returns
me a generator object.
I can just print it to be sure that what I'm doing is right.
I say print "siblings_of_statement" and if I run this now
it just returned me a generator object.
I can just loop through this.
I can say "for sibling in siblings_of_statement",
print "sibling" and let's remove this and let's run
this and see if we're able to access the siblings and
if these examples are the siblings of our problem
statement, or this "div" here which has its class
"minh". I think we are successful here.
I'm getting the "br" tag and I am also getting the examples here.
You can see them right here.
But there's also a lot of unnecessary
garbage here which we don't really want.
OK, so how do we filter this.
Something like that.
The this "br" tag doesn't really has anything for its ".string".
So let's say if
"sibling.string" is not "None".
The ".string" method, we are going to see that if the tag
the which we are accessing right now which is a sibling
of our main "div" here, this main "div" here, if it has
a string object associated with it then
we are going to print it
else you are not going to print it.
Let's just run this and see if we can get this working.
So this is working great.
And you can see that what I have here is that I have the
examples which we really wanted the three examples
and I'm getting and
what I did was
if I don't to use this...
So what was happening was that I was getting all the
siblings of the main "div" here and which I didn't
really want and I don't want this "br", I don't
want this "p" tag here, I don't want this "form"
tag here.
I don't want these "script" tags here.
So how do we get rid of them.
So what I did was I made an observation.
I saw that this "br" tag does not have a string object
associated with it, this "p" tag
is the same, the "button" tag is the same.
So they don't have strings is associated with
them so why not just try and see if "sibling.string"
is not "None".
And print "sibling".
So I tried this and I found that I was actually able
to get the examples and it worked perfectly.
So what I can do now as I can say
"examples" is equals to "sibling for siblings".
if "sibling.string" is not "None".
And now what I can do is I can just print this "for example in the examples",
print and if I run this now I should give examples the three here.
So this is working great.
So now what we have here is that we are accessing the problem statement and
we are also successfully retrieving three
examples associated with this problem statement.
I can just print both of them here I can say print "problem_statement"
and we should be good to go now.
I should have the problem statement first and an example associated with it.
So you can see that I have the problem statement and then examples associated with that.
So this ends our project.
I'm just going to remove the "break" tags here and
now what this is going to do is this is going to run
this for each category and each question and it might
take some time to it might take
some time to actually successfully run this.
I mean considering that it will have to open a lot of pages.
So I'm just going to add another print statement here
to differentiate between different questions and
the are examples.
So I'm just going to run this and we
will see that it's working great.
OK, so what we have achieved now is that
we were able to get the categories,
we were able to scrape the categories first,
each category, the link for each category and
then we open each category and found the links
for each question that category contained.
So then we open each question and then we successfully
scraped the problem statement and the example
associated with that.
So this is how to work and you can see that it's working great.
I'm getting the problem statement first
and then the examples associated with that and it
will take some time. You can see that
because it has to open a lot of questions.
And I mean it is going to run for each category and for
each question in each category so that's a lot
actually.
So just let it run and you'll see that it's like we're good here.
So don't worry about it
if it takes a lot of time.
OK.
So I'll see you in the next video. I hope that we have
successfully completed this project and you
don't have any queries.
Thank you very much.
See you in the next video.