Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to scrap some
data from this URL which I've opened, this website
page, this HTML page I have so the site's name is Consumer Reports
".org".
And I have this URL for this page here. I've showed you all with you in my code.
So this
here, this page contains products from A to Z.
So for A you have different products, air
conditioners, airline travel, appliance stores, athletic
shoes. For B
you have baby food, baby bathtubs, backpacks, batteries, beer, bike helmets and so on.
So the list goes on and on and on.
For each alphabet you have some products listed here.
So what I want to do here is that I want to
scrap the names of these products, these whole
products from A to Z.
One way would be that
I can write them down manually, I could say
"OK, air conditioner is first, air purifier, airline
travel, all-purpose cleaner, appliance stores..."
And I don't know how many there are there.
I mean they look a lot.
OK.
So the other ways is that we can write
a script and we can scrape the list,
the names of them, like okay which products are listed here.
So how are you going to do that. I'm going to show
this in this video, I'm going to show you
how to get a list of these products here, of all the products that are listed here.
OK.
So I have this Python file here.
What it does is I give it a URL and give it a
filename and output filename and it gives
me the HTML of that file.
It's pretty simple what I've done here is that
I've sended a request to this URL
and then I write the HTML of this URL to a
".txt" file so we don't ping the server of the site
often. OK.
So what we want to do here is that we want to scrape the names of these products.
We want to know which products are listed here.
So what do I do.
OK.
So in your browser, I'm using Safari right now.
But I'll say you could use Firefox or Chrome for
this if you want to or even Safari. Safari is good.
So when you double click,
when you right click, you get this window here and then you click "Inspect
Element" and this "Inspect Element" gives you the whole page HTML.
I have the whole page HTML here, right here.
Like where my cursor is. I'm scrolling through it right now.
So as soon as I move over to some element, you know, it's highlighted.
Here you can see, the "By Category" is highlighted in my HTML page.
So as like I moved here now the product part is highlighted.
So this shows me that this div contains this data on the HTML page.
So what I'm interested in is I'm interested in the
names of the products listed so I say "air conditioner",
"Inspect Element".
So you see here we have this "air conditioner" is written
and it is in the "span" tag. Can you see this here?
This is a "span" tag
and as I move upward
I get a "a href" tag and then as I get a "div"
tag and then I have another that "div". So
if I close this "div", you can see I have
multiple divs which say "results".
And in each "results" there, there is another "div" "entry-letter".
And this is similar for each product.
You can see that "entry-letter" here is for "air
conditioners". Then as I move downwards I get it for "air
purifiers" and then as I move further down what I get
is for "airline travel", so it's safe to assume that each
product has this div. I'll just make sure by
going to some random product and if I go to
"coffee makers" and if move I forward here, you can see right
now in this "span" of this "coffee makers", I move up a tag
then there is this "div" and this "div" which has a
class "entry-letter" so you can see that this is consistent like
all the products are under a "div" tag which has its class "entry-letter".
So this is something which is common in all the product,
all the products that are listed here.
So right now I want you to run this script and this would generate
a HTML file for this page.
So the name I've set is "consumer_reports".
I mean it depends on you.
Whatever you want, you can set it here and the URL for this site is this one.
So I run this and here is my "consumer_reports.txt" this page.
You can see that here, so I have the HTML for this page here in this ".txt" file.
OK so what I do know is
I open this file, I read this file and then I make a soup out of this file
this "consumer_reports" file. So I have a soup of this
whole page here, the soup of the page you are viewing.
So what did we decide on? We decided that every product
has one thing in common that it is under a "div"
tag which has its class "entry-letter".
You can see it here.
We can just make the sure by moving to some on the very end.
So for some of the products that are listed at the very end.
So if I click on this "Washing Machine" and if I say
"Inspect Element", I can see this "span" and then as I move upwards
I can get to the "a" tag
and then up further to the "div" tag and then here,
this "div" here which has its class "entry-letter".
OK, so now what we can do is I want to find all the divs
which have the class "entry-letter" as they contain
the name of a product. OK, so I say "all_divs" is
equals to "soup.find_all", and then I say "div"
and now I can set the attributes and I could say "class",
"entry-letter". I think this is it, "entry-letter" yes.
I've just matched it and it's "entry-letter". OK, so
if I say "for div in all_divs", print "div"
you can see it returns me a list of divs with class "entry-letter".
OK so now I want to print this.
I want to know that.
OK.
Which product is being listed here.
No this is garbage.
I mean OK.
Yes, I can see that "air conditioners" is here right
now but I only want the "air conditioning" thing.
I don't want this "a" tag, I don't want this "span" tag, I
don't want this "div" tag here, I only want to see
the name of the product listed.
I don't want this, I don't want these tags here,
I don't want the HTML of these tags here.
So what do I do.
As you can see that if I'm at this "div" which has
its class "entry-letter" where is my span
which contains "Washing Machines".
So this "div" has a child which is a "div",
then this is a child which is an "a" tag.
And then this "a" tag has a child with just the "span" tag.
So what I do is I say print "div.div". OK.
So I started off from here when they say "div.div"
I get to this div here and then I want to get
to this "a" tag. What I do is I say ".a".
Now I made this "a" tag and now I want to get the "span"
tag so what I do know is I say ".span". So now I'm
at the "span" tag.
And if I run this, you can see it gives
me "span" tags, whole "span" tags.
And then in each "span" tag I have a string which
lists the name of the product I'm interested in.
So how do we get the list out the tag? We use the ".string" method.
And if I run it, it gives me the names of all
the products which are listed on this page
here. All of them.
So I hope this is clear to you.
So if I want to make a list what I can do is I can say "products" is equal to
"div.div.a.span.string for div in all_divs".
and now
I can iterate over this.
If I want to I can say print "product". You can
see it gives me the whole list of products.
This "product" contains the name of each product that is listed on this page.
So I hope this example is clear to you and I hope
that how this works and how we can actually
apply the skills we have learned on life sites and
how we can scrape data and how we can define
the data that we have scraped and get the values which we really need.
And I hope that now this is both clear to you. In the next video, we are going to work on
this.
We are going to work more on this.
I'll have a slight change.
So the data that I want to extract and then we'll see how we do that.
After that you've been to get a project which I want you to work on yourself.
And then then we can discuss on the project like what I
want you to do with the project and how you are going to
achieve it.
Thank you very much.
I'll see you in the next video.