Hello everyone!
In the last video, we saw how we can scrape these product names from this HTML page.
Now as you can see that each product, if I
open it, like it's a link which opens to another page.
So what I want to do here is I want to be
able to scrape the links for these products.
So I mean like each of them is a link.
If I say "Inspect Element", you can see it says me an "a"
tag and it gives me a link here which I can open.
So I'm here in this "Best Athletic Shoe Buying Guide"
and then here in this "Best Baby Bathtub Buying Guide".
So there are separate links which I can open.
Now what I want is I want the names as well
as the links for each of my products here like what
link do I have for baby bathtubs.
So what I can do is I can have a dictionary.
I can have a dictionary of products and I say "products" is
equals to this and now a dictionary could be like
product name is key and the product
link is the value. OK.
So how do we get this.
How do we get these "a" tags.
So that's the first task.
If you remember you know like how we managed to get the the name tags in
our previous video where we said that all of these products are under this "div"
which has class "entry-letter".
So what we did was we found all that divs which had the class "entry-letter"
and then we extracted the string from this "span" tag.
After getting these divs. So we are going to do
the same thing, I'm going to say "div.div.a.span.string
for div in soup.find_all" and then I say
"div" and it has class equals to "entry-letter".
So this gives me product names
"product_names".
So if I say "for product in product_names" and if I
print "product", you can see I have the names here.
So this line here gives me the product names
of all the products which are listed
on this HTML page. OK, so now that I have the names
of the products which are listed here, what
I want now is I want the links to these products.
So as you can see what
I was doing here was I was saying "div.div.a.span",
I had this "a" tag here and this "a" tag
contains the link to that product. So I can say
"product_links" is equals to "div.div.a"
and I could either use a function or a dictionary value, and then
I could say "href" and "for div in soup.find_all()"
"div", and "class_" is equals to "entry-letter"
so "for link in product_links"
and if I print "link".
It gives me the link to all of the products which are mentioned here.
So what I did was I just walk through this again.
And I find that the "entry-letter" div, which is
this, and I get to this "div" and then to this
"a" tag.
And then this "a" tag contains the link to this product.
So I say "div.div.a".
And then I get the link which is in this "href" attribute.
And I make a list out of this and in this list I have the links for each
of the products that are listed here.
Now another way to do this could be using
a dictionary, we could say "products"
is equal to "div.div.a.span.string" and
then I say "div.div.a['href']
for div in soup.find_all"
and then I say "div",
I say "class_='entry-letter-".
Now when I run this, I say "for key.value
in products.items()", print "key"
and then I say
"value". So if I run this, you can see it gives me
the name of the product and the link and
the relevant link to that product.
So what did I do was I used dictionary comprehension.
This here is the key,
it is the product name as you can see here,
and this here is the value of this column which is the
link against that product name which we which
we just found here in "product_links". So then I
say "for div in soup.find_all" and I find all the divs
that have the class "entry-letter". And then this
loop, this returns me all the divs which
have the class "entry-letter".
And then I iterate through them and then I
get the desired values. The first desired
value is a string of the name of the product
which is the string in "span" which I have here.
And then the other is the link to that
product which is here, "div.div.a['href']",
and then I just print them.
So I hope this is clear to you and if you want
to scrape something from these links
what I could do was I have the list, I could
just open them and then I could scrape them.
Scrape whatever I want to from them.
So this is the basic idea of how we can do this.
And there are many different ways that you can achieve this.
And I mean this is just one way of doing this.
OK, so now we are going to move towards
a project which I'm going to give you.
And in the next video, we are going to discuss what I
want you to do for this project and I hope what I explained
in this video is clear to you and now you understand
better how we can organize our data and how we can
extract different things using the same "for" loop here.
You know, here in this statement, we are extracting
two different things, using a single "for" loop.
We're iterating over a single list and extracting multiple things.
I mean the other way to do this was that I
had to call this method two times and that just creates
complexity that's in trees that are very, very, very, very large.
So I would try to avoid that. I would
try to avoid calling the "soup.find_all" function because then
it has to recursively search my whole parse tree
which is expensive in terms of memory and time.
And this does only once.
So this is better than doing this two times.
OK, so I hope this is clear to you. In the next video, I'm going to
explain more about the project what I want you to do.
Thank you very much.
See you in the next video. Bye.