Hello everyone! In this section, we are going to discuss
Selenium and how we can use it to interact with our browsers.
So before I get into what is Selenium
and the why do we need Selenium,
I need you to understand two technologies which are widely used in the web.
One is JavaScript and the other is Ajax. So JavaScript and
Ajax, so Ajax stands "Asynchoronous JavaScript and XML".
I'm sure all of you must have heard of these technologies before.
And I'll just briefly explain what each technology is and
what problem they pose when they're scraping data
from websites.
OK so if you remember I have this Coding Bat
opened here and that section is "Warmup-1".
OK.
We opened Coding Bat in the project 1.
So I'm going to open this question here and you can see that
here I have the question statement and then I have
the examples for this question.
So what I want you to do is I wat you to scrape the solution
for this question which, if I click this button,
is here.
So when I say "Inspect Element" and I see that OK this
is a "div" which has the id "result", it contains the
solution so it should be fairly easy to get.
I mean that I could just get to this "div"
because it has a ID and ID is unique.
All I have to do is have to search for a "div" which has its ID "results".
So I give you URL of this question and
you're supposed to scrape the solution for this question.
Can you do that?
Using requests.
Can you do that? Apparently, right,
you can say that "yes, you can do that"
but I'll just show you why that is not possible.
OK.
I'm going just to reload this.
And now here we are.
This is the page.
This is the response you get when
you send a request to this URL.
So and use "Inspect Element" here and you can see that
I have the div ID here "results" but it contains
nothing, absolutely nothing.
How are you going to get your result now?
You're going to get this web page or this HTML which is here right now.
When you open this URL.
But I want a solution for this.
I want a solution for this question and I can't get it
unless click this button. As soon as I click this button I get the solution.
And you can see that my "div" is now populated.
It is not empty.
It contains some elements.
And then navigable strings.
So what happened?
I click this button and then the content of the "div"
changes but when I send a request to the server
it returns me an empty "div" which had this ID "result".
That is an empty "div".
So how do I scrape the solution for this question here.
How do I do that?
I mean I can't actually click the button with that HTMl.
You can't do that so I can't do that.
That is not possible and this
is the same
URL we use.
So what this means is that when I click this button,
my page is not reloading or it is not sending
another request to the server.
This is only happening at our site, only at the
web browser site, only my HTML content changing
and no request is being sent to the server.
So what is going on and how can we tackle this?
I mean if I want to scrape the solution for this, I
can't do that with request. Can we do that?
Unfortunately, I can't do that.
I have to know some way to interact with my webpage
so that I can click this "Show Solution"
button or let's say that I want you to search for something on Google.
So if you open Google, I want you to search for let's say my name.
How are you going to do that?
Can you type my name in using requests,
can you do that?
If you keep it simple.
You can do that if we keep it simple. You can do this, you
can search like this using requests if you
keep it simple so.
But for this case here, this JavaScript case here
I'm afraid you can't do anything about this.
You can't do anything about this.
OK, so right now here I have this Instagram open
here so you can see that here asks for me
to sign up.
I'm just giving you an example of JavaScript
and what is the problem it poses
when they're scraping data so you can see that I
need to sign up here and if I want
to sign in, I have, it says "have an account?" and log in.
So as soon as I click log in it should give me a username an ID password fields.
So just see carefully, does my page reload?
I mean does your URL changes or something when I click log in?
Or is this just happening?
This is just happening using JavaScript.
Did you see that my page did not reload as soon
as I clicked log in my page did not reload.
What does this mean.
This means that JavaScript is being used here.
JavaScript is being used here to access, to modify
the content, to modify the HTML of this page
without sending a request to server.
So I'm just going to show you something and then
I'll explain to you the next technology I mentioned,
Ajax.
OK so this is open here and it contains my news feed.
I mean this is my news feed.
OK.
So you can see that the scroll bar here and
I can only move it here and you can see
that right now there are no more photos after this.
But as soon as I get to them, many of them
like new photos appear like how is
that happening.
There weren't there in the HTML.
You see that again. OK.
Just to see it slowly.
I'm going to go slowly now.
Did you see that? How is this happening.
I mean there weren't there in the first place.
How is this happening, how are they loading again.
I mean my URL remains the same, it is same, nothing is going
wrong with then, how is this happening?
My page is not reloading.
And this is not javascript because I mean you
can't have that much photos here there.
I mean my news feed is refreshing.
So AJAX is that you send a request to server but
we don't actually reload your whole page.
So this news feed here is working the same way.
You see this.
This is working the same way.
It's the same way.
I mean like it is using AJAX to only change some
content of my HTML page here which is our news
feed stories here.
So this is Ajax and if I said I wanted you to scrape
something like I wanted you to scrape the names
of this, all the caption or something. How would you have done that?
I mean if I say I want you to scrape them like a whole news feed.
How would you do that
As soon as you open your Instagram, like your scroll bar.
That's like you can see only this much.
But as soon as I move down
you see it loads photos.
So if I open this with Beautiful Soup, I can do this.
I can do this if I parse it Beautiful Soup. I can
do this because I don't have access to all of my
photos here because they have not been loaded.
There are not in HTML.
So do how do I handle this? These problems
require some other way of thinking, there require some other way for us to interact
with their webpages so that we can actually
interact with the HTML in the server sends us
and parse it later on according to our wishes like
a want to be able to click this button but I
can't do that using requests.
Unfortunately I can't do that.
So the solution here is Selenium.
There this module Selenium which is used for
this purpose. Iit is basically a tool for automating
that applications.
But as this goes as far for web scraping that only going
to stick to that very basic stuff and how it can
help us scrape web pages which use these technologies
JavaScript and Ajax. In the next video, I'm going to
show you how to set up Selenium and how we can
actually like how we use Selenium to open web pages
and interact with them, just a very basic introductory video.
And then the later videos, we'll move on and see how we
select elements and all that stuff and how to
click buttons and write texts in our websites using Selenium.
I hope this is clear to you now and see you in the next video.
Thank you.