Hello everyone! In this video, we're going to talk about
Selenium and how we can use it with Python. In the
previous video,
we discussed JavaScript, Ajax and the need for Selenium.
So from what we know right now, Selenium is another
way of opening web pages and interacting with them.
So let's see what Selenium does and how actually does
it interact with web pages and how we can open
web pages using Selenium.
So at line number one, this is a necessary import
you need to do, "from selenium import web driver".
After doing that in my installation video you'll see that
I have shown you, you have to download the Chrome
driver for Selenium.
So wherever you have the Chrome driver in your system,
just copy that path. Like for my system the path is here,
I have it in my "Downloads" folder.
So it is right here, the Chrome driver, that's in my
"Downloads" folder. I've just copied the path and it is here
in my system.
What do you have to do is you have to see what's the path for your system.
After doing that, we are going to create a driver object.
We say "driver" is equals to "webdriver.chrome" and here I'm going
to copy this path and send it as a parameter.
OK, so now I have a driver object, that driver object.
So what is that webdriver object. You can think of it
as a complete browser, like I have a complete Chrome
browser which I can programmatically control,
I can actually control this Chrome browser programmatically.
I can actually control with clicks and
stuff, actually moving my cursor or doing
something, I'm going to control it with my code.
So as soon as you make a driver object, you need to
realize that this will open an instance of Chrome.
So what do you need to do now is you need to make
sure that when your program ends you need to close
that instance.
So I'm going to say "driver.close" this will
quit the Chrome application which is being
launched at line number eight and I'm going to run this
now and I'm going to show you what's going on and how this is
going on.
Can you see this?
It was really quick.
Maybe I'll use time to have some sleep so that
after opening, my program sleeps for let's say
five seconds so that we actually know that
the Chrome browser opened. I think five is good.
OK.
I'm going to run this now. Ok, can you see
this here? And it automatically quits.
So I can have a print statement here before "sleep".
Print "after sleep".
So "before sleep".
And here we go.
So this basically opens a Chrome browser, a complete
Chrome browser, and it can do whatever I want with
that
with that browser, with that window I have opened.
So the most basic thing that we need to do right now
is we need to open some page and see how that works
out.
So we say the method is "get" method. Here
I'm going to input the URL for Google
and then I'm going to use sleep for five
seconds so that I can see that Google is open.
OK, and I'm going to run this and then going to see if
we have Google opened, the Chrome instance, which
we create at line number eight. Let's run this
here.
So it actually opens a Google window.
I can change to anything. I could have it
to Facebook. I'm going to run this now.
You can see that here.
So you can see. So I have a Chrome window which opens a Facebook page.
So the method is "get" method and the parameter
required is the URL and these are the parameters.
OK.
So what we have seen right now is we have
learned how to open a Selenium web driver and
for these videos, we are using Chrome driver for doing this.
And we have learned that whenever we open
an instance of Chrome we need to close it.
So that's why we have this "driver.close" statement.
And if we need to open some web page we use the "driver.get" method.
This opens the required web page. And let's
say I want to get the HTML for that page.
How do I do that?
So first of all, I'm going to make a soup out of this
Facebook's HTML. I say "BeautifulSoup".
And now what I'm going to do.
What I'm going to do is I'm to say "soup" is equal to "BeautifulSoup".
Now I'm to say "driver.page_source".
This is going to give me the HTML for
Facebook page and I'm going to remove the
"sleep" here because I we only want to get the
HTML right now and see if it works or not.
And how this is actually going on.
So you can see that I have the Facebook's HTML here, you
can see this here, "html class", "id='facebook'", language
English and all that.
So this is how we get the HTML in for whatever page we
have opened on the web driver. The method is
"driver.page_source".
Sorry this
is a ".page_source".
So now this is how we can make a soup out of the
web page we have opened and using Selenium.
So previously we used Beautiful Soup with requests
and now we've seen how we can use Selenium instead of
request to open some page and in the future we are
going to see how we can interact with the elements
that are present on the web page and programmatically
control then and control the flow and elements of
our program and the browser and how this is going to work out.
I hope now you understand how this works.
I'll see in the next video, we'll
discuss more Selenium. Thank you.