Hello everyone! In this video, we are going to discuss how
we can interact with the elements that are present on
the page using Selenium.
So let's say I have opened Google here.
So if you use request and you
open Google you get this page here.
But what I want to actually do is I want to
search for something by inputting
something in this text bar and then saying Google search.
I'm want to do something like this but how can I
do it?
So one way is that we're going to use Selenium for this job.
So how do we do with this?
So this is a textfield and what Selenium is going to do
is it is going to open this page and then going
to ask it to search for this text field here
and I am just going to use "Inspect Element".
And let's see if we can locate this textfield, this "input" tag.
So this "input" tag has id "lst-ib", if you can see that here.
So I mean an id is something that is unique.
So we can access this "input" tag.
And then
what we are going to do is
we are going to write something down using Selenium
and then we'll do a google search using Selenium.
This is what I've decided for this video.
And let's get on with it now.
OK.
So here we are.
This is the basic setup we have, I made a driver object of Selenium.
OK.
And then I've also closed it.
Now what I want to do is I want to be able to search
text field here so that I can input some value
in this.
So as we have the id for this, I say "search_bar" is equals to "driver".
Now I say "find_element_by_id". There are different
ways that you can find elements using Selenium.
So you can see that one of them is by ID, then
one of then is by class name and css selectors,
link_text, element by name.
I'll have a reference document and you can
actually see which suits you better and you
can do it there.
So I'm going to show you right now how to do this by ID.
So I say "driver.find_element_by_id" and here
I'm going to input this ID for this "input" tag.
So the id is this
and OK, now my search bar is actually this text here we can see.
Now I want to send some value to this.
Like I want to input some value.
What do I do now?
Now this has another method.
It's a "search_bar.send_keys" method. Let's say
I'm going to write "I want to learn web scraping".
OK, so now what search bar is doing
is if I'm saying "search_bar.send_keys"
"I want to learn web scraping" this is going
to write this text in this field here. We are going
to see how this is happening
but, this is the method which
does this ".send_keys" method.
OK, so now as you know that this "input" tag
is basically inside and under there "form" tag.
That is how you input some data.
And data is sent to
server back as a request.
So mostly websites use forms for this.
And similarly we have a "form", we have a form
here which is the parent of this "input"
tag.
And if we actually want to search for something
what we're doing is we are submitting that form.
So where is that form.
Let's see but one other thing to note here is
that you see like this is the form here.
This is the form it contains these two buttons
and this "textfield".
If I get to this tag here, it is the closing braces
I mean there's the closing tag for "form".
So this is the "form" here.
And as soon as you press Enter or you press
Google search what that means is "OK, I'm
submitting my form. I've written and what I
wanted to know and now I want to search Google".
By submitting a "form" you mean that
OK, now you are actually submitting that
data you have input back to the server
and then server is going to send you another response back.
So how do we submit a "form" using Selenium.
One way could be that I could search this
"button" and I could use another
method which is going to search Google.
I mean it's going to click this button but we'll do
that in the next video. For right now, we can see
how we can automatically submit the form of this "input" tag.
So how do we do that
is there is a method it says "search_bar.submit".
It is going to submit the form, the search
bar.
This method is going to submit the form
in which this "input" tags is enclosed.
So this "input" tag here, this one here, it is enclosed
in this form so it is automatically going to submit
this form and when they call the submit method and
then I'm going to remove this "sleep" here
so that we can actually see that.
OK, did it even work or not.
So let's see how this goes and I'm going to run it
now.
So you see I have Google here.
I didn't do anything, I didn't write anything.
I assure you of that.
So this is like it automatically did this
it wrote that and it submitted the form.
And it's closed now because we had "sleep" for 10 seconds.
So I hope that this is clear to you.
We discussed searching tags or elements.
There are different ways we can search tags or elements
and I'll provide a document you can make. It's
a little kind of cheat sheet.
You can actually look at it and see how this works.
So you can train with yourself and learn how to do that.
And then we learned the "send_keys" method with which
we can input data into a text field or "input" tags
and then we learn how we can submit a form. In the
next video, we are going to learn how to click a button and some
other things using Selenium and then we'll move on to
some different things which we can do with Selenium.
Thank you very much.
I hope this is clear to you.