Hello everyone! In this video, we're going to learn
another way to interact with the elements present in
the Selenium web page.
So now here we have this log in button or a link.
And if I click it I get the log in window. So
JavaScript actively changes this part here.
So how is this happening?
I mean I click log in.
I get this.
So the page is not really loading it is
only JavaScript and this is like a button.
So like as soon as I click it again, this changes.
So how do I make this happen?
We're going to see right now how we can do this.
So I'm going to see the HTML for this here.
And I can see that this is basically an "a" tag which has an
"href" to a JavaScript function and the text for this
is "Log in".
So the document I shared for selecting different
elements with Selenium One. way is to select an
element using its links text.
So this "a" tag is a link and the text here is "Log in".
Let's see how we can make this work and
select this element and then interact with it.
OK, so I've opened "Instagram.com".
You can see it, this is a very basic setup we have.
OK, I've opened it.
I made a driver object, a web driver object.
Sorry.
Then I opened this "Instragram.com".
Then I've closed the driver.
OK.
So now the thing we want to do is you want to get this
element here or get this tag here and then you
want to be able to click this tag.
So what are you going to do.
I'm going to say
"login_button",
"driver.find_element_by_link_text" and then copy
the link text which is here, that is "Log in".
So now I have the "login_button".
Now I have the "login_button".
So I can say "login_button.click" and this is
actually going to click this "Log in" button.
And when I do this you can see that this window opens.
OK.
Let's see if we can make this work and I'm going
to say "sleep" for five seconds and I'm going to put some
more here too so that we can actually see this happen.
OK.
I'm going to run this now and let's see how this works.
OK, so here we go with insta
where we used five seconds of sleep.
Did you see that? Actually click that
"Log in" button or link so like this.
Right now we learned another method to which we can
interact with the elements listed on a web page in
Selenium.
That is this "click" method.
So if it's a button or a link we could we can actually click
it by selecting that element and then using
"login_button.click".
I hope up to now this is clear to you. In the next video,
we are going to discuss XPath. I'm going to give you
a very brief introduction to what XPath is that how we
can write XPath expressions, the rest of that
file and we can get to it then.
Then I hope this is clear to you and I want you
to play around with Selenium, I want you to select
different elements, open different pages.
See how you can play around with this,
search on Google, automate something, log
into your Facebook account or log in on the
Instagram account or something using Selenium.
Just try this out play with that.
Thank you very much everyone.
See you in the next video.