Hello everyone! In this video, we
are going to discuss XPath expressions.
So as we saw, with Beautiful Soup we could select different
elements using different methods of Beautiful Soup or we
could navigate through our Beautiful Soup parse
tree using different methods like we could
use different methods like "next_sibling", "siblings"
"children" or "parents". These methods help
us navigate through our parse tree while we are
at some tag in our parse tree.
So similarly there is another parser
which which is more commonly
known as "lxml" parser and it uses XPath to select
elements instead of Beautiful Soup. So XPath is generally
faster than Beautiful Soup. So XPath, we
are going to stick to very basic stuff right
now.
And and then I'm going provide you with some documents.
So you know like you could play around with it
later on just understand this more.
OK, so I'll explain how that works, how you
can write a very basic XPath function.
My function I mean an expression to select any element
in your page, in your HTML page or in an XML
file.
OK.
So let's get started.
And Xpath expression contains three different things.
First of all it contains the axis then it contains
a nodetest and then it contains the predicate.
I'll explain what this means.
Can you see this photo here?
So there is this man here and then there are like two boats.
Three boats.
And then you know there's this lighthouse
and then there's the seal here, seal here.
So OK, so what
happens now is that this guy here, he has binoculars. Can you see this?
He has binoculars.
So what do binoculars do?
I mean you know they make like wherever you point them,
they make those objects look closer or they
make those objects bigger. Apart from doing that,
what else do they do? They narrow down your line of sight.
So if you don't use binoculars,
you might be seeing the whole picture.
But if you're using binoculars, they narrow down your line
of sight. I mean you can see the lines here.
I mean
you'll only be seeing this part
and not the whole picture and the whole scenery.
So they're also narrowing down your line of sight,
the binoculars are narrowing down your line of sight.
So wherever you point to them that is like you're
narrowing down your line of sight to that point, to
that specific point.
And this is what we call axis.
Like where are you looking at.
Where exactly are you looking at.
So this was axis and the next part was nodetest. Nodetest is
what exactly are you looking after or are you
looking for boats or are you looking for seals or are
you looking for a lighthouse.
This is the nodetest.
What are you looking for.
So the axis is
where are you looking at.
OK.
Nodetests are
what are you looking for.
And then finally the predicate. The predicate is what
kind of attributes does the object you're
looking for have.
So if you're looking for a boat
what kind of attributes does that boat have.
Should it have red sails,
blue sails, white sails or some of
the stuff, that is the predicate.
I'll just say this again.
The axis is where you're looking at, where you
have narrowed down your line of sight.
OK.
Then the nodetest is what you're looking for.
Are you looking for boats or are you looking
for a lighthouse or are you looking for seals.
Then the final one is predicate
and predicate is like what kind of attributes does
you nodetest should have. Three things: axis, nodetest
and predicate.
OK.
OK, so let's move forward.
I've written this here, the three components that a
location step may contain. Only the nodetest is required.
So by this means that you can omit
the axis and the predicate if not needed.
So if you omit the axis, you omit the double colon that
delimits from sections from the nodetest there so
you can just write the nodetest directly.
I'll explain this to you
but what I mean by this and we can then
write some XPath expressions to
further understand how this works.
OK.
So the axis basically selects the direction you're looking for.
You can see that here, the nodetest selects particular
generic kinds of objects to see which
object are you after.
OK, the predicate highlights those objects
which have the right attributes,
specifically characteristics.
So that's the predicate.
So I have this XML example here. It's like
a pantry and then it has shelfs, then it has
supplies.
And those supplies have paper goods.
And then in paper goods I have two paper goods,
paper towels and paper plates then I
have snack foods in supplies, snack
foods and then I closed my shelf and then I have another
shelf and then I had a supply and then that
I have paper goods
and then I also have snack foods here.
This is my XML file here.
OK.
So what are you going to do now is we going to write an
XPath expression, a very simple one and then
I'm going to explain how this works.
So first of all we start off from nodetest. Let's
forget about axis for now, let's forget about it.
OK, I'll get to that in a while.
So let's start off from the nodetest. So notice if you
want to write an XPath expression note this
is something that is explicitly required, you can't omit them.
You can't omit the nodetest, you can omit the axis
and the predicate but you can omit
the nodetest. You just can't do that.
OK.
So let's say I want to get to this paper good here.
I mean this paper good here. What do I do that?
Is pretty much similar to what we did with Beautiful Soup.
So I said "pantry" and then I say "shelf".
Ok, so when I use this one forward slash
this means that I'm accessing a direct child which of
this "pantry" which should be "shelf" and then I use
another forward slash.
This supplies.
Then I say "paper_goods".
"paper_goods"
and then I say "paper_good".
What this is going to do is
this is going return me all the "paper_good"
tags which are direct children "paper_goods".
So this is this the Xpath expression for
extracting these two tags or elements here.
This is expression for that.
So what I did was this is like your parent, "pantry",
and then I've moved to the direct child, "shelf", and I've moved to
"supplies" and then I moved to paper goods, them I moved
to paper goods.
OK, so let's include the axis now and
see what like what does the axis do.
So the axis basically dictates like are you looking
at your children or are you looking at the parents or
are you looking at the ancesters or are you looking
at descendants like what's the difference between
parent and ancesters.
Parent is like a direct parent.
OK, this "paper_good" only has one parent, "paper_goods".
Let's say this "supplies" is its parent,
so "supplies" is its ancestor.
So "paper_goods" is also an ancester but it is also a parent
but "supplies" is not a parent, it is only
an ancestor and it shows it's only one
ancester to this "paper_good" tag here.
OK, so what axis does is axis
dictates that I will be looking for
children only, descendants only, looking for parents only
or are we looking for ancestors only or how this is
working or what they are.
How are we viewing, what site are we going now.
I provided a document, there is a document please. Just
have a look at it and I'm sure you'll understand for
further like what this means.
What I mean by axis.
So by default if you don't include any axis,
I mean I'm looking at the descendants. That means that
I'm looking at the descendants.
So you know as we haven't included any axis this means
that we are moving downwards, we are looking upwards.
SO by this I would have said that I'm
accessing my parent and this would have
been different, if
I would have moved upwards instead of downwards.
So this is what axis does to this,
to your XPath expression.
OK, so now there's one more thing that you should know.
Well the thing is like let's I want to
get the "paper_good" tags which are here,
all of them, not just one.
All of them.
What do I do now.
So what I can do is I can say "paper_good".
So when I use two slashes
this means that it is going to recursively search
the whole subtree or the tree like wherever we are
and it is going to get me this tag wherever it finds it.
These two slashes mean that.
So let's say I say "shelf", I say "pantry"
and then I say "shelf"
and then I use this.
So what this will do is this will
look for any "paper_good"
which are descendants of this "shelf",
this "shelf" where my cursor is.
So this comes to here,
still here, it is going to look to any "paper_good"
within the scope here, within this "shelf" scope here.
It is going to look at each descendant of
"shelf", each descendant of "shelf" and
there are only two. OK, so if I remove "shelf",
and I only say "pantry", it is going to get me all of the
"paper_good" tags which are present in this XML document
it's also going to get these two.
And then it's also going to get this one again. It is going to do that.
So this is what two slashes does like when
you use two slashes just this means that we are looking
for descendants and moving to descendants. A single slash means that we're only
moving towards our direct children.
And when the searching the whole trees recursively. OK.
So now let's get to the predicate part. So this
here we have the person name is equals to John then I say
child name is equals to John.
And this person has four children.
OK, John,
Connie,
Cindy and Mike. So let's say I want to get the child
which has its name Mike so this name is equals to
Mike, this is an attribute or a characteristic of this child.
So I how can I write a XPath expression for this. What I'm going to do
is I'm going to use predicate here.
So I say "person" and then I say "child"
and then I use this square brackets.
And then I have this array.
And then I say "@name" is equals to "Mike".
This is going to give me...
I've written the predicate here.
OK.
This is going to get me this child here. This is
how we handle attributes.
If this was an HTML tag and it might have
some attributes and this is how we would have
handled them. So I would have moved
from "person" to "child" and
I would have used the square brackets.
OK.
And then I would have written the attribute name,
it is in this iterator, is equals to...
I would have input the value, directly input the value.
So this is how I would have done this and
this is how you write predicates in XPath,
XPath expressions.
OK.
So in the next video, what we are going to do is
we are going to write some examples and we are going to
actually use Selenium and we are going to use XPath
to select different elements so that understand this further.
And I hope just go through the document
provided and try to understand and do
as many examples as you can with this and I think this
is pretty much it. XPath expressions can be
very complex if you get into this and there are a lot of things involved.
But I would like to keep this very simple because
I mean it is in essence a beginner's course.
So I don't want to get into a lot of things with XPath
right now but this is like the whole gist of
it.
So I hope I've made myself clear today and I'll you see the next video.
We will we work on examples by looking with Selenium.
Thank you very much everyone. I'll see in the next video.