Hello everyone! In the previous video, we discussed
the basics of XPath expressions, of writing
XPath expressions and what constitutes an
XPath expression like we have axis, we have
nodetest and then we have predicate.
In this video, we are going to do some examples of
writing XPath expressions so that we can
actually see them live.
You know like selecting different tags and
interacting with webpages in different ways.
So for now the first example is this Instagram example.
If you remember in the earlier video,
we searched for this "Log in" button and
we used the ".click" method to get to this
I mean to change the HTML of this
this section here.
So I mean if I click "Log in", this changes things
without sending a request to the server.
So what what we did earlier was we used
Selenium "link_text" method for finding this
"a" tag.
But for this video, what we are going to do is going to
select this "Log in", this is basically the "a" tag
we get from previous videos.
This is in "a" tag.
So what we are going to do is say we are going
select this "a" tag using XPath expression.
So by that we are going to learn how we
can do this, write a XPath expression for
a live website.
Let's see how we can do that.
I say "login_button" and I say "driver.find_element_by_xpath".
Now here comes my XPath.
OK.
So let's see the tree structure for this.
And then we can decide like how we're
going to write the XPath expression for this.
Like for this "a" tag here.
So this is the "a" tag in question for which you want to
get a XPath expression. As you can see
it does not contain an ID.
So if I go directly with class, I mean you never
know if there is another "a" tag which contains the
same class so I'm not sure if I can get to this "a" tag directly.
So what I do was I move to the parent and
see the first parent in which has an ID.
I mean that is a good practice to do this.
So let's move upwards and see this "p" doesn't have one, this "div"...
No, no, no.
I mean you can see that I am moving
up, moving up and I get to this "span"
I see that it has an ID which is "react-root".
So what I do is I say "OK, I want to get
to this element, the "span" which has its id
'react-root'".
So if you remember from our previous video, if we use
the double slashes, these two forward slashes,
this mean that we can search our
parse tree from where we're standing
right now.
And initially we are standing at
the very root of our parse tree.
This means that it is now like
when there are two forward slashes,
it is going to search from the entire
parse tree, from entire HTML tree.
OK, so now what we do is we say "span" and I'm going to
write a predicate here using the square brackets.
The predicate is that the span should have an ID "react-root".
So I say "id" is equals to "react-root" that being done now
as I'm here now what I want to do is I say let's
give it a shot for this "p" tag which has its class this.
So I'm copying its class.
And now what I want to do is I want to search the
whole descendants of this "span" so I used the
two slashes again and I say I want to search for
this "p" tag in the predicate which has its class
this.
Now when I'm at this, I can see
that it is a direct child of "p".
So what I can do right now is I can use a single
forward slash and then I write "a". The forward slash
only means that it is only going to
look in the direct children of this "p" tag.
It is going to search for the
whole descendents of this "p" tag.
Then it would look to the direct children.
And then "a" tag is a direct child of this "p".
So what I do now is I say "login_button.click".
So this should work.
I mean like we have written a expression.
which is next to this "a" tag and then we click it.
So let's see if we can make this work or not.
So I'm just introducing sleeps so
that we can see if it is working or not.
And I'm going to run it
now.
You see that it actually found it and clicked it.
So this XPath expression is absolutely valid.
That is valid.
So now I'm going to do another example which is
going to be, if you remember in one of our
previous videos, we searched Google, we used the
"send_keys" method to write some text
into this text field and then we submitted the form
using the "submit" function of selenium.
So what we are going going to do is
we're going to find this text area,
we are going to write an expression to find
this text are using XPath expression.
So let's do this, I'm just going to comment this
Instagram example so that we can write one for Google.
OK, so this being this, I have opened Google, I have sleep tag
here and then what I'm going to do is I'm going to
say "Inspect Element" and I'm going to see if I get
this "input" tag. I want an expression for this
"input" tag.
So let's see if this "input" has
an ID as you know ID is unique.
You get directly to it.
It has a class and it has an ID.
So this should be should be fairly simple.
So what should I do now.
I mean I want to search my whole
parse tree for the "input" tag.
What should I do.
How do I search for this "input"
tag in the whole parse tree.
So if you remember what we should do is I say "search_bar" is
equals to "driver.
find_
element_by_xpath" and if you remember if you
want to search your whole tree we use two
forward slashes from where you are right now.
So I wanted to search for a whole tree from the very start,
from a root node. So now I want to search for the
"input" tag which has its "id" equals to this.
So this is an example of predicate.
We are using a predicate here.
Just let me copy this.
I say "driver.find_element_by_xpath" then
I say I'm searching for an "input" tag, I say
"id" is equals to this.
OK, so now that I have the search bar, I say
"search_bar.send_keys" and "valid xpath expression"
and then I say "search_bar.submit". Let's see
if this works or not and how this goes on.
I'm going to run this now to see if this works or not.
So OK.
Open Google and let's see.
Yes.
It works.
So it sends the keys, the XPath expression
ended and it did submit in the form.
So this is also a valid XPath expression.
Now I've provided you with a word document, I want you to
look at it, I want you to play around with XPath
expressions, open different sites, select
different elements using XPath expressions
play around with them, use Selenium, use Beautiful Soup,
just learn as much as you can and make
your own XPath expressions
because they're widely used on web scraping
as they are quite efficient in terms of time and memory.
I hope this clear to you now.
So I'll see you in the next video.
Thank you very much.