Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed
RegEX and in this video we are trying to start
searching our parse tree and this video is going to
give an intro on searching our parse tree. If you remember
each HTML page is treated as a tree by Beautiful Soup when we make the Beautiful Soup
out of this HTML file. So it is treated like a tree.
We discussed before that we can navigate
through our tree using different methods.
We have like three different ways we can navigate through
our parse tree that is like going down, going up and going
sideways.
And then we had different methods for each these
directions. Like if Im moving up, we can
use the "parent" method. If I'm moving
sideways,
we can have the "next_sibling" method and there are
different methods for each of the movements
we have.
OK, so now the thing with that is you can
only move around a HTML document if we know
which tag you want, which tag you're
after and where it is located in the tree.
But it lets say your tree has thousands of tags.
How are you going navigate through thousands
of tags to get to the tags desire.
So here we come to searching. Beautiful Soup
provides us with very strong methods and very efficient
methods which return us the tags
we want.
It searches the whole parse tree for the tags
we want and it gives us back to those tags.
So the most popular method for searching are
"find" and "find_all". To keep it simple for now,
we say that these both methods
take the tags name as its parameter. OK, so I'm
going to be using this HTML file here for
searching examples right now. And this code here,
what it does is I've imported the necessary
modules and I'm reading this file and making a soup of it. OK.
So let's get started.
This video basically aims to make you
more familiar with searching and I
intend to
show you which filters you can use to retrieve tags.
OK, so filters are basically what dogs we want to retrieve.
So I can parse a string string like let's
say I want to find all "b" tags.
So what I do is I say "soup.find_all" and I run it.
It gives me all "b" tags, this "b" here
and I have this "b" tag here
and then this "b" tag here.
So "find_all" returns us a list.
We'll discuss more
"find_all" in detail later on.
This is just a introduction.
What kind of filters it is going
to accept as a parameter.
OK, so this was very basic like it accepts
a string and treats it like a tag name.
So if I have "a" here, you see it
gives me all "a" tags in my document.
So this was for string.
Now we can pass
a Regular Expression to retrieve tags.
So let's say I want all those tags
whose name start with "b".
So what I'm doing is I'm going to make a Regular
Expression. The Regular Expression is going to
be "^b". This indicates any strings which start with "b".
So I say "for tag in soup.find_all(regex)", I say
print "tag.name". And if I run it, you can see
it gives me all tags whose first character is "b". OK.
So this just shows you how we can use RegEX
to find tags and we can write very complex Regular
Expressions for finding different kind
of tags or by narrowing down classes,
narrowing down tags using their attributes and RegEX. We'll
discuss more of it.
We will use RegEX more later on as we do "find_all"
and "find" later this introduction to see how
we can use RegEX to help give us tags. OK.
So just to give you one more quick example.
I want all those tags,
all those tags which contain the character "t".
I write the Regular Expression for this and it's simple.
And I say "for tag in soup.find_all('t')", and say print "tag.name".
And if I run that.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't pass the RegEX object. It gives
me all the tags which contain the character "t"
here. OK.
So this is just an example of how we can use
RegEX to retrieve tags, to search for tags.
OK, so right now we have discussed two
ways. We can give it a string which it treats
as a tag name and then we have discussed Regular Expressions,
like we can send Regular Expressions and that
will retrieve those tag names which satisfy our Regular Expression.
So now I can also send a list of tag names.
Let's say I want all "a" and "b" tags.
So I say "for tag in tag.soup.find_all", and
then pass a list and I say "a" and "b".
And if I print "tag.name", you can see it has given
me all tags which are either "b" or "a" tags.
So we just discussed that filter and that list. We can pass this function a list and
it will give us all those tags which satisfy a list of constraints.
I said I want all those tags which are "a" tags or "b" tags. So lastly
it can also accept functions.
This "find_all" function can accept functions as its parameters.
So this is just one example here.
Like when we discuss "find_all" in detail, we
are going to discuss more on how we can
use functions to narrow down our search and get those tags which you
really want.
So this function, just to give you a basic intro,
this function either return true or false.
So you write a function that say I want all those which have class. I say "has_class",
return "tag.has_att('class')". Then I say print
"for tag in soup.find_all"
and then I say this "has_class", and I say print.
OK so what happens is I've written a function which accepts
a tag as its parameter and what it does is it returns either true or false.
So tag has this method has attribute, "has_attr".
And then I check if that has an attribute "class".
If it does it is going to return
true and if it returns true I get that tag here in this "find_all".
And if it returns false, this "find_all" doesn't include that tag in my result.
So before I run this I want us to see this document.
So you can see that only this "p" tag, this "p" tag and
this "p" tag have the "class" attribute and these
"a" tags too.
So if I run this now, you can see it gives me these "p"
tags and the "a" tags. So I can also have functions as
parameter for this "find_all" function or the
"find" function. We'll discuss more about this later, in the later
videos.
So I'll see you in the next video, I'll start off with these
common methods and what are the parameters we can send
and how we can search
more to get the data we really need.
So thank you very much.
I hope to see you soon.