Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed
how we can search through our parse tree.
That was an introduction as to why searching
is important and how we can do it. In this video
we are going to discuss the most commonly used
function in Beautiful Soup for searching elements.
So that function is "find_all", I did give you an intro to
this function in the previous video and we discussed
the different filters we can use to get different tags or elements.
So now I will discuss this function in detail and see
what kind of parameters it can take and how we can
actually use it to get the elements we want.
So I'm going to use the same HTML file as we've been
using before, this one, the three sisters story.
And
OK, so the signature for this function is here, this.
So the first parameter of this function takes his name.
The second is attribute.
The third is recursive, the fourth string and the fifth limit and the sixth are keyword arguments
that I
hope you're familiar with keyword arguments.
I mean we can give as many arguments as we want here. OK.
I'll explain this part in the next video,
when we'll discuss this function in detail, in more detail.
OK.
In this video, we're going to discuss the name
parameter, the attribute and the limit parameter.
OK, so the name parameter is very simple.
It's really simple.
It can take a
RegEX object or it can take a string.
Or it can take a object.
It can take a string.
It can take a "True", it can take a function.
I mean these are the filters as discussed before.
So in the previous video.
OK, let's just show you how this works.
I say that I want to find all the "a"
tags in this HTML file, this one.
I have this one here.
So I say "soup.find_all" and I say "a".
And if I print "a_tags",
you can see I have all the "a" tags here or I
could loop through this "for a in a.tags".
So I have all the "a" tags here
which are present in this document.
There are three. This "link1", "link2"
and this "link2" should be "link3".
OK.
So there are three "a" tagss and I have them all.
I have all of them here using this
function, this "find_all" function.
Ok, so the second parameter takes the attributes parameter.
This actually is basically a dictionary.
It's a dictionary and I'll just show you how this works.
This is like each tag has an attribute like this "p" tag here.
It has an attribute class which is equals to "title".
OK.
Or this "a" tag here.
It has three attributes. Has one attribute "class", this is a "href", this
is then "id". It has three attributes, this tag has three attributes.
So what I can do is I can say "attr" is equals
to "class" and I want to get this tags here,
this "Elsie" a tag.
So I say the class is "sister"
and let's give it another attribute.
Let's give it "id". So "id" is "link1", you can see that here.
The "id" is "link1" and the class is "sister".
So now I have this dictionary, it says
the class is "sister"
and the "id" is "link1".
So what I do is I say "first_a" is equals to "soup.find_all", I say a.
And then I say "attrs" is equal to "attr". And if I print
"first_a", you can see it returns me this "a" tag which
I want, this one.
So let's say I want all those
tags which have the class "sister".
So what can I do.
What I'll do
is I'll just remove this "id" here.
And if I run this now, it returns back
three "a" tags, it returns back tags which
are "a" and which have the class equal to "sister".
So what I can do is I can also delete this name
parameter. And if I run this now it still
gives you the same thing. Why does it do that.
It does that because there are only "a" tags which
have their class "sister". If I change to "story".
Let's see what happens then if they change to "story".
Do you see this? What it does is it returns me two "p" objects now,
"p" tags now. This tag here and this tag
because both of them have their class "story".
So that returns me "p" tags which have the class "story".
So this is how the attribute tag works.
Now we're going to move to the limit parameter,
the last one for the video here. What limit parameter
does is it limits the number of search or the number
of searches it returns.
So let's say I want you to find "a" tags.
Now there are three "a" tags in our HTML file as you
can see here. One, two, three. So what I can do is
I can say "find_all('a')" then I say "limit" is equal to two.
Let's keep it to one. And if I say print "a_tags" now.
There's gonna be one "a" tag. If I remove
the "limit", you can see it returns me three now.
So what "limit" does is it limits the number of search results returned.
So if I say two, it gives me two "a" tags, not three now.
So "limit"
limits the number of searches so.
This "attr" parameter,
these are the tags attributes and we can pass
this parameter using a dictionary like the
class "story", I can have "id", I can
have "style", I can have like "href".
Whatever attributes that we can specify them here in the dictionary and
then pass them to this "find_all" function. OK.
And then the name parameter, we discussed this in the
previous video when I was giving an intro to searching
and this takes a RegEX object, a string
or a boolean "true" or a function or anything.
I mean the filters we discussed in the previous video. I hope
up to now we are clear.
I want you to play around with this. In the next video,
we're going to discuss the remaining parameters and
how they work and how we can utilize them and
these parameters to search efficiently.
Thank you very much.
See you in the next video.