Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed
some of the parameters of "find_all" function. In this video,
we're going to cover the rest of the parameters
we did not discussed in previous video.
So in the last video, we discussed the name parameter,
the attributes one and the limit one. In this video,
we are going to discuss the recursive one, the string one
and the key with arguments one as to how we can implement them
and what they mean and how we can use them to search
efficiently through our HTML tree case. Ok, so the first
way we are going to discuss is the string parameter.
So the string parameter expects a string or a RegEX
object as its input and it returns us a
a navigable string it finds in the whole document which contains our string
we specified.
So let's say I have this document here. It's the same one, the three sisters one.
And what I want is I want to know if there is some navibable string which
contains the word "Elsie".
So now we know that there is this navigable string, this here.
This is between this "a" tag here.
I mean this "a" tag here is the parent
of this navigable string and I want to find this
navigable string which contains "Elsie". What
I do is I say "regex" is equals to "re.compile" and "Elsie".
Now I'm going to say "tag" is equals to "soup.find_all"
and I say that "string" is equals to "regex"
and if I print "tag"
it returns me this navigable string which contains "Elsie".
I can do this.
Let's say I want to find a navigable string which contains the word
"story".
So what I do is I a RegEX object, I say "story". And if
I run that, you see it gives me back two navigable
strings which contain the word "story".
So if I go back to my HTML, you can see I have two
navigable strings which contain the word "story".
This one here between "title" and this one here between this "b" tag.
So you can see that here that it
returns me two different navigable strings which contain the word "story".
This is a list and it has two elements in it.
OK, so this was the "string" parameter.
It can either expect
expect a string or a RegEX object and it goes through the whole document
and sees all the navigable strings and see if any of them
equal to the string you have specified or it equals
to the regex that we have mentioned.
OK, so the next argument we are going to discuss is the
keyword argument. So the keyword argument what they do is
let's say I want to find all the tags which have the class "sister".
OK.
So what I do is I say "tags" is equals to "soup.find_all"
and then I say "class_" is equals to "sister".
Then I say "for tag in tags", print "tag". Ok, so what
I do here is I write the attributes of a tag
like this "class" here, this "class" is an attribute of "p" tag.
This "id" here is an attribute of "a" tag.
These are attributes.
So what I do is I specify the attributes.
Like I say if it's "id" I say "id" is equals to
"link1". I specify the attribute.
I write it down and then I say is equals to
the navigable string, to the given value
that attribute has,
which you want to search and then what this
"soup.find_all" does is it returns
me those tags which satisfy these attributes.
So let's say I want to have all the tags which
have the class "sister". So if I run it
now, you can see it has given me all the tags which
have the class "sister" and there are three here.
The first one, the second and the third. All of them
are "a" tags. So you know that "class" is a keyword
in Python.
So what we do here is we say "class" and then we have
this underscore here. You write it that way.
I mean, if I don't write the underscore, then this
"class" is a keyword and it gives me an
error here.
So when you are going to write the class attribute
when passing it as a keyword argument then
you are going to write "class_".
So let's say I want to find all the tags which have the
class "story". I just change it here and say "story".
And if I run it, you can see it gives me back two "p" tags. I can
just say print "len(tags)". It says two, it has returned me two "p" tags.
OK.
So now the last one, the last parameter here which I am
going to discuss now is the "recursive" parameter.
So what "recursive" does is let's say you search
"a" tags. So what happens is your parser starts from this "html" tag and
then it recursively searches through the whole parse
tree to see if there are any "a" tags. It goes to
"head" and it goes to head's children and then sees if
"head" contains any "a" tag then goes to "body" and
then goes to body's children, like this "p" tag here,
then goes to this "p" tag's children, this "b" tag
here and see if there is any "a" here then it goes to this "p" tag
and it comes here and it finds "a".
And then it collects all of them and goes back.
"recursive" searches the whole parse tree.
So what we do is let's say I only want to
search direct descendants of a particular
tag. Let's say I only want to search direct children
of "html", I don't want to search my whole tree
for an "a" tag.
So what will happen now is that if I want to do that
what I do is I say "title", and what I am going
to do is I am going to search for "title".
OK.
And I'm going to say "recursive" is equals to
"False". What it will do is it will force the
Beautiful Soup
to just look at this level here, in body
level, and not to go into the children.
It will just look into the children of "html" and nothing more.
If I say "soup.find_all", I say "title" and
I say "recursive" is equals to "False".
So now it is going to start from "html",
it is only going to access the HTML
children which are "head" and "body".
It is not going to go into head's children which here is "title".
So it is not going to recursively search the whole tree
because I've said "recursive" is equals to "False".
So if I print "title" now, it is an empty
list because it couldn't find "title".
But if I have this "True", which by default
is "True", it gives me "title" tag.
So again what happened was that when I send a
"False" there, it only searches the children
of "html", the direct children, and they did not go
into their children. So it did not go into "head".
It did not go into the children of "head".
It says "Ok, so 'html' has two children, 'head'
and 'body'".
So is there any "title" tag which is a direct child
of HTML? And it couldn't find any so it returned me an
empty list.
But when I have it "True", it
recursively searches the whole parse tree
for the tag.
So it goes to descendants, all of them, every one of
them and it fetches me all the "title" tags which
are present.
Which in our case we only have one.
So by default, this "recursive" parameter is "True".
So you don't need to set it to "True".
But if you only want to search the children of
some tag, the direct children, you
set it to "False" and it will return you an empty list.
So I hope that this is more clear to you.
We have discussed the "find_all" function and we discussed
the different parameters it can take and how we
can use them to refine our search.
I hope this is clear to you and I'll see you in the
next video and we'll discuss the "find" function
which is pretty similar to "find_all". I will
discuss in the next video what differences
we have in "find" and "find_all".
Thank you very much.