Hello everyone! In the last video, we discussed the
parameters of "find_all" function and we
completed all the parameters we can send to
"find_all" function to refine our search.
In this video, we are going to discuss the "find" function.
It is the same as the "find_all" function.
I mean it takes the same arguments as you can see
here, the "name", the attributes, "recursive", "string"
and keyword arguments but the one argument that
is missing here is the "limit" argument if you
remember. "limit" is the argument which in "find_all"
function limites the number of searches it also returns.
So what's the difference between "find" and "find_all"?
"find" only returns a single object if it finds
any, it doesn't return more than one.
I mean if there are more than one. Let's say we
are searching for "a" tags using "find".
So if there are let's say 5 "a" tags, it only returns
us the first "a" tag, not the whole list of "a" tags. So
"limit" is of no use here.
"find" only returns us a single object. "limit" was
used to limit the number of search results returned and "find" here
only returns one, so it doesn't make sense to have a limit argument here.
So the signature for the "find" function is same as you can see here.
It's the same as "find_all" except for the "limit", we don't have a limit here.
I'm just going to give you an example.
We're going to use the same HTML document here.
So you can see let's say I have
three "a" tags. I'm going to call this find function on "a".
And let's see what happens.
And if I call this, it only returns me one "a" tag, the first one precisely.
If you see this here. So it only returns us
the first "a" tag, it doesn't return us
all "a" tags and if I change this to "find_all", you
can see ir returns me a list of "a" tags which are
three in number.
I mean I could say "len(tag)"
and you can see this three.
So ir returns three tags
if we use "find_all" but when we use
"find" it only returns us one.
So the difference between "find" and "find_all" is
that "find" only returns us one single object if it finds
any.
And in case of multiple objects it only returns us the first
object it finds and "find_all" what it does is that
it returns us the whole list of objects it finds in the whole parse tree.
So this is a difference between "find" and "find_all". In the next
video, we are going to discuss a live example of how to scrap from a life site
and I'll show you how we can apply these techniques, how we apply these techniques
to parse a real HTML tree of a website.
And see you soon.
Thank you very much.