Hello everyone.
Now as we as we've ended our course, we have
covered a lot of stuff like Beautiful Soup,
request, Selenium.
We have written Regular Expressions.
We have written XPath expressions. We have learned
how to parse data, how to actually get what
we want and how to handle that amount of data
and how we can write them to ".csv" files and stuff.
So now in this video, I'm just going to
highlight some best practices which you should keep
in mind when you are scraping.
So the first thing as you can see is
that you should avoid using Selenium.
You should actually avoid the use of Selenium and
use the request as much as possible because Selenium
slows up things.
So use Selenium as your last resort.
Don't jump to Selenium each time you get a chance.
So like let's say you want to search Google.
You can actually do that using requests,
you don't need Selenium for that.
But for that it will actually have to read
some documentation for request and go dig deeper
into that.
So I would advise you to do that. For now
you can stick to Selenium but for future you should
always improve and then try to be a better version of
yourself.
So you should avoid using Selenium.
And second is that you should limit your request to the server.
What I mean by that is that let's say you
send like in the final project we were downloading
images from Instagram.
And let's say that you run your scraper
again and again and again and
again for different target profiles and you downloading
hundreds of thousands of images.
So what Instagram is going to do is it is
going to see that something fishy is going on.
A single IP has send so many request to our server, what is going
on?
And they would get suspicious and
then they would block you out.
So you should introduce delays in your code.
First things that that actually helps that you can actually
undercover when you do that.
And secondly you should scrape carefully.
It is actually wrong to bombard someone's server
like this and they can actually block you.
So blocking is not an issue for them
and they're going to do that and they
will do that.
So they will definitely do that.
If you disrespect their policies and
you actually just go on sending
requests.
So the third one is a continuation of the second one. What
you can do is you can download web pages which
you intend to scrape.
So like if you have a very complex
structure of website and you know that you may
open the same links twice or thrice or many
times, what you can do is you can actually
download the HTML,
anything you can have them on your
local machine and then you can access
those files and then parse them later on instead
of sending requests to the server again and again. So
I would advise you to download web pages if you
think you are going to use it
many times and not once.
So the fourth one is that you should parse pessimisically.
What I mean by that is that let's say that
you parse some data and that data contains digits.
So I mean you should always think pessimistically here.
What I mean by that is that you should
think that it is a string, like
they are not digits because that would actually
help you that you don't actually get surprised
when you run your scraper.
So this will help you a
lot when you think pessimistically.
So you should think of them as a
string and you can just type cast
them as integers. You can definitely do that,
it is not a headache and if there are integers,
what's going to happen?
Nothing.
It's just that you remain safe from your end.
So just do that.
I mean it helps a lot when you are writing
a lot of code and you don't
have to... know definitely that this
is an integer or I'm just giving an example
here often intergers, this can be anything.
So when you are parsing, narrow your approach
and think pessimistically think
what is
the worst thing that can happen.
And then just take effective countermeasures for that.
So the fifth one is divide and conquer.
This is actually quite important.
As far Instagram scraper which we wrote in the last file, in the last
section, we saw that we actually downloaded
it in different parts. We were logging
in and we were opening a target profile and it
was scrolling down and scrolling with downloading images
and then getting captions.
So we had actually broken down this parts so we didn't
try to take everything had done. What we did was
we broke everything in parts.
Even if you even if you go for project one
when we scraped from "codingbat.com", what we did
was we knew we had three webpages, three main web pages
which we had to scrape from.
So first of all we did what we did
was we divided our scraper.
We had the first part for the main page and then the second part
was the scraper we had for them middle page
which when you open a section
to question which appeared.
And then the final one was the question part.
So divide and conquer is a really effective strategy.
And we should always look towards
because that really helps.
So I hope that you learned what
and what I taught you and I really
hope that you may utilize this knowledge in
a good manner and you don't actually
go on and get lot and stuff.
So it was great.
It was actually great teaching in this course.
I really look forward to having
another course with you guys. So thank you very much
guys, it was really nice teaching you this course.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.